<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-09-11T00:34:31.222Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-09-11T00:34:31.222Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.17 Released With Better HiDPI Support For Built-In Apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.17-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.17-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T20:30:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.17 is out as the latest bi-weekly development release as we move closer towards the Wine 7.0 release around the start of the new year...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Habana Labs AI Driver Updates Submitted For Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Habana-Labs-Linux-5.15-Changes</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Habana-Labs-Linux-5.15-Changes"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T17:57:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While last week was the main "char/misc" pull request for the Linux 5.15 merge window, the Habana Labs driver changes were previously reverted from there due to opposition from the upstream kernel developers in the Direct Rendering Manager  space. The concerning patches around DMA-BUF have now been removed and a new pull request submitted with updates to this AI driver for Linux 5.15...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Performance Still Pushing Ahead Of Windows 10, Latest Windows 11 Build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30514</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30514"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T11:55:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With less than one month out from the official release of Microsoft Windows 11, I was curious to run some fresh benchmarks of the latest Windows 11 Insider Preview build against Windows 10 21H1 to see how the performance is looking. Of course, also to see how Windows 11 is shaping up against Ubuntu 21.10 also due for release in October.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Habana Labs Opens Up The Code To Their AI Compiler, SynapseAI Core]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Hababa-Labs-Open-Compiler-AI</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Hababa-Labs-Open-Compiler-AI"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel-owned Habana Labs now has the most open software stack among AI accelerators! While Habana Labs has long provided an open-source, upstream kernel driver for their Gaudi AI training and Goya AI inference accelerators, the user-space portions including their code compiler and run-time library have been closed-source. This has been a thorn for upstream kernel developers and their standards, but now Habana Labs has open-sourced their user-space components too...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Readies More Code For Compile & Run-Time Detection Of Buffer Overflows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-More-BO-Detection</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-More-BO-Detection"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T09:29:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week a number of patches were merged in the quest to provide the kernel with comprehensive compile-time and run-time detection of buffer overflows. Another patch series was sent out today while still for this cycle they are expected to enable the compiler warnings around array-bounds and zero-length-bounds...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Just Squeezed More Workstation Performance Out Of Its RadeonSI Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-VBO-DLIST-Opt</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-VBO-DLIST-Opt"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Vulkan is quickly taking over as the dominant graphics API for Linux gamers especially with the likes of DXVK and VKD3D-Proton mapping Direct3D atop Vulkan, OpenGL remains widely used by workstation software. It's also for workstation software where AMD's "PRO" closed-source OpenGL Linux driver has traditionally competed well (and outperformed) the open-source Mesa driver. But with all the recent changes, that's either a matter of the past or close to not being relevant with the latest Mesa enhancements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Privacy-Screen DRM API With Intel Support Ready Now That GNOME Is Prepared To Use It]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Privacy-Screen-DRM-Ready</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Privacy-Screen-DRM-Ready"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past two years we have seen work around bringing up privacy screen support on Linux whereby an increasing number of laptops can reduce the amount of visible light when viewed at wide angles to try to block the screen contents from anyone potentially snooping at the screen. Ready to go now is the DRM/KMS user-space interface and the Intel graphics driver support now that there is a user-space "client" ready...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to deploy the GitLab Kubernetes Agent with limited permissions]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/10/setting-up-the-k-agent/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/10/setting-up-the-k-agent/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GitLab Kubernetes Agent (agentk) is an active in-cluster component for solving GitLab and Kubernetes integration tasks in a secure and cloud native way. The agentk communicates to the GitLab Kubernetes Agent Server (kas) to perform GitOps operations.
In many examples, we see the agent being deployed with global-level permissions on your cluster. There are use cases where we want to reduce the scope of what agentk has access to. In this guide I will provide information on deploying agentk on your cluster, limiting what namespaces it can access, as well as using it to deploy your applications.
Prefer a video? Watch the walkthrough below to learn how to deploy agentk to your cluster:


How it works
Anytime a developer performs changes to a manifest file managed within GitLab, the agentk w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The benefits of DevOps practices for IBM Z]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/10/adopt-agile-and-devops-for-ibm-z/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/10/adopt-agile-and-devops-for-ibm-z/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As more organizations adopt open source software, DevOps and cloud computing, teams are moving towards a hybrid approach to application development and deployments. This is a particular challenge for siloed mainframe development teams that typically work within their own development tools – and those tools are are not the same ones used by their distributed developer counterparts. These disparate toolsets are not integrated between build, package, test, and deploy steps. GitLab aims to provide a unified enterprise-wide DevOps platform with enhanced support for IBM z/OS® applications. Here are three critical areas to focus on that can help bridge the gap between mainframe and "modern" DevOps development.
Common workflows for hybrid environments
DevOps is naturally aligned to Agile processes…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server Adds "AsyncFlipSecondaries" To Deal With Crappy Multi-Monitor Experience]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-AsyncFlipSecondaries</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-AsyncFlipSecondaries"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T20:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the moment when running the X.Org Server in a multi-monitor configuration with displays of different refresh rates, it can lead to a poor experience with a variety of visual deficiencies when running an unredirected full-screen window with page-flipping for DRI3/Present. There is now a change that was merged into the X.Org Server with a new "AsyncFlipSecondaries" to improve that experience when running multiple displays of varying refresh rates...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Releases Its August Update For The CBL-Mariner Linux Distribution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CBL-Mariner-August-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CBL-Mariner-August-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T19:21:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While now into September, Microsoft just published its "August 2021" update to their CBL-Mariner Linux distribution with a variety of changes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Cloud-Hypervisor 18.0 Brings AArch64 Improvements, VHDX Disk Image Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Cloud-Hypervisor-18</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Cloud-Hypervisor-18"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T18:37:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Intel-led open-source Cloud-Hypervisor project building off Linux's KVM (and also supporting Microsoft MSHV) and being cloud-focused and leveraging the Rust programming language for greater security is out with its newest major release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Adds VDUSE For vDPA Devices In User-Space]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-VDUSE-vDPA</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-VDUSE-vDPA"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T18:12:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Akin to FUSE for file-systems in user-space, VDUSE is set to be merged for Linux 5.15 in adding support for vDPA devices in user-space...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Posts New "AMD-PSTATE" CPUFreq Driver Leveraging CPPC For Better Perf-Per-Watt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PSTATE-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PSTATE-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T11:48:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At last! AMD has posted the Linux kernel driver patches for their new "AMD-PSTATE" driver! This driver with modern AMD Zen CPUs (initially limited to Zen 3) to achieve greater performance per Watt / power efficiency on Linux than the conventional ACPI CPUFreq driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMDVLK 2021.Q3.6 Brings New Extensions, Valheim Shader Optimization]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDVLK-2021.Q3.6</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDVLK-2021.Q3.6"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T10:51:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMDVLK 2021.Q3.6 is out as the latest routine open-source code drop for this official AMD Radeon Vulkan Linux driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Branch Sampling Support Being Worked On For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-BRS-Branch-Sampling</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-BRS-Branch-Sampling"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T10:00:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new kernel patch series was posted this morning working on AMD Branch Sampling "BRS" support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD PTDMA Driver Landing For Linux 5.15 After Two Years In The Works]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PTDMA-For-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PTDMA-For-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going back to September 2019 was work on the AMD PTDMA driver for supporting this controller found on modern AMD processors for high bandwidth memory-to-memory and I/O copy operations. With the Linux 5.15 cycle the AMD PTDMA driver is finally being merged to the mainline kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SLUB Adapted To Be Real-Time Linux Compatible (PREEMPT_RT)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SLUB-Linux-RT-Compatible</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SLUB-Linux-RT-Compatible"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the nice low-level improvements we've seen with Linux 5.15 is a number of pieces falling into place in the quest of upstreaming the real-time (RT) patches for Linux. The latest merge makes SLUB RT-compatible...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GitLab's 5 new code review features will make life easier]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/09/5-code-review-features/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/09/5-code-review-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the second in a series of blog posts looking at the challenges of code review and the ways a DevOps platform can help. Read the first post.
Code review can be one of the most deceivingly difficult things in delivering software faster. Given the high stakes involved, we've made some key additions to our DevOps Platform that focus on making the code review process as seamless and effective as possible. We believe the number one way to make code reviews effective is to provide context. Too often we think of code reviews as only "reading" and commenting on others' code - but what a good code reviewer does is understand the entire context of the proposed change. Context-driven code reviews should include factors like the issue that spurred on the change, how the change impacts non-obvio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNOME 41 Release Candidate Arrives With Many Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNOME-41-RC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNOME-41-RC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T23:05:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ahead of the official GNOME 41 release later this month, the release candidate is now available to facilitate more testing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon's DAMON Merged Into Linux 5.15 For Data Access Monitoring Framework]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DAMON-Merged-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DAMON-Merged-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T20:22:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The DAMON kernel functionality developed by Amazon engineers has successfully landed in the Linux 5.15 tree...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Delivering Some Performance Gains On The Intel Core i9 11900K]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10-Rocket-Lake</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10-Rocket-Lake"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T19:15:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those wondering how the upcoming Ubuntu 21.10 release is looking for Intel "Rocket Lake" owners, here are some Ubuntu 21.04 versus 21.10 development benchmarks across dozens of different tests...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Has An Important Suspend/Resume Fix With Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-S2idle-Fix-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-S2idle-Fix-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T18:47:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since last year AMD has been working to get its s2idle / suspend-to-idle S0ix sleep state code in order for supporting this lowest power platform idle state on newer AMD laptops and there has also been other AMD suspend/resume improvements in recent times. Now with the Linux 5.15 kernel cycle is an important fix for the AMD s2idle code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not All Of The IBM POWER10 Firmware Is Currently Open-Source]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=IBM-POWER10-Not-All-Open-FW</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=IBM-POWER10-Not-All-Open-FW"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T12:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Power E1080 server as their first in a new family of servers based on the IBM POWER10 processor. Sadly though not all of the POWER10 firmware is open-source...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OverlayFS On Linux 5.15 Improves Performance, Copies Up More Attributes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-OverlayFS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-OverlayFS"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T11:02:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OverlayFS continues to be used by Linux IoT/embedded devices and other use-cases as a union mount file-system. With Linux 5.15 the OverlayFS file-system continues to improve...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook Opens Up CacheLib As Their New Caching Engine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Facebook-Open-Source-CacheLib</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Facebook-Open-Source-CacheLib"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T10:22:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook last week formally announced CacheLib as their new open-source caching engine designed for web scale services and to make for effective non-volatile memory caching to offset the increasing costs of DRAM...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Working On DP 2.0 Panel Replay Power Savings For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-DP-2.0-Panel-Replay</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-DP-2.0-Panel-Replay"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T09:57:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month Intel's open-source Linux graphics driver engineers began posting patches working on DisplayPort 2.0 support for their driver with DG2/Alchemist now set to be Intel's first GPU supporting the newest DP standard. DP 2.0 enablement work continues with Panel Replay being the latest feature being worked on for their Linux driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Hit By Some Early Performance Regressions But Quickly Reverted]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Memcg-Regressions</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Memcg-Regressions"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T09:37:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to Linus Torvalds dealing with the -Werror fallout, separately in kernel land there were also some significant performance regressions introduced during the Linux 5.15 that led to Linus reverting some of the changes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15's New "-Werror" Behavior Is Causing A Lot Of Pain]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Werror-Pain</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Werror-Pain"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T00:48:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Landing this past weekend was the surprise move by Linus Torvalds to enable "-Werror" behavior by default for all kernel builds. That compiler flag addition makes all warnings be treated as errors, which in turn stops the kernel build. As expected, this change has led to quite a mess...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making the case for a DevOps platform: What data and customers say]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/08/making-the-case-for-a-devops-platform-what-data-and-customers-say/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/08/making-the-case-for-a-devops-platform-what-data-and-customers-say/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the struggle to release safer software faster, development teams are increasingly choosing a DevOps platform to help them get there. In our 2021 Global DevSecOps Survey we asked respondents what their DevOps practices included and a "DevOps platform" was among the top four choices, right next to CI/CD, test automation, and DevSecOps.
We're of course bullish on the idea of a DevOps platform, but we're far from alone. Here's a fresh look at how the data – and the customers – support the optimistic trajectory of a DevOps platform.
DevOps is hot
The DevOps market was worth $6 billion in 2020, according to Global Industry Analysts, and five-year growth forecasts range from $17 billion to as much as $23 billion, depending on the firm. 
[Watch a deep dive into GitLab's DevOps Platform]
This pr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to write and continuously test vulnerability detection rules for SAST]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/08/write-vulnerability-detection-rules/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/08/write-vulnerability-detection-rules/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In summer 2021, the Vulnerability Research and Static Analysis
teams launched the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) project: Write vulnerability detection rules for SAST.
For this project, we built and implemented a framework to helps transition GitLab away from our current SAST tools over to Semgrep. Semgrep is a language-agnostic SAST tool that is gaining popularity in CI/CD environments.
Before replacing an analyzer with the corresponding Semgrep configuration (called rule-sets), we need to ensure that they are equivalent – in that they yield the same set of findings.
For this purpose, we built a testing framework that helps us assess the quality of a Semgrep rule-set. This framework has been used to guide the replacement of flawfinder, a C/C++ analyzer with a corresponding Semgrep rule-set.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GhostBSD 21.09.06 Released For This FreeBSD-Based Desktop OS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GhostBSD-21.09.06-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GhostBSD-21.09.06-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T22:07:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GhostBSD 21.09.06 is now available as the latest release of this desktop-minded, FreeBSD-based operating system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 KVM Defaults To The New x86 TDP MMU, Enables AMD SVM 5-Level Paging]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-KVM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-KVM"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T18:43:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux 5.15 Kernel-based Virtual Machine (KVM) changes this cycle are quite exciting on the x86 (x86_64) front with several prominent additions...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Khronos Group Is Hosting A Virtual Vulkan Event Next Month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkanised-2021-Next-Month</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkanised-2021-Next-Month"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T17:23:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While The Khronos Group previously hosted in-person Vulkan events, due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic their "Vulkanised 2021" event next month has morphed into a free virtual event...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 5 5600G / Ryzen 7 5700G Linux Gaming Benchmarks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30505</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30505"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently with my Linux benchmarks of the Ryzen 5 5600G and Ryzen 7 5700G Zen 3 APUs with Radeon Vega graphics I touched on the GPU graphics/compute performance in some of the basic benchmarks while in this article are a number of Steam Play and native Linux gaming benchmarks for looking at the potential for these latest-generation desktop APUs for Linux gaming.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSSL 3.0 Officially Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenSSL-3.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenSSL-3.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T13:08:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After many development snapshots and three years worth of work, OpenSSL 3.0 is now available as a major update to this widely-used SSL library...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org DMX Dropped After More Than A Decade Of Crashes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-DMX-Dropped</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-DMX-Dropped"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T11:53:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The X.Org Distributed Multihead X (DMX) DDX driver has been dropped from the X.Org Server source tree due to its rather broken state for more than one decade...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are developers so vulnerable to drive-by attacks?]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/07/why-are-developers-vulnerable-to-driveby-attacks/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/07/why-are-developers-vulnerable-to-driveby-attacks/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As someone who spends a lot of time working with computers, I know how easy it is to grow over-confident with regards to security. My systems are patched, my firewall rules are tight, and I’m vigilant when it comes to just about anything that looks out of the ordinary.
No one’s hacking their way into my workstation, that’s for sure.
But my experience working as a hacker myself has shown me that the opposite is often true. Those of us who are more technical are often much more vulnerable to an attack due to the complexity of our working environments.
In this blog, we’re going to dive into the anatomy of something called a “drive-by attack,” where malicious code hidden within a website uses your own browser to attack your computer.
As an example, I’ll show you how our own Red Team was able t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The code review struggle is real. Here's what you need to know]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/03/the-code-review-struggle-is-real-heres-what-you-need-to-know/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/03/the-code-review-struggle-is-real-heres-what-you-need-to-know/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When making a list of the reasons to consider moving to a DevOps Platform, don't forget about code review, a critical piece of the process that's also an incredible source of frustration and delays to developers and their teams.
In our 2021 Global DevSecOps Survey, respondents told us code quality was the number one reason they chose DevOps. But, when asked what was most likely to delay a product release, code review – vital to code quality – was one of the top four culprits (the others were testing, planning and code development). 
The fact that code review is a pain point is hardly surprising, given that it can often require context-switching, communication, collaboration, and of course subject matter expertise. At a time when it's never been more urgent to release secure code as quickly…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The journey to a DevOps Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/the-journey-to-a-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/the-journey-to-a-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a recent blog post about the importance of a DevOps Platform, GitLab CEO Sid Sijbrandij outlined four phases through which organizations frequently travel as their practice matures. It’s a painful journey we see again and again when we meet new customers. It spans every industry and every company size, and it’s the most mature DevOps teams with the most at stake who’ve felt the most pain. 
Historically, if you wanted DevOps to work, you had to be prepared to pay for it. Just managing the backbone of DevOps – the toolchain -– has been a grind. Your “Jenkins Team,” your “GitHub Team,” or even, as one of our customers described, your “Duct Tape Team” (designed to hold it all together and patch holes), added no end value beyond keeping everything from falling apart. That’s a lot of investme…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we learned about configuring Sidekiq from GitLab.com]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/specialized-sidekiq-configuration-lessons-from-gitlab-dot-com/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/specialized-sidekiq-configuration-lessons-from-gitlab-dot-com/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sidekiq in GitLab works perfectly well out-of-the-box in most use cases, but it requires a little more attention in larger deployments or other specialized cases. We've learned a lot about how to configure Sidekiq in large deployments by maintaining GitLab.com – one of the largest instances of GitLab in existence. We added some critical features to GitLab.com in the past year to make it easier to configure Sidekiq in a manner more consistent with the maintainer's guidance, having strayed from this path for some time.
We are publishing two blog posts devoted to this topic. In this first post, we will unpack how we configured Sidekiq for GitLab.com, and in our second post, we will explain how to apply this to your GitLab instance.
[Learn more about how we iterated on Sidekiq background jobs]…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 13.12.11]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-13-12-11-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-13-12-11-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 13.12.11 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
the 13.12 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
The main purpose of this release is to resolve high CPU usage by the Gitaly
server:
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Backport improved replication logic
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.10 and 14.1.5]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-14-0-10-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-14-0-10-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.0.10 and 14.1.5 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
These versions resolve a number of regressions and bugs in the
14.0 and
14.1 releases.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
The main purpose of these two releases is to resolve high CPU usage by the
Gitaly server:
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Backport improved replication logic
Additionally, 14.1.5 includes the following fixes:
Geo: Replicate multi-arch containers
Run AWS Release rake task only if on latest stable tag
Important notes on upgrading
These versions do not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Summer of Code at GitLab – some intern highlights]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/01/gsoc-at-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/01/gsoc-at-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab participated in Google Summer of Code for the first time this year. We hosted four student interns to work with us on four different projects under the supervision of two or three mentors each.
For the past 16 years, Google has hosted the Summer of Code to introduce students to the world of open source. Over the summer, student interns work on a project with an open source organization and are closely mentored by the developers of the open source project. More than 200 organizations participated this year.
We started off the summer with a two-week long community bonding period to get our students familiar with how we work at GitLab and helped them set-up their local development environments. During the 10-week program we worked through scoped projects with regular check-ins and a fi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.2.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/01/gitlab-14-2-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/01/gitlab-14-2-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.2.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
last month's 14.2 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Geo: Replicate multi-arch containers
Reset severity_levels default
Create 14.2 In-app top 7 product highlights
Fix OrphanedInviteTokensCleanup migration
Fix Live Markdown Preview in personal and subgroup projects
Downgrade grpc from 1.38.0 to 1.30.2 for compatibility with older CPUs
Restore proper contents to toolbox ubi8 image
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Important notes on upgrading
This version does include post deploy db migrations. For multi-node deployments, it should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Security Release: 14.2.2, 14.1.4, and 14.0.9]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/31/security-release-gitlab-14-2-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/31/security-release-gitlab-14-2-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.2.2, 14.1.4, and 14.0.9 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your software build pipeline using code signing]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/30/secure-pipeline-with-single-sign-in/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/30/secure-pipeline-with-single-sign-in/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If there is one thing that recent cyberattacks at companies such as SolarWinds, Codecov, and Kaseya have taught us, it's that software build pipelines are being targeted for attacks more than ever before. Hackers are no longer just attacking the bits and bytes of source code that go into our products, but also the development, testing, and build infrastructure tools that are used to build these products.
Even if you believe your company is at low risk of an attack, it's also important to think about your customers. Businesses with high profile customers – like government agencies or large, multinational corporations that use your products – might have attackers target them by hacking your company, or more specifically, the software you provide them.
The incidents at Solarwinds, Codecov, an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's time to update Docker Engine]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/26/its-time-to-upgrade-docker-engine/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/26/its-time-to-upgrade-docker-engine/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alpine Linux distribution is the base OS used by many Linux container images. It provides a handy packaging mechanism, new versions of software, and a quick and predictable release cycle – all while being distributed using a minimal image size. It's used by many very popular container images, for example docker:dind,
widely used in GitLab CI/CD workloads handling container
images building and management in the jobs.
On June 15, 2021, Alpine Linux released version 3.14. As documented in the release notes, changes in the musl library require
an updated version of runc or updated version of
Docker for the Alpine 3.14-based images to work properly.
Software products across the computer industry have started migrating their Alpine Linux-based container images to 3.14 since it includes significa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.8]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/26/gitlab-14-0-8-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/26/gitlab-14-0-8-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.8 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
the 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Revert backfill on ci_build_trace_sections
Resolve "operator does not exist: integer[] || bigint in app/models/namespace/traversal_hierarchy.rb"
Fix Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Geo 2.0 Regression - Add ability to remove primary
Backport fix for flaky spec to 14.0
Important notes on upgrading
This version includes a post deploy migration. For multi-node deployments, it should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Write a stageless CI/CD pipeline using GitLab 14.2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/24/stageless-pipelines/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/24/stageless-pipelines/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab CI/CD technology has historically divided a pipeline into stages based on the typical development workflow. Now that GitLab 14.2 has launched, users can speed up cycle times by using the needs command to write a complete CI/CD pipeline with every job in the single stage. In fact, you can omit stages completely and have a "stageless" pipeline that executes entirely based on the needs dependencies.
Understanding stages
In GitLab CI/CD, you use stages to group jobs based on the development workflow and control the order of execution for CI/CD jobs.
Pipelines execute each stage in order, where all jobs in a single stage run in parallel. After a stage completes, the pipeline moves on to execute the next stage and runs those jobs, and the process continues like this until the pipeline com…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/23/build-cloud-for-macos-beta/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/23/build-cloud-for-macos-beta/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World-class CI/CD comes as a part of the GitLab DevOps Platform to help streamline how development teams build, test, and deploy their apps. GitLab Runner is the execution engine that "does the work," enabling you, as a developer, to run fast, scalable CI/CD pipelines on your on-premises infrastructure or the cloud. Historically, Apple developers on GitLab SaaS had to set up runners on their own macOS systems to execute CI/CD workflows, introducing additional cost and operational overhead. As organizations and teams develop more apps for the Apple ecosystem, the need to create and deploy quickly becomes more important.
Introducing GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta
Today, you can say goodbye to that Mac mini under your desk! We are pleased to announce the GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.2.1]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/23/gitlab-14-2-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/23/gitlab-14-2-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.2.1 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.2 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Adding upgrade messaging for PK migrations
Don't override vulnerability feedback UUID anymore
Reorder vulnerability check criteria
Fix "getAction is undefined" bug
Drop un-used db/ci_migrate symlink
Fix migration NameError in rails env helper
Bump Container Registry to v3.9.0-gitlab
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab 14.2 released with the Build Cloud for macOS beta and Markdown preview]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/22/gitlab-14-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/22/gitlab-14-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are excited to announce the release of GitLab 14.2 with  introduction of the Build Cloud for macOS beta, Markdown preview, expanded Gitpod integration, new DevOps adoption metrics, and much more!
These are just a few highlights of the 50+ improvements in this release. Read on to check out all of the great updates below.
To preview what's coming in next month’s release, check out our Upcoming Releases page, which includes our 14.3 release kickoff video.
Join us for an upcoming event









This month's Most Valuable Person (MVP) is
Cornelius Ludmann

Cornelius added support
for opening code changes directly in Gitpod when viewing a merge request. In fact, this
release blog post was created and edited with Gitpod! Cornelius initially helped add an
option to open a project in Gitp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>