<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-09-05T00:37:22.326Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-09-05T00:37:22.326Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Has A New Maintainer For Its CD-ROM Driver Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-CD-ROM-New-Developer</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-CD-ROM-New-Developer"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T20:28:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After more than two decades of maintaining the Linux CD-ROM driver code, Jens Axboe who also serves as the block subsystem maintainer, IO_uring lead developer, and filling other roles, announced he was looking for someone to take over the CD-ROM code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA Confirms Sway Wayland Compositor Works Fine With Their New GBM Driver Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-GBM-Works-With-Sway</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-GBM-Works-With-Sway"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T16:24:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Stemming from an ongoing Mesa GBM discussion over introducing new gbm_bo_create_with_modifiers2 / gbm_surface_create_with_modifiers2 functions since the original "gbm_*_create_with_modifiers" functions lack support for passing usage flags, NVIDIA confirmed that the Sway Wayland compositor is working fine with their forthcoming driver supporting GBM...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung 860/870 SSDs Continue Causing Problems For Linux Users]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Samsung-860-870-More-Quirks</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Samsung-860-870-More-Quirks"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T11:24:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Samsung has explicitly stated before that queued TRIM works for Samsung 860 SSDs on Linux and thus leading to only older Samsung 840/850 drives being blocked from queued TRIM usage, that turns out to be inaccurate and now more quirks are added for the Samsung 860 and 870 series SSDs on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple M1 IOMMU Driver Merged For Linux 5.15, Intel Scalable Mode By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M1-IOMMU-Lands-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M1-IOMMU-Lands-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T09:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Linux 5.13 landed initial Apple Silicon M1 support, it was just the very initial bits. Now for Linux 5.15 we are seeing another step in the bring-up with the community-created Apple M1 IOMMU driver being merged...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE's Plasma Wayland Session Is "Finally Reaching Stability" Following Many Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Wayland-Reach-Stability</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Wayland-Reach-Stability"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T09:27:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE developers have kicked off September by landing many fixes for their desktop stack, including around their Plasma Wayland session...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Looks To Drop DMX After Being Rather Broken For ~14 Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DMX-DDX-Dropping-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DMX-DDX-Dropping-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-04T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org's DMX DDX driver for supporting Distributed Multi-Head X looks like it will be removed from the source tree after finding out the code has been rather broken for the past 14 years...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Has A Critical Improvement For Tiered Memory Servers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Demote-During-Reclai</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Demote-During-Reclai"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T19:48:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Landing via Andrew Morton's patch series today in the Linux 5.15 kernel is handling for demoting pages during memory reclaim, which can be used for punting cold pages off to slower, tiered memory devices (like Intel persistent memory) when under system memory pressure...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New NTFS File-System Driver Has Been Submitted For Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NTFS3-For-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NTFS3-For-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T17:25:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It looks like Paragon Software's NTFS3 kernel driver providing much better Linux support for the Microsoft NTFS file-system will land for the 5.15 kernel!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gzip 1.11 Released With "Orders of Magnitude Faster" Performance On IBM Z]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Gzip-1.11-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Gzip-1.11-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T16:53:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The last release of Gzip was v1.10 back at the end of 2018 while now it's finally been succeeded today by Gzip 1.11...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Benchmarking The Performance Impact Of Linux 5.15's Newest Protection Around Side Channel Attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30504</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30504"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T13:05:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the in-development Linux 5.15 kernel there is a new option for further protecting the kernel around side channel attacks and information leakage. Enabling the option will ensure that any caller-used register contents are zeroed prior to returning from a function. While the reported performance cost is said to be small, I decided to run some benchmarks when toggling this new Kconfig hardening option.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Snapcraft 6.0 Coming To Finally Move From Ubuntu 18.04 To 20.04 LTS Base, Phase Out i386]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Snapcraft-6.0-Coming</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Snapcraft-6.0-Coming"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T12:45:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical is preparing to soon release Snapcraft 6.0 as the latest version of their utility for packaging and distributing Snaps, the Ubuntu-preferred route for sandboxed apps...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freedesktop SDK 21.08 Released With RISC-V Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Freedesktop-SDK-21.08</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Freedesktop-SDK-21.08"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T11:41:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Freedesktop SDK as a platform and SDK run-time for Flatpak apps/run-times is out with its first major stable update in one year...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Working Towards Comprehensive Compile-Time & Run-Time Detection Of Buffer Overflows]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Overflows</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Overflows"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T11:17:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest security effort being pursued by Google's Kees Cook is to provide full compile-time and run-time coverage of all detectable buffer overflows...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Haiku Upstreams Its GNU Binutils Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Binutils-Haiku-Upstream</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Binutils-Haiku-Upstream"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T10:40:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BeOS-inspired Haiku open-source operating system project has upstreamed its GNU Binutils support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NFS Client Changes For Linux 5.15 Bring Connection Sharing, Better Responsiveness]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NFS-Client-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NFS-Client-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T09:19:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Linux 5.15 has added KSMBD as an SMB3 in-kernel file server, the NFS code within the Linux kernel continues advancing as well for network file sharing needs. With NFS in Linux 5.15 are a few notable improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Looking To Bolster EPEL]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Red-Hat-More-EPEL</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Red-Hat-More-EPEL"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat is said to be establishing a "small team" to work on activities around EPEL, the "Extra Packages for Enterprise Linux" that is popular with RHEL/CentOS users for easily fetching extra packages not available via RHEL proper...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 12 Looking At Enabling Its Vectorizer For "-O2" Optimization Level]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-O2-Vectorization-Talk</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-O2-Vectorization-Talk"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GCC compiler when using the default "-O2" optimization level is likely to be slightly faster with next year's GCC 12 release as the developers are looking at enabling the vectorizer options by default...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The code review struggle is real. Here's what you need to know]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/03/the-code-review-struggle-is-real-heres-what-you-need-to-know/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/03/the-code-review-struggle-is-real-heres-what-you-need-to-know/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When making a list of the reasons to consider moving to a DevOps Platform, don't forget about code review, a critical piece of the process that's also an incredible source of frustration and delays to developers and their teams.
In our 2021 Global DevSecOps Survey, respondents told us code quality was the number one reason they chose DevOps. But, when asked what was most likely to delay a product release, code review – vital to code quality – was one of the top four culprits (the others were testing, planning and code development). 
The fact that code review is a pain point is hardly surprising, given that it can often require context-switching, communication, collaboration, and of course subject matter expertise. At a time when it's never been more urgent to release secure code as quickly…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 5 5600G Linux Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30499</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30499"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T19:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month were our benchmarks of the AMD Ryzen 7 5700G on Linux for that new desktop APU with Zen 3 cores and Vega graphics available through retail channels. Due to reader interest and with the Ryzen 5 5600G still readily available via Internet retailers, here is a look at the AMD Ryzen 5 5600G Linux performance in a variety of benchmarks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EXT4 Ready With Some New Optimizations - Orphan_File, Moving Discard's Work]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-EXT4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-EXT4"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T17:44:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's busy on the Linux file-system front for the 5.15 cycle with Btrfs adding a degenerate RAID option along with performance improvements to big improvements for XFS and now comes the EXT4 updates...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA Jetson TX2 NX + Other ARM Platforms Now Supported By Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-ARM-SoCs-Platforms</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-ARM-SoCs-Platforms"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T13:10:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Arm SoC and platform updates have been merged for the in-development Linux 5.15 kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Big Batch Of New AMD RDNA2 PCI IDs Is Heading To Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=More-RDNA2-IDs-For-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=More-RDNA2-IDs-For-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T11:50:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week I wrote about AMD adding 17 more RDNA2 PCI IDs to their Linux driver which is rather unusual given the amount and the number of PCI IDs already found in the AMDGPU kernel driver for these latest-generation GPUs and the Radeon RX 6000 series already being mid-life. As noted in that article and seemingly in agreement with the various other industry articles following that Phoronix news, it seems to be for some sort of RDNA2 refresh likely. Now those new PCI IDs are being queued up for introduction in the current Linux 5.15 cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qt 6.2 LTS Will Nearly Be At Feature Parity To Qt 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Qt-6.2-LTS-Feature-Parity-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Qt-6.2-LTS-Feature-Parity-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T10:02:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the Qt 6.0 tool-kit debuted last year much of the early criticism stemmed around it not having all the modules/functionality ported over from Qt5 meanwhile The Qt Company was restricting newer Qt 5.15 LTS point releases to paying customers only. Since then the developers have been working to address the voids in Qt6 and with the upcoming Qt 6.2 as their next long-term support release, all of the important functionality should be in place...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Van Gogh Audio Driver Lands For Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Sound</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Sound"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T09:29:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sound/audio drivers have landed for the ongoing Linux 5.15 kernel driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam On Linux Continues Hovering Around The 1% Mark]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Linux-August-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Linux-August-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T09:05:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In July -- the same month as Valve announcing the Steam Deck -- the Steam on Linux marketshare hit 1.0%. That 1.0% marketshare was a +0.14% bump and the highest seen in years since Steam on Linux's debut nearly a decade ago back when it commanded around a 2% marketshare...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genode OS Framework 21.08 Streamlining Its Porting Of Linux Driver Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Genode-OS-21.08</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Genode-OS-21.08"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We've been covering Genode OS for more than a decade now as this original open-source operating system "framework" and through this time they have managed to keep up with their routine feature releases. Out this week is Genode OS Framework 21.08 as they seek to make it easier porting device driver code to their platform...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The journey to a DevOps Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/the-journey-to-a-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/the-journey-to-a-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a recent blog post about the importance of a DevOps Platform, GitLab CEO Sid Sijbrandij outlined four phases through which organizations frequently travel as their practice matures. It’s a painful journey we see again and again when we meet new customers. It spans every industry and every company size, and it’s the most mature DevOps teams with the most at stake who’ve felt the most pain. 
Historically, if you wanted DevOps to work, you had to be prepared to pay for it. Just managing the backbone of DevOps – the toolchain -– has been a grind. Your “Jenkins Team,” your “GitHub Team,” or even, as one of our customers described, your “Duct Tape Team” (designed to hold it all together and patch holes), added no end value beyond keeping everything from falling apart. That’s a lot of investme…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we learned about configuring Sidekiq from GitLab.com]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/specialized-sidekiq-configuration-lessons-from-gitlab-dot-com/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/specialized-sidekiq-configuration-lessons-from-gitlab-dot-com/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sidekiq in GitLab works perfectly well out-of-the-box in most use cases, but it requires a little more attention in larger deployments or other specialized cases. We've learned a lot about how to configure Sidekiq in large deployments by maintaining GitLab.com – one of the largest instances of GitLab in existence. We added some critical features to GitLab.com in the past year to make it easier to configure Sidekiq in a manner more consistent with the maintainer's guidance, having strayed from this path for some time.
We are publishing two blog posts devoted to this topic. In this first post, we will unpack how we configured Sidekiq for GitLab.com, and in our second post, we will explain how to apply this to your GitLab instance.
[Learn more about how we iterated on Sidekiq background jobs]…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 13.12.11]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-13-12-11-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-13-12-11-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 13.12.11 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
the 13.12 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
The main purpose of this release is to resolve high CPU usage by the Gitaly
server:
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Backport improved replication logic
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.10 and 14.1.5]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-14-0-10-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-14-0-10-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.0.10 and 14.1.5 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
These versions resolve a number of regressions and bugs in the
14.0 and
14.1 releases.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
The main purpose of these two releases is to resolve high CPU usage by the
Gitaly server:
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Backport improved replication logic
Additionally, 14.1.5 includes the following fixes:
Geo: Replicate multi-arch containers
Run AWS Release rake task only if on latest stable tag
Important notes on upgrading
These versions do not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Addressing Scalability Issue That Caused Huge IBM Servers 30+ Minutes To Boot]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Kernfs-Scalability</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Kernfs-Scalability"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T20:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Very large IBM mainframes/servers were taking 30+ minutes to boot the Linux kernel... No, just not for POST'ing the system with memory training and the like, but for loading Linux. Fortunately, with the Linux 5.15 kernel there is a set of scalability enhancements to allow these large IBM systems to be able to boot in around five minutes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Staging Replaces Its Realtek RTL8188EU WiFi Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Staging</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Staging"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T18:27:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The staging updates for Linux 5.15 continue to have a lot of code churn including some drivers being promoted while one Realtek WiFi driver has been replaced...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows Server 2022 Reaches General Availability With Focusing On Hybrid Clouds, Containers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Windows-Server-2022</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Windows-Server-2022"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T17:30:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Microsoft announced that Windows 11 will be formally released on 5 October, rolling out today is general availability on Windows Server 2022...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel "Crocus" Gallium3D Now Part Of Mesa's Default Drivers To Build]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Crocus-Default-Gallium3D</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Crocus-Default-Gallium3D"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T13:15:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's i965 classic DRI driver is still the default within Mesa for i965 through Haswell generations of Intel integrated graphics, but the new "Crocus" Gallium3D driver has been added to the default driver build list so it's now at least building by default on x86/x86_64 systems and thus trivial after that to override...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Hardware Monitoring Is Big But Overdue For AMD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-HWMON</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-HWMON"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux 5.15 hardware monitoring "HWMON" subsystem changes were sent out and now merged for this next kernel version. Particularly notable this cycle is AMD catching up on some of their sensors support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RadeonSI Enables DCC Stores For RDNA2 APUs To Squeeze Out More Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-DCC-Stores-RDNA2-APU</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-DCC-Stores-RDNA2-APU"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T11:56:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RadeonSI Gallium3D as the official AMD OpenGL Linux driver has mirrored the unofficial RADV Vulkan driver in enabling DCC stores support for RDNA2 APUs in the name of greater performance...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wayland Protocols 1.22 Released With DRM Object Leasing Support For VR HMDs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wayland-Protocols-1.22</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wayland-Protocols-1.22"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T10:56:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Designed with VR headsets in mind, Wayland-Protocols 1.22 was released today and adds the DRM leasing protocol to its staging area...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Summer of Code at GitLab – some intern highlights]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/01/gsoc-at-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/01/gsoc-at-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab participated in Google Summer of Code for the first time this year. We hosted four student interns to work with us on four different projects under the supervision of two or three mentors each.
For the past 16 years, Google has hosted the Summer of Code to introduce students to the world of open source. Over the summer, student interns work on a project with an open source organization and are closely mentored by the developers of the open source project. More than 200 organizations participated this year.
We started off the summer with a two-week long community bonding period to get our students familiar with how we work at GitLab and helped them set-up their local development environments. During the 10-week program we worked through scoped projects with regular check-ins and a fi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.2.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/01/gitlab-14-2-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/01/gitlab-14-2-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.2.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
last month's 14.2 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Geo: Replicate multi-arch containers
Reset severity_levels default
Create 14.2 In-app top 7 product highlights
Fix OrphanedInviteTokensCleanup migration
Fix Live Markdown Preview in personal and subgroup projects
Downgrade grpc from 1.38.0 to 1.30.2 for compatibility with older CPUs
Restore proper contents to toolbox ubi8 image
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Important notes on upgrading
This version does include post deploy db migrations. For multi-node deployments, it should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Security Release: 14.2.2, 14.1.4, and 14.0.9]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/31/security-release-gitlab-14-2-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/31/security-release-gitlab-14-2-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.2.2, 14.1.4, and 14.0.9 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your software build pipeline using code signing]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/30/secure-pipeline-with-single-sign-in/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/30/secure-pipeline-with-single-sign-in/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If there is one thing that recent cyberattacks at companies such as SolarWinds, Codecov, and Kaseya have taught us, it's that software build pipelines are being targeted for attacks more than ever before. Hackers are no longer just attacking the bits and bytes of source code that go into our products, but also the development, testing, and build infrastructure tools that are used to build these products.
Even if you believe your company is at low risk of an attack, it's also important to think about your customers. Businesses with high profile customers – like government agencies or large, multinational corporations that use your products – might have attackers target them by hacking your company, or more specifically, the software you provide them.
The incidents at Solarwinds, Codecov, an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's time to update Docker Engine]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/26/its-time-to-upgrade-docker-engine/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/26/its-time-to-upgrade-docker-engine/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alpine Linux distribution is the base OS used by many Linux container images. It provides a handy packaging mechanism, new versions of software, and a quick and predictable release cycle – all while being distributed using a minimal image size. It's used by many very popular container images, for example docker:dind,
widely used in GitLab CI/CD workloads handling container
images building and management in the jobs.
On June 15, 2021, Alpine Linux released version 3.14. As documented in the release notes, changes in the musl library require
an updated version of runc or updated version of
Docker for the Alpine 3.14-based images to work properly.
Software products across the computer industry have started migrating their Alpine Linux-based container images to 3.14 since it includes significa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.8]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/26/gitlab-14-0-8-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/26/gitlab-14-0-8-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.8 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
the 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Revert backfill on ci_build_trace_sections
Resolve "operator does not exist: integer[] || bigint in app/models/namespace/traversal_hierarchy.rb"
Fix Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Geo 2.0 Regression - Add ability to remove primary
Backport fix for flaky spec to 14.0
Important notes on upgrading
This version includes a post deploy migration. For multi-node deployments, it should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Write a stageless CI/CD pipeline using GitLab 14.2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/24/stageless-pipelines/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/24/stageless-pipelines/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab CI/CD technology has historically divided a pipeline into stages based on the typical development workflow. Now that GitLab 14.2 has launched, users can speed up cycle times by using the needs command to write a complete CI/CD pipeline with every job in the single stage. In fact, you can omit stages completely and have a "stageless" pipeline that executes entirely based on the needs dependencies.
Understanding stages
In GitLab CI/CD, you use stages to group jobs based on the development workflow and control the order of execution for CI/CD jobs.
Pipelines execute each stage in order, where all jobs in a single stage run in parallel. After a stage completes, the pipeline moves on to execute the next stage and runs those jobs, and the process continues like this until the pipeline com…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/23/build-cloud-for-macos-beta/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/23/build-cloud-for-macos-beta/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World-class CI/CD comes as a part of the GitLab DevOps Platform to help streamline how development teams build, test, and deploy their apps. GitLab Runner is the execution engine that "does the work," enabling you, as a developer, to run fast, scalable CI/CD pipelines on your on-premises infrastructure or the cloud. Historically, Apple developers on GitLab SaaS had to set up runners on their own macOS systems to execute CI/CD workflows, introducing additional cost and operational overhead. As organizations and teams develop more apps for the Apple ecosystem, the need to create and deploy quickly becomes more important.
Introducing GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta
Today, you can say goodbye to that Mac mini under your desk! We are pleased to announce the GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.2.1]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/23/gitlab-14-2-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/23/gitlab-14-2-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.2.1 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.2 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Adding upgrade messaging for PK migrations
Don't override vulnerability feedback UUID anymore
Reorder vulnerability check criteria
Fix "getAction is undefined" bug
Drop un-used db/ci_migrate symlink
Fix migration NameError in rails env helper
Bump Container Registry to v3.9.0-gitlab
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab 14.2 released with the Build Cloud for macOS beta and Markdown preview]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/22/gitlab-14-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/22/gitlab-14-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are excited to announce the release of GitLab 14.2 with  introduction of the Build Cloud for macOS beta, Markdown preview, expanded Gitpod integration, new DevOps adoption metrics, and much more!
These are just a few highlights of the 50+ improvements in this release. Read on to check out all of the great updates below.
To preview what's coming in next month’s release, check out our Upcoming Releases page, which includes our 14.3 release kickoff video.
Join us for an upcoming event









This month's Most Valuable Person (MVP) is
Cornelius Ludmann

Cornelius added support
for opening code changes directly in Gitpod when viewing a merge request. In fact, this
release blog post was created and edited with Gitpod! Cornelius initially helped add an
option to open a project in Gitp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a new integration helps GitLab customers secure their code]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/20/how-grammatech-and-gitlab-enables-better-devsecops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/20/how-grammatech-and-gitlab-enables-better-devsecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software development teams that embrace agile and DevSecOps are able to code with a security-first mindset, which is essential for industries that build particularly complicated products where security is paramount, like: Aerospace and defense, automotive, industrial controls, medical devices, and more.
Static application security testing (SAST) solutions, like CodeSonar® from GrammaTech, integrate directly into CI/CD pipelines to bake security into every step of the software development life cycle (SDLC) – protecting your products every step of the way. Security solutions like GrammaTech pair well with an all-in-one DevOps Platform like GitLab, and allow development teams to follow best practices and industry standards to develop code that is better quality and more secure.
The GrammaTech…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Spamcheck: A data-driven, anti-abuse engine]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/19/introducing-spamcheck-data-driven-anti-abuse/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/19/introducing-spamcheck-data-driven-anti-abuse/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spam and abuse are a very real concern for us at GitLab – and likely every company providing services at scale. That's why our Trust and Safety team works hard every day to detect, mitigate, and lessen the effects of spam. Back in October 2020, the GitLab Security team detailed some of the ways they combat spam and abuse and referenced new approaches we were developing and testing to help us better detect and prevent spam.
We're excited to introduce Spamcheck, our new anti-spam engine. Spamcheck has been enabled for all projects on GitLab.com, which runs 14.1, and will be included in the 14.2 release for GitLab self-managed coming on August 22.
This tool was designed, tested and integrated by our GitLab Security Automation team (with amazing partnership from our Trust and Safety team and o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How DevSecOps can protect businesses from future supply chain attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/18/what-the-solarwinds-attack-can-teach-us-about-devsecops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/18/what-the-solarwinds-attack-can-teach-us-about-devsecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the cybersecurity keywords for 2021 will undoubtedly be "software supply chain attacks". For decades, we've seen a global move toward connected systems and highly complex supply chains. Today these supply chains are under attack, with malicious actors jeopardizing the sensitive data of millions of users through attacks on the public and private sectors.
After public and federal entities were targeted in some high-profile supply chain attacks, the United States government released an executive order with plans to improve the security posture of the nation when it comes to software supply chains. The UK issued a similar call for views on cybersecurity in supply chains around the same time.
Supply chain security became a global priority after the SolarWinds attack, reminding businesses…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to provision 100 AWS Graviton GitLab Spot Runners in 10 Minutes for $2/hour]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/17/100-runners-in-less-than-10mins-and-less-than-10-clicks/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/17/100-runners-in-less-than-10mins-and-less-than-10-clicks/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Managing elastically scaled or highly available compute infrastructures is one of the key challenges the cloud was built for. Application scaling concerns can be handled by cloud services that are purpose designed, rigorously tested, and continually improved. This article dives into some specific enablement automation that brings the benefits of AWS Autoscaling Groups (ASG) to runner management. There are benefits to both the largest fleets and single instance runners.
Embedded in this article is a YouTube video that demonstrates the deployment of 100 GitLab runners on Amazon EC2 Spot compute in less than 10 minutes using less than 10 clicks. The video also shows updating this entire fleet in under 10 minutes to emphasize the time savings of built-in maintenace.
The information and automat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.1.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/17/gitlab-14-1-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/17/gitlab-14-1-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.1.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
last month's 14.1 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
AS Fix SAML SSO login redirects not working
Bump kas to v14.1.1
Resolve operator does not exist: integer[] || bigint in app/models/namespace/traversal_hierarchy.rb
Geo 2.0 Regression - Add ability to remove primary
Add AES256-GCM-SHA384 to allowed list of Nginx SSL ciphers
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I use analogy to design for highly technical spaces]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/13/understand-highly-technical-spaces/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/13/understand-highly-technical-spaces/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a designer, you're lucky when you get to design an application you're familiar with, such as a supermarket app or a travel website – something we might have already used or even use every day. Most of the time, we are tasked with designing an application or technology that's unfamiliar or highly technical. Sometimes, we may not know what the application we're designing is used for, like creating an interface for an MRI machine controlled by a doctor, or a dashboard used by a professional musician – knowing what all the buttons do is already an achievement.
One of the trickiest questions for designers is understanding exactly how much you need to know how to use an application to design the best system for the user. This conundrum is typical for designers that work in a highly technical,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>