<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-09-22T00:36:06.600Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-09-22T00:36:06.600Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1 RC1 Released With VRR Support For Modesetting Driver, Other Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1-RC1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1-RC1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T22:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than three years after X.Org Server 1.20 was released, it's set to finally be succeeded soon by X.Org Server 21.1 under its new versioning scheme. Out today is the X.org Server 21.1 release candidate...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMDGPU Linux Driver To Overhaul Its Approach To Device Enumeration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Device-Enumeration-IP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Device-Enumeration-IP"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD's open-source Linux graphics driver engineers are working to overhaul how the initial driver loading with device enumeration happens to ultimately make it more robust. In the process though PCI IDs become less important and in turn less of an avenue for exposing possible indicators of new graphics cards...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cycles X Merged Into Blender 3.0 With NVIDIA CUDA/OptiX Support, AMD HIP Pending]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Blender-3.0-Lands-Cycles-X</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Blender-3.0-Lands-Cycles-X"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T19:33:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cycles X as a modernizing of Blender's Cycles rendering engine has now landed in the latest development code for Blender 3.0. Cycles X brings big performance improvements but does eliminate OpenCL support in the process...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 94 Released With WebGPU For Testing, WebCodecs API Now Official]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-94-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-94-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T18:48:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 94 is available today as another exciting update for Google's web browser...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle's Next-Generation GNU Profiler "gprofng" Is Looking Great For Developers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Profiler-gprofng</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Profiler-gprofng"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T18:21:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle engineers have been working on "gprofng" as a next-generation GNU Profiler that can analyze production binaries. Oracle talked up Gprofng today during the GNU Tools Track as part of Linux Plumbers Conference 2021...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Foundation To Host PaSh For Automatic Parallelizing Of Shell Scripts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Foundation-PaSh</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Foundation-PaSh"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T17:16:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux Foundation announced today they will be hosting the PaSh project that is focused on automatically parallelizing POSIX shell scripts...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samba 4.15 Released With Improved CLI Experience, Modernized VFS Interface]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Samba-4.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Samba-4.15"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T12:40:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While there is now KSMBD with Linux 5.15 for offering an in-kernel SMB file server, its scope is much more limited than that of the Samba project in user-space. With that said, Samba 4.15 is out now with its latest batch of features and improvements for open-source SMB/CIFS support on Linux and other platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical Extending Ubuntu 14.04/16.04 LTS Support To Ten Years]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-14.04-16.04-Ten-Years</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-14.04-16.04-Ten-Years"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical is announcing this morning they are extending the Ubuntu 14.04 LTS "Trusty Tahr" and Ubuntu 16.04 LTS "Xenial Xerus" releases to a ten year lifespan...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkan Video Decoding Still In The Early Stages For Open-Source]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkan-Video-XDC2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkan-Video-XDC2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T10:33:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going public back in April was the provisional specification around the Vulkan Video extensions as a new industry-standard video encode/decode interface. While several months have passed, there hasn't been much activity yet in the open-source space around Vulkan Video...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.3 Lands Initial Radeon Ray-Tracing Support In Open-Source RADV Vulkan Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-RADV-Ray-Tracing</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.3-RADV-Ray-Tracing"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T09:25:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Landing overnight into Mesa 21.3 was experimentally enabling the Vulkan ray-tracing extensions within the open-source Radeon "RADV" driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Extending DWARF To Better Handle GPU Debugging, Continues Collaborating With GCC & LLVM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Extending-DWARF-GPUs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Extending-DWARF-GPUs"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to AMD's increasing Linux kernel contributions, they are also contributing more improvements in user-space too thanks to their super-computing wins and other big enterprise deployments that are Linux-based. One of the areas talked about this week at the Linux Plumbers Conference with the GNU Tools track is how they are working to extend the DWARF debug format to better handle GPU debugging...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phoronix Ad-Free/Premium Special For Oktoberfest 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Oktoberfest-2021-Special</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Oktoberfest-2021-Special"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T03:59:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Oktoberfest was once again cancelled due to the COVID-19 pandemic (then again, due to the state of the ad industry / ad-block users we haven't had any European meet-up / open-source gathering in years), the wiesn would have kicked off this past weekend. So as is tradition, there is the Phoronix Premium Oktoberfest sale where you can join the ad-free service as a reduced rate. If you enjoy the daily, original Linux and open-source content on Phoronix with plenty of benchmarking, you can do so at a reduced rate...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's time to build more accessible software. A DevOps platform can help]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/21/how-the-devops-platform-makes-building-accessible-software-easier/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/21/how-the-devops-platform-makes-building-accessible-software-easier/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The earlier a feature or process is introduced in the multi-step software development lifecycle (SDLC), the more likely it is to be fully integrated into the product.
It's well documented how security can shift left using a DevOps platform, so it's time to make the case that accessbility needs to be thought about earlier (and, clearly, a DevOps platform can facilitate that too). Although there are laws that require applications to meet certain accessibility requirements, which opens an application up to a broader user base, rarely is accessibility considered a core product requirement. Instead, it is just a test tacked on at the end instead of being built into the DevOps platform process.
[Learn more about how the open source development community helps build accessible software]
"The prob…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab's realtime Preview Markdown is an editor for everyone]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/21/introducing-markdown-live-preview/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/21/introducing-markdown-live-preview/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fostering better, more meaningful collaboration is an integral part of DevOps and a key part of what GitLab, the complete DevOps Platform, unlocks for developers and their teams. While many developers or engineers feel more comfortable working locally on their machines and spend a majority of their time using a CLI to push code changes, with GitLab you can also use the Web Editor or Web IDE to collaborate and edit content in a much easier, faster, and approachable way.
Starting in GitLab 14.2, editing Markdown content in the Web Editor or Web IDE just got even better.
Introducing the realtime Preview Markdown editor
GitLab Flavored Markdown automatically renders Markdown content in an easy-to-read and easy-to-write plain text language. Although Markdown is inherently more “human-readable” …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Posts New Linux Patches Looking To Re-Enable ENQCMD Ahead Of Sapphire Rapids]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-ENQCMD-Restoring-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-ENQCMD-Restoring-Patches"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T20:25:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Intel is normally quite good with their new hardware support being in good shape well ahead of launch, their new code for supporting the ENQCMD functionality for the Data Streaming Accelerator (DSA) with Xeon "Sapphire Rapids" has been an exception. This summer the mainline Linux kernel disabled ENQCMD support since the code was "broken beyond repair" while now Intel engineers have sent out a new series looking to get it re-enabled...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CUPS 2.4 Coming Next Month, CUPS 2.5 + CUPS 3.0 Already In Planning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CUPS-2.4-Next-Year-Then-2.5-3.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CUPS-2.4-Next-Year-Then-2.5-3.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T19:02:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Printing micro-conference took place today during the Linux Plumbers Conference 2021 week. While it's hard to get excited about printers in 2021, it is exciting the renewed effort around CUPS with it now being back to effectively led by the community and CUPS founder Michael Sweet who left Apple. CUPS 2.4 is coming as the first feature release in quite a while and then CUPS 2.5 followed by CUPS 3.0 are already being talked about with features being discussed...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenVPN DCO Linux Kernel Module Aims To Offer Faster VPN Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenVPN-DCO-Kernel</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenVPN-DCO-Kernel"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T18:31:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenVPN has been implementing a kernel module for data channel offload (DCO) capabilities to enhance the performance of this virtual private network system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 470.74 Linux Driver Released With Several Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-470.74-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-470.74-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T13:47:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA has released their latest 470 series Linux driver point release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DXVK 1.9.2 Released With More Games In Better Shape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-1.9.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-1.9.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T13:36:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DXVK 1.9.2 is out as the newest version of this key library necessary to the success of Valve's Steam Play (Proton) by translating Direct3D 9/10/11 calls to Vulkan for a much more performant Windows gaming experience on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust Lands Support For The Motorola 68000 Processors]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Rust-Adds-Motorola-M68k</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Rust-Adds-Motorola-M68k"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T13:02:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the m68k community continuing to be active around supporting the vintage Motorola 68000 series with modern open-source software, Rust has now merged support for these old processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Continues CRIU Work To Checkpoint/Restore ROCm Compute Workloads]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-ROCm-CRIU-XDC2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-ROCm-CRIU-XDC2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T12:21:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this year AMD went public with prototyping CRIU support for Radeon GPUs around ROCm to be able to checkpoint/freeze running compute workloads and to then restore them at a later point. This CRIU focus is driven by their big accelerator needs and forthcoming supercomputers for migrating workloads particularly within containers. AMD continues working on CRIU support for GPUs and last week provided an update on the project...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA Prepares The Linux Kernel For Future Laptops With EC-Driven Backlights]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-EC-Driven-Backlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-EC-Driven-Backlights"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T11:17:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA is contributing a new open-source driver to the upstream Linux kernel for dealing with upcoming laptops where the backlight controls are handled by the device's embedded controller (EC)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat's Upstream Contributions Are Making For A Great Fedora Workstation 35]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-35-Great-Features-Coming</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Fedora-35-Great-Features-Coming"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T10:00:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fedora Workstation 35 will hopefully be out at the end of October (currently the beta is running behind schedule) and when it does ship it's once again at the bleeding-edge of Linux features. Fedora Workstation 35 is shaping up to be another great release for those interested in a feature-rich desktop experience...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[xf86-input-libinput 1.2 Brings Touchpad Gestures, High Resolution Scrolling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=xf86-input-libinput-1.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=xf86-input-libinput-1.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T09:38:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those continuing to make use of the X.Org Server, xf86-input-libinput 1.2 is now available for integrating the latest functionality of libinput input handling library...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc2 Released With Many Fixes, Addressing Issues Raised By "-Werror"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-20T00:48:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc2 is now available as the latest weekly release candidate for this next version of the Linux kernel. Linux 5.15 in turn should be out as stable around the start of November...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HarfBuzz 3.0 Released With Unicode 14.0 Support, More APIs Considered Stable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=HarfBuzz-3.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=HarfBuzz-3.0"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T20:11:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HarfBuzz 3.0 has been released as a new version of this widely-used, open-source text shaping library that is used by the major Linux desktop environments along with Chrome OS, Java, Android, Chrome, and a plethora of other software projects and UI toolkits...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[That Didn't Take Long: KSMBD In-Kernel File Server Already Needs Important Security Fix]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SMB3-File-Server-Security-Fix</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SMB3-File-Server-Security-Fix"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T17:05:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was just a few weeks back that KSMBD was merged into Linux 5.15 while now it's seeing its first important security fix...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.16 To Support Sensor Readings On More ASUS Motherboards]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ASUS-WMI-NCT6775</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ASUS-WMI-NCT6775"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T10:19:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a change to the nct6775 hardware monitoring sensor driver, more ASUS motherboards should enjoy working sensor support come Linux 5.16...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jolla Releases Sailfish OS 4.2 For Continuing To Improve This Linux-Based Smartphone OS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Jolla-Sailfish-OS-4.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Jolla-Sailfish-OS-4.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T09:53:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jolla this week released Sailfish OS 4.2 "Verla" as the newest version of this Linux-based smartphone operating system that continues to be made commercially available for various devices...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SDL Still Has A Number Of Issues To Address Before Defaulting To Wayland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL-Wayland-State-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL-Wayland-State-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-09-19T09:45:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The recently released SDL 2.0.16 brought much-improved Wayland support but it's still not quite good enough yet to have it be the default over the SDL X11 path. However, developers continue working in that direction to eventually use it by default...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Is Now Slightly Less Broken For The DEC Alpha "Jensen"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Less-Broken-Jensen</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Less-Broken-Jensen"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T23:36:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One has to wonder how much longer the Linux kernel will keep around some very old and known to be borked hardware support but at least for now the DECpc AXP 150 "Jensen" platform support is sticking around and with Linux 5.15 is no longer marked as "broken" outright...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DRM Driver Posted For AI Processing Unit - Initially Focused On Mediatek SoCs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DRM-AI-APU-RFC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DRM-AI-APU-RFC"/>
        <updated>2021-09-18T17:12:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[BayLibre developer Alexandre Bailon has posted a "request for comments" of a new open-source Direct Rendering Manager (DRM) driver for AI Processing Unit (APU) functionality. Initially the driver is catering to Mediatek SoCs with an AI co-processor but this DRM "APU" driver could be adapted to other hardware too...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.2.4]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/17/gitlab-14-2-4-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/17/gitlab-14-2-4-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.2.4 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
last month's 14.2 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Removes cleanup job from Terraform.latest
Run AWS Release rake task only if on latest stable tag
Fix Elastic::MigrationWorker current_migration
Derive virtual storage's filesystem id from its name
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running Linux 5.15-rc1 Causing A New Slowdown... Here's A Look]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30531</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30531"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As usual when the Linux 5.15 merge window began wrapping up, I set out to dive into its performance to see what is in store for this next version of the kernel and whether there was any regressions or other performance changes worth noting. Linux 5.15 overall has been in good shape for the "-rc1" state except noticing that code compilation workloads were taking longer on multiple Linux 5.15-rc1-running systems than Linux 5.14 or prior. Seeing it across multiple systems and a very real-world regression, it was worth bisecting and looking closer so here are the details.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.1]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.1"/>
        <updated>2021-09-16T06:39:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: Unexpected nested element in author field crashes the parser
Thank you @ad-m]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How QPage achieved automatic deployment and efficiency using the GitLab DevOps Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/15/qpage-on-the-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/15/qpage-on-the-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deployment automation is essential for any company involved in software development to stay competitive. QPage, a company that provides an end-to-end sourcing and recruitment solution for SMEs, realized it quickly and migrated to GitLab’s DevOps Platform to accelerate their deployment process.
We spoke with Pouya Lotfi, the co-founder of QPage, to see how they use GitLab at QPage and how it has helped the company.
Why GitLab?
QPage was initially using a local bespoke CI/CD for about the first two months, but they soon realized they needed a more professional DevOps Platform system. Because Pouya and the team at QPage had already used GitLab at a previous employer, they knew it would be the right fit. So, they didn’t consider other options and opted for GitLab straight away.
Everything you …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA RTX 30 Series Resizable BAR Support Continues Helping Performance On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30523</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30523"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T13:09:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While NVIDIA has been supporting Resizable BAR for a while now with their GeForce RTX 30 series graphics cards, for those exclusively using Linux it remains more of a challenge due to AIB partners generally not releasing any vBIOS updates for ReBAR support that can be easily applied under Linux. But if you do carry out an update -- such as under Windows -- the performance uplift can be worthwhile if using a game that can benefit from the support.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use Terratag to automatically manage tags and labels for your Terraform Code]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/14/gitlab-together-with-terratag-open-source-to-help-you-manage-terraform-resources/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/14/gitlab-together-with-terratag-open-source-to-help-you-manage-terraform-resources/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When using infrastructure as code (IaC) on a public cloud provider, it's important to use tags and labels to organize your IaC using their complementary services. Terratag, an open source project developed by env0, can be used with Terraform and placed on top of the GitLab CI/CD platform, making tagging and labeling IaC easier and more efficient.
GitLab and Terraform make it easy to tag and label infrastructure as code.
Inside your toolbox
GitLab the industry's leading DevOps platform. Not long ago, we announced the ability to control Terraform deployments, remote state management, private module registry, and merge request integration for Terraform. This gives users a range of solutions for running CI/CD for Terraform code and managing it on a large scale.
Terraform is the most widely ado…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Weet integrates localization into the GitLab pipeline with Lokalise]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/13/lessons-weet-learned-lokalise/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/13/lessons-weet-learned-lokalise/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a GitLab customer, Weet has fully invested in the premise of "Iterate faster, innovate together." Weet has a low tolerance for processes that don't keep pace with the way they develop and launch. One important process that was slowing the business down – localizing their app.
Localization is a key way to drive growth and accelerate product adoption. When done poorly, localization or l10n, as it's commonly known, can slow down your development process, introduce bugs, and make it cumbersome to launch updates. When done right, teams can smooth out the process and continuously localize their app. We unpack how Weet conquered its localization problems using GitLab and Lokalise.
What is Weet?
Weet is an asynchronous video communication tool designed to reduce the need for meetings. By combin…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to deploy the GitLab Kubernetes Agent with limited permissions]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/10/setting-up-the-k-agent/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/10/setting-up-the-k-agent/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GitLab Kubernetes Agent (agentk) is an active in-cluster component for solving GitLab and Kubernetes integration tasks in a secure and cloud native way. The agentk communicates to the GitLab Kubernetes Agent Server (kas) to perform GitOps operations.
In many examples, we see the agent being deployed with global-level permissions on your cluster. There are use cases where we want to reduce the scope of what agentk has access to. In this guide I will provide information on deploying agentk on your cluster, limiting what namespaces it can access, as well as using it to deploy your applications.
Prefer a video? Watch the walkthrough below to learn how to deploy agentk to your cluster:


How it works
Anytime a developer performs changes to a manifest file managed within GitLab, the agentk w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The benefits of DevOps practices for IBM Z]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/10/adopt-agile-and-devops-for-ibm-z/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/10/adopt-agile-and-devops-for-ibm-z/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As more organizations adopt open source software, DevOps and cloud computing, teams are moving towards a hybrid approach to application development and deployments. This is a particular challenge for siloed mainframe development teams that typically work within their own development tools – and those tools are are not the same ones used by their distributed developer counterparts. These disparate toolsets are not integrated between build, package, test, and deploy steps. GitLab aims to provide a unified enterprise-wide DevOps platform with enhanced support for IBM z/OS® applications. Here are three critical areas to focus on that can help bridge the gap between mainframe and "modern" DevOps development.
Common workflows for hybrid environments
DevOps is naturally aligned to Agile processes…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GitLab's 5 new code review features will make life easier]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/09/5-code-review-features/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/09/5-code-review-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the second in a series of blog posts looking at the challenges of code review and the ways a DevOps platform can help. Read the first post.
Code review can be one of the most deceivingly difficult things in delivering software faster. Given the high stakes involved, we've made some key additions to our DevOps Platform that focus on making the code review process as seamless and effective as possible. We believe the number one way to make code reviews effective is to provide context. Too often we think of code reviews as only "reading" and commenting on others' code - but what a good code reviewer does is understand the entire context of the proposed change. Context-driven code reviews should include factors like the issue that spurred on the change, how the change impacts non-obvio…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making the case for a DevOps platform: What data and customers say]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/08/making-the-case-for-a-devops-platform-what-data-and-customers-say/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/08/making-the-case-for-a-devops-platform-what-data-and-customers-say/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the struggle to release safer software faster, development teams are increasingly choosing a DevOps platform to help them get there. In our 2021 Global DevSecOps Survey we asked respondents what their DevOps practices included and a "DevOps platform" was among the top four choices, right next to CI/CD, test automation, and DevSecOps.
We're of course bullish on the idea of a DevOps platform, but we're far from alone. Here's a fresh look at how the data – and the customers – support the optimistic trajectory of a DevOps platform.
DevOps is hot
The DevOps market was worth $6 billion in 2020, according to Global Industry Analysts, and five-year growth forecasts range from $17 billion to as much as $23 billion, depending on the firm. 
[Watch a deep dive into GitLab's DevOps Platform]
This pr…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to write and continuously test vulnerability detection rules for SAST]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/08/write-vulnerability-detection-rules/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/08/write-vulnerability-detection-rules/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In summer 2021, the Vulnerability Research and Static Analysis
teams launched the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) project: Write vulnerability detection rules for SAST.
For this project, we built and implemented a framework to helps transition GitLab away from our current SAST tools over to Semgrep. Semgrep is a language-agnostic SAST tool that is gaining popularity in CI/CD environments.
Before replacing an analyzer with the corresponding Semgrep configuration (called rule-sets), we need to ensure that they are equivalent – in that they yield the same set of findings.
For this purpose, we built a testing framework that helps us assess the quality of a Semgrep rule-set. This framework has been used to guide the replacement of flawfinder, a C/C++ analyzer with a corresponding Semgrep rule-set.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are developers so vulnerable to drive-by attacks?]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/07/why-are-developers-vulnerable-to-driveby-attacks/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/07/why-are-developers-vulnerable-to-driveby-attacks/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As someone who spends a lot of time working with computers, I know how easy it is to grow over-confident with regards to security. My systems are patched, my firewall rules are tight, and I’m vigilant when it comes to just about anything that looks out of the ordinary.
No one’s hacking their way into my workstation, that’s for sure.
But my experience working as a hacker myself has shown me that the opposite is often true. Those of us who are more technical are often much more vulnerable to an attack due to the complexity of our working environments.
In this blog, we’re going to dive into the anatomy of something called a “drive-by attack,” where malicious code hidden within a website uses your own browser to attack your computer.
As an example, I’ll show you how our own Red Team was able t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The code review struggle is real. Here's what you need to know]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/03/the-code-review-struggle-is-real-heres-what-you-need-to-know/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/03/the-code-review-struggle-is-real-heres-what-you-need-to-know/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When making a list of the reasons to consider moving to a DevOps Platform, don't forget about code review, a critical piece of the process that's also an incredible source of frustration and delays to developers and their teams.
In our 2021 Global DevSecOps Survey, respondents told us code quality was the number one reason they chose DevOps. But, when asked what was most likely to delay a product release, code review – vital to code quality – was one of the top four culprits (the others were testing, planning and code development). 
The fact that code review is a pain point is hardly surprising, given that it can often require context-switching, communication, collaboration, and of course subject matter expertise. At a time when it's never been more urgent to release secure code as quickly…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The journey to a DevOps Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/the-journey-to-a-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/the-journey-to-a-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a recent blog post about the importance of a DevOps Platform, GitLab CEO Sid Sijbrandij outlined four phases through which organizations frequently travel as their practice matures. It’s a painful journey we see again and again when we meet new customers. It spans every industry and every company size, and it’s the most mature DevOps teams with the most at stake who’ve felt the most pain. 
Historically, if you wanted DevOps to work, you had to be prepared to pay for it. Just managing the backbone of DevOps – the toolchain -– has been a grind. Your “Jenkins Team,” your “GitHub Team,” or even, as one of our customers described, your “Duct Tape Team” (designed to hold it all together and patch holes), added no end value beyond keeping everything from falling apart. That’s a lot of investme…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What we learned about configuring Sidekiq from GitLab.com]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/specialized-sidekiq-configuration-lessons-from-gitlab-dot-com/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/02/specialized-sidekiq-configuration-lessons-from-gitlab-dot-com/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sidekiq in GitLab works perfectly well out-of-the-box in most use cases, but it requires a little more attention in larger deployments or other specialized cases. We've learned a lot about how to configure Sidekiq in large deployments by maintaining GitLab.com – one of the largest instances of GitLab in existence. We added some critical features to GitLab.com in the past year to make it easier to configure Sidekiq in a manner more consistent with the maintainer's guidance, having strayed from this path for some time.
We are publishing two blog posts devoted to this topic. In this first post, we will unpack how we configured Sidekiq for GitLab.com, and in our second post, we will explain how to apply this to your GitLab instance.
[Learn more about how we iterated on Sidekiq background jobs]…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 13.12.11]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-13-12-11-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-13-12-11-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 13.12.11 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
the 13.12 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
The main purpose of this release is to resolve high CPU usage by the Gitaly
server:
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Backport improved replication logic
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.10 and 14.1.5]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-14-0-10-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/02/gitlab-14-0-10-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.0.10 and 14.1.5 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
These versions resolve a number of regressions and bugs in the
14.0 and
14.1 releases.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
The main purpose of these two releases is to resolve high CPU usage by the
Gitaly server:
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Backport improved replication logic
Additionally, 14.1.5 includes the following fixes:
Geo: Replicate multi-arch containers
Run AWS Release rake task only if on latest stable tag
Important notes on upgrading
These versions do not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Summer of Code at GitLab – some intern highlights]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/01/gsoc-at-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/01/gsoc-at-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab participated in Google Summer of Code for the first time this year. We hosted four student interns to work with us on four different projects under the supervision of two or three mentors each.
For the past 16 years, Google has hosted the Summer of Code to introduce students to the world of open source. Over the summer, student interns work on a project with an open source organization and are closely mentored by the developers of the open source project. More than 200 organizations participated this year.
We started off the summer with a two-week long community bonding period to get our students familiar with how we work at GitLab and helped them set-up their local development environments. During the 10-week program we worked through scoped projects with regular check-ins and a fi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.2.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/01/gitlab-14-2-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/01/gitlab-14-2-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.2.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
last month's 14.2 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Geo: Replicate multi-arch containers
Reset severity_levels default
Create 14.2 In-app top 7 product highlights
Fix OrphanedInviteTokensCleanup migration
Fix Live Markdown Preview in personal and subgroup projects
Downgrade grpc from 1.38.0 to 1.30.2 for compatibility with older CPUs
Restore proper contents to toolbox ubi8 image
Only activate Git pack-objects hook if cache is enabled
Important notes on upgrading
This version does include post deploy db migrations. For multi-node deployments, it should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Security Release: 14.2.2, 14.1.4, and 14.0.9]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/31/security-release-gitlab-14-2-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/31/security-release-gitlab-14-2-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-31T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.2.2, 14.1.4, and 14.0.9 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your software build pipeline using code signing]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/30/secure-pipeline-with-single-sign-in/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/30/secure-pipeline-with-single-sign-in/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If there is one thing that recent cyberattacks at companies such as SolarWinds, Codecov, and Kaseya have taught us, it's that software build pipelines are being targeted for attacks more than ever before. Hackers are no longer just attacking the bits and bytes of source code that go into our products, but also the development, testing, and build infrastructure tools that are used to build these products.
Even if you believe your company is at low risk of an attack, it's also important to think about your customers. Businesses with high profile customers – like government agencies or large, multinational corporations that use your products – might have attackers target them by hacking your company, or more specifically, the software you provide them.
The incidents at Solarwinds, Codecov, an…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>