<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-08-12T00:21:44.884Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-08-12T00:21:44.884Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thunderbird 91 Released With Big Improvements For This Open-Source Mail Client]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Thunderbird-91-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Thunderbird-91-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-12T00:06:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thunderbird 91 is now available as the first major update in a year for this Mozilla mail client that is succeeding the Thunderbird 78 series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon RX 6600/6700/6800 XT: RADV vs. PRO Vulkan Driver Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30434</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30434"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With yesterday's launch day Radeon RX 6600 XT Linux review the benchmarks were conducted using the popular Mesa RADV open-source driver used by many Linux gamers considering it's the driver Valve has been relentlessly optimizing and is the default on most (or all) Linux distributions. For those wondering how the performance of RADV is comparing to that of AMD's closed-source "PRO" Vulkan driver distributed as part of the "Radeon Software for Linux" package, here are some benchmarks exploring that difference.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DXVK-Native Sees First Release For Easing Direct3D-To-Vulkan Game Porting On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-Native-First-Release</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-Native-First-Release"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T13:26:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DXVK has proven to be a huge success for improving the experience of running Windows Direct3D 9/10/11 games on Linux by translating those D3D calls to Vulkan. DXVK-Native meanwhile is the newer spin-off effort around providing a DXVK-based build native for Linux to help in game ports that still can then rely on their Direct3D renderer path...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi V3DV Driver Nearing Vulkan 1.1 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-Nears-Vulkan-1.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-Nears-Vulkan-1.1"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T13:13:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-source V3DV driver living within Mesa for providing Vulkan API support for modern Broadcom VideoCore graphics -- most notably found in the Raspberry Pi 4 and newer -- is nearing Vulkan 1.1 compliance...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Preparing Linux Kernel Support For "Unaccepted Memory"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Patches-Unaccepted-Memory</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Patches-Unaccepted-Memory"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest patch series from Intel engineers worth noting for the Linux kernel is around implementing support for on-demand "unaccepted memory". Unaccepted memory is supported by the latest-generation AMD EPYC processors but not yet supported under Linux for on-demand/as-needed handling while Intel is preparing the kernel support for their next-gen Xeon CPUs having this capability...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMDVLK 2021.Q3.4 Driver Fixes "Horrifically Broken" Switchable Graphics Layer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDVLK-2021.Q3.4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDVLK-2021.Q3.4"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T10:05:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been less than one week since the AMDVLK 2021.Q3.3 update for this official open-source Radeon Vulkan Linux driver while today AMD has issued its latest update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polychromatic 0.7 Released With Improved UI For Configuring Gaming Keyboards, Mice]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Polychromatic-0.7</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Polychromatic-0.7"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T09:42:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Polychromatic as the long-running, third-party, open-source project to allow Razer's gaming peripherals like mice and keyboard to be configured under Linux is out with a major update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Libre-SoC Pursuing New Crypto Primitives & Instructions For OpenPOWER]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Libre-SoC-Crypto-Project</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Libre-SoC-Crypto-Project"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Libre-SoC began as "Libre RISC-V" envisioned as a low-power graphics/Vulkan accelerator, it has morphed into a hybrid CPU/GPU design built on OpenPOWER and in very early form seeing test fabrication on a TSMC 180nm process. The latest funding received is now working on adding cryptographic improvements to it and/or the upstream OpenPOWER ISA...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Graphics Driver Queues More DG2 Code For Linux While Removing Cannon Lake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Linux-5.15-DG2-CNL</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Linux-5.15-DG2-CNL"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel has another big batch of open-source kernel graphics driver updates it sent out to DRM-Next for queuing ahead of the upcoming Linux 5.15 cycle. The DG2 graphics card is getting wired up while this pull request does also finally remove the Cannon Lake "Gen 10" graphics that never materialized in commercial products...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ExpressVPN Opens Up Its Lightway VPN Protocol]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ExpressVPN-Lightway-OSS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ExpressVPN-Lightway-OSS"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T22:47:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year major VPN provider ExpressVPN announced "Lightway" as their new virtual private network protocol designed for speed, stability, and reliability. ExpressVPN announced today they are now making the protocol open-source...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[elementary OS 6.0 Released For A Meticulously Crafted Linux Desktop]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Elementary-OS-6.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Elementary-OS-6.0"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T19:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Elementary OS Linux distribution known for its very polished and well crafted desktop experience is out with its big 6.0 "Odin" update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon Software for Linux 21.30 Brings Support For Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS, RX 6600 XT]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Radeon-Software-Linux-21.30</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Radeon-Software-Linux-21.30"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T18:05:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the Radeon RX 6600 XT review embargo lifted and the cards set to hit retail channels this week, the Radeon Software for Linux 21.30 driver has been released in now officially supporting the RX 6600 series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SDL 2.0.16 Released With Better Wayland Support, PipeWire Integration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL-2.0.16-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL-2.0.16-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T17:45:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SDL 2.0.16 is officially out today as the latest update to this widely-used cross-platform library for serving as an abstraction layer around graphics, controllers / input, and more that makes it widely used by cross-platform games as well as the likes of the Steam Runtime...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 470.63.01 Linux Driver Brings RTX A2000, Vulkan Wayland Surface Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-470.63.01-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-470.63.01-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T17:14:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA today released their latest stable driver update in the 470 series for Linux users...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Radeon RX 6600 XT Linux Gaming Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30430</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30430"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T13:00:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Radeon RX 6600 XT was announced at the end of July as AMD's newest RDNA2 graphics card and is optimized for a performant 1080p gaming experience. For those wondering about its performance, this morning the embargo lifts to be able to talk about its performance. Here are the first Linux gaming benchmarks of the Radeon RX 6600 XT against a wide assortment of other AMD Radeon and NVIDIA GeForce graphics cards.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 91 Released As New ESR Base, HTTPS First Policy For Private Mode]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-91-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-91-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firefox 91.0 is out this morning as the latest monthly update to Mozilla's cross-platform web browser...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RADV Lands Fast Clear Improvements, Helping RDNA With VKD3D-Proton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Fast-Clear-Improvements</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-Fast-Clear-Improvements"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T12:39:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Samuel Pitoiset of Valve's Linux graphics driver team has been working on a number of improvements in recent days to the RADV Vulkan driver's handling around delta color compression (DCC) fast clears...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Preparing 5-Level Paging Linux Support For Future CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-5-Level-Paging-KVM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-5-Level-Paging-KVM"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Future AMD CPUs -- potentially AMD EPYC 7004 "Genoa" -- will be supporting 5-level paging...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alder Lake P Support Added To Intel's IGC Graphics Compiler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-IGC-Alder-Lake-P</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-IGC-Alder-Lake-P"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T09:59:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Graphics Compiler "IGC" that is used by their Windows driver as well as the Intel Compute Runtime for OpenCL / Level Zero support (and potentially the Mesa drivers in the future) has now landed Alder Lake P enablement...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1 Will Aim To Release In The Coming Weeks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1-Coming</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1-Coming"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T06:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It looks like X.Org Server 21.1 (long in development the past few years as X.Org Server 1.21) will see a stable release in the coming weeks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use a push-based approach for GitOps with Terraform and AWS ECS and EC2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/10/how-to-agentless-gitops-aws/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/10/how-to-agentless-gitops-aws/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In part two of our GitOps series, we described how to use a push-based (or agentless) approach for GitOps by using GitLab scripting capabilities as well as integrating infrastructure-as-code tools into GitOps pipelines. In this third blog post, we’ll also dig deep into how to use a push-based approach, but this time our focus will be on the integrations of Terraform, AWS ECS, and AWS EC2 in GitOps flows. This approach may be preferable when using infrastructure components that aren't Kubernetes, such as VMs, physical devices, and cloud-provider services.
Similar to Ansible – an agentless IT automation solution – Terraform can be leveraged by the scripting capabilities of GitLab to shape your infrastructure. GitLab also provides out-of-the-box integrations with Terraform, such as GitLab-man…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 13.12.10]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/10/gitlab-13-12-10-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/10/gitlab-13-12-10-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 13.12.10 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
May's 13.12 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Fix: Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Do not create audit event for failed logins on read-only DB
Fix validation method regarding MIME type keys
Resolve "operator does not exist" in app/models/namespace/traversal_hierarchy.rb
gitlab-rails: checks/postgresql detect silent NoDatabaseError
Adding -ubi8 to version to find UBI images
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Fully Embracing LLVM For Their C/C++ Compilers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-LLVM-Adoption-C-CPP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-LLVM-Adoption-C-CPP"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T22:31:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's next-generation C/C++ compilers are fully leveraging the LLVM compiler stack in place of their former proprietary compiler code-base. Intel has "complete[d] adoption" of LLVM moving forward for their C/C++ compiler needs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux "sev_secret" Patches For Tapping Confidential Computing Secret Areas In AMD SEV]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-AMD-sev_secret</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-AMD-sev_secret"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest AMD SEV work happening to the Linux kernel for benefiting EPYC servers with virtualization is the new "sev_secret" module for allowing guests to access confidential computing secret areas...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle Sends Out Newest Patches For Trenchboot / Secure Launch For The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Trenchboot-Linux-v3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Trenchboot-Linux-v3"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T17:37:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For more than one year now Oracle engineers have been working on Trenchboot support for securely booting the Linux kernel. Sent out today is the third revision of this work for establishing a dynamic root of trust for measurement...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arch Linux, Clear Linux & Ubuntu Against Windows 10/11 On Intel Rocket Lake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30426</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30426"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T13:05:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month after Microsoft began publishing their Windows Insider Preview builds of Windows 11, I ran some early Windows 11 benchmarks against Linux using an AMD Ryzen 9 5950X. Linux led in those benchmarks on the AMD Zen 3 desktop while for those wondering if that still holds true for Intel hardware, here are benchmarks of a Core i9 11900K "Rocket Lake" desktop with Windows 10 21H1, Windows 11 in its latest preview build as of testing, and then compared to Arch Linux / Clear Linux / Ubuntu.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rav1e 0.5 Beta Released For This Rust-Written AV1 Encoder]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Rav1e-0.5-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Rav1e-0.5-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T11:56:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Audio/video encoders and decoders are one of the areas where usage of the Rust programming language has increasing interest for speed and safety. One of the most promising Rust-written encoders at the moment is Rav1e for AV1 video encoding and it's now working towards its v0.5 release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RadeonSI Lands Regression Fix For ~10x Higher CPU Usage For Some Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-Too-Many-Variants</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RadeonSI-Too-Many-Variants"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T11:17:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged one month ago was RadeonSI enabling by default its optimization to replace uniforms with literals inside shaders. This uniform inlining helped with SPECViewPerf and other workloads but it turns out in the process sharply drove up CPU usage when running some games...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.0, Linux 5.11 Prepared For Ubuntu 20.04 LTS Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-20.04.3-LTS-Coming</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-20.04.3-LTS-Coming"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T10:11:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS is expected later this month as the next point release to the "Focal Fossa" long-term support cycle. With this update comes the hardware enablement stack from Ubuntu 21.04 which in turn means Linux 5.11 and Mesa 21.0 graphics support is available as package updates now...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synopsys Looks To Remove Oldest ARC CPU Support From The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ARC750-Drop-Linux-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ARC750-Drop-Linux-Patches"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Synopsys is looking to phase out support for the oldest ARC processors found within the mainline Linux kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Ways to scale remote work on your team]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/09/five-ways-to-scale-remote-work/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/09/five-ways-to-scale-remote-work/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At GitLab, we believe that remote work at scale will define not only the future of work, but the future of living. We created REMOTE by GitLab to bring together the remote work community and answer the questions many companies are asking: "How do we do this, and what's next?"
We heard from some of the top leaders in remote work, from large companies that made the decision to leave the office behind, to teams of experts who have been studying the organizational design for years.
We share five lessons from the REMOTE by GitLab event that your team can apply to uplevel your remote practices and culture.
Set guiding principles for your remote transition (and stick to them)
As you navigate the changes that come with implementing remote-first practices, it's important to have a set of values and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.14-rc5 Released - "Looking Perfectly Normal"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-rc5-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-rc5-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-08T21:04:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds just released the fifth weekly release candidate of Linux 5.14 and he's happy with how it's shaping up a few weeks before release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[0 A.D. Alpha 25 Released For This Open-Source RTS Game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=0-AD-Alpha-25</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=0-AD-Alpha-25"/>
        <updated>2021-08-08T13:40:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[0 A.D. as the long in development real-time strategy game developed by Wildfire Games is out with its twenty-fifth alpha release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thunderbird 91 Is Flying Soon As First Major Mail Client Update In A Year]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Thunderbird-91-Coming-Soon</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Thunderbird-91-Coming-Soon"/>
        <updated>2021-08-08T11:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thunderbird 91.0 is approaching release as an annual feature release to this open-source, cross-platform mail client and RSS reader. Given the current release is Thunderbird 78 from last July, there is a lot in store for this "2021" update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arm SMCCC TRNG Driver Queued Ahead Of Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Arm-SMCCC-TRNG-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Arm-SMCCC-TRNG-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-08-08T10:43:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux kernel already supports making use of Arm's True Random Number Generator (TRNG) SMCCC interface within the random seed code while for the upcoming Linux 5.15 cycle an "arm_smccc_trng" driver is being added and will allow exposing the entropy to user-space...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[23% Cost savings and 36% performance gain by deploying GitLab on Arm-based AWS Graviton2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/05/achieving-23-cost-savings-and-36-performance-gain-using-gitlab-and-gitlab-runner-on-arm-neoverse-based-aws-graviton2-processor/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/05/achieving-23-cost-savings-and-36-performance-gain-using-gitlab-and-gitlab-runner-on-arm-neoverse-based-aws-graviton2-processor/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Companies in all industries and sectors have significantly invested in digital transformation and increased their software development capabilities. GitLab delivers modern DevOps with a complete DevOps platform. However, some organizations require self-managed GitLab and GitLab Runners, which creates added costs for hosting and running GitLab infrastructure. Our latest cost analysis and performance benchmarks show that customers can realize cost savings of up to 23% and performance gains of up to 36% by deploying the GitLab application and GitLab Runner on the Arm-based Graviton2 when compared to the x86 based M5/C5 EC2 instances.
Arm is a leading provider of silicon intellectual property (IP) for intelligent systems-on-chip (SoC) that power billions of devices. GitLab and Arm have collabo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How UBS created their own open DevOps Platform using GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/04/ubs-gitlab-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/04/ubs-gitlab-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UBS, the largest truly global wealth manager, uses GitLab to power DevCloud, a single DevOps Platform that allows for a cloud-based, service-oriented, software development lifecycle.
"GitLab is a fundamental part of DevCloud," said Rick Carey, Group Chief Technology Officer at UBS. "We wouldn't be able to have that seamless experience without GitLab. It allowed us to pull ahead of many of our competitors, and break down the barriers between coding, testing, and deployment."
During GitLab Virtual Commit 2021, Rick and Eric Johnson, Chief Technology Officer at GitLab, talked about how building DevCloud on GitLab's DevOps Platform allowed UBS to increase their development velocity, lower their infrastructure costs, and increase collaboration between engineers and non-engineering teams worldwi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the DevOps Platform era]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/03/welcome-to-the-devops-platform-era/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/03/welcome-to-the-devops-platform-era/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps has evolved since its infancy, over a decade ago. Swiss developmental psychologist Jean Piaget believed human cognitive development has four stages (sensorimotor, preoperational, concrete operational, and formal operational). Through each of these stages, the human mind obtains new knowledge while building and modifying memories to inform one's understanding of the world around them.
In the same way that people go through stages as they grow, markets and industries also go through stages of development. Over the years, DevOps has grown into a mature, business-critical practice.
As the DevOps industry expanded, so did the number and complexity of tool-project integrations within an organization. This was the result of three developments in DevOps:
Companies moved from monolithic arch…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Security Release: 14.1.2, 14.0.7, and 13.12.9]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/03/security-release-gitlab-14-1-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/03/security-release-gitlab-14-1-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.1.2, 14.0.7, and 13.12.9 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GitLab 14 satisfies the need for speed with modern DevOps]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/velocity-with-confidence/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/velocity-with-confidence/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How DevOps and NFS changed the game
What if I told you that one of the best-selling racing video game franchises of all time, the "Need For Speed" (NFS), and DevOps have more in common with each other than you think? Yes, you read that correctly, probably not the NFS (Network File System) you were expecting.
An appetite for change
For context, the NFS series originally set out to redefine a saturated, yet unsophisticated, racing video game market. Motivated by an appetite for change, the NFS user experience reflected the human connection to real cars and how they behaved, which was a big challenge for developers in the 1990s. Nearly 30 years ago, "The Need for Speed" forever changed the landscape of racing games, selling 150 million copies since its debut.

The original Need For Speed vide…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Orange made a first step toward CI/CD standardization with GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/how-orange-uses-gitlab-ci-cd-for-modern-devops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/how-orange-uses-gitlab-ci-cd-for-modern-devops/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CI/CD is a foundational piece to modern software development. It's a major brick in the DevOps "Automation" pillar and every company involved in IT has to implement CI/CD or they're already quite far behind the curve.
But implementing CI/CD can be challenging especially for growing or large companies. Some of those challenges include:
DevOps expertise and technical skills
DevSecOps
Standardization
Three key hurdles that come with implementing CI/CD
This blog post unpackes these challenges and explains how Orange overcame them using GitLab.
DevOps and technical skills
No matter which CI/CD tool you're using, it requires some amount of expertise to implement it right.
DevOps expertise is important because your team needs some experience with Git workflows, deployment, environments, secrets m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your container images with GitLab and Grype]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/28/secure-container-images-with-gitlab-and-grype/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/28/secure-container-images-with-gitlab-and-grype/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The importance of container image security
Thanks to containers, what it means to "ship software" has changed dramatically. Engineering teams have shifted to produce container images and use these container images to deploy their software. Because of this change teams are now shipping significantly more software alongside their app – whether they realize it or not.
Besides packaging an application, container images also include hundreds of binaries and libraries. These binaries and libraries are included in the container image produced by the team because the process of creating a container image requires teams to select a base image. A base image is a preexisting container image on which to "base" their own container image. In doing so, all software contained in the base image is inherite…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.1.1]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/28/gitlab-14-1-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/28/gitlab-14-1-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.1.1 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.1 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Extend RackAttack basic authentication detection for rate limiting
Enable bulk dismissal checkboxes on group vulnerability report"
Fix syntax highlighting inline background on darkmode
Fix: Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Prevent terms from being created if blank
Remove backfill migration for ci_build_trace_sections
Geo: Fix snippet verification by replicating the HEAD ref
Remove securityScansSucceeded from DevOps adoption
Fix markdown in development docs
Fix deployer task
Don't ask users to upgrade to PG 13 yet
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing the GitLab Helm Package Registry]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/26/gitlab-helm-package-registry/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/26/gitlab-helm-package-registry/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud native application architectures use containerization, microservices, and Kubernetes to run reliably at cloud-scale. With a built-in container registry and Kubernetes integration, GitLab is the best way to develop and deploy cloud native applications. GitLab version 14.1 also includes a Helm registry, which allows users to publish, install, and share Helm charts and packages from within our single application for the entire DevOps lifecycle.
What is Helm?
Helm is a package manager for Kubernetes. A Chart is a Helm package that contains the resource definitions required to run an application inside a Kubernetes cluster. Helm allows you to manage complex applications by storing the application definition in a chart that can be versioned, shared, and collaborated on.
The differences bet…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use a push-based approach for GitOps with GitLab scripting and variables]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/how-to-agentless-gitops-vars/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/how-to-agentless-gitops-vars/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In part one of our GitOps series, we described how to use a pull-based (or agent-based) approach. In this second blog post, we'll dig deep into how to use a push-based approach. The agentless approach may be preferable for situations with non-Kubernetes infrastructure components or when you don't want to install, run, and maintain agents in each infrastructure component for GitOps. In this post, we will discuss how the scripting capabilities of GitLab can be used in GitOps workflows, and how to use predefined GitLab variables to shape infrastructure components.
About a push-based or agentless approach
With the agentless approach, infrastructure expressed and managed as code on GitLab, and updates and drift detection are automated and handled by GitLab without having to install any agents o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Package Hunter: A tool for detecting malicious code in your dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/announcing-package-hunter/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/announcing-package-hunter/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern programming ecosystems make code reuse exceptionally easy. No matter the
programming task at hand, chances are there is a package in a public registry
such as rubygems.org or npmjs.com that implements that task.
While the reuse of publicly available packages reduces the time necessary to write an app, this reuse
brings its own set of challenges. Apps quickly depend on hundreds of packages,
and programmers often simply just trust that these packages don't contain malicious code.
In an ideal world, all depended-upon code is thoroughly vetted before being included in a program – however, this is often unfeasible in practice due to the sheer amount of dependency code that needs to be reviewed and the lack of existing tools to help with vetting dependency code.
Malicious code in the wild…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab 14.1 released with Helm Chart Registry and Escalation Policies]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/22/gitlab-14-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/22/gitlab-14-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are excited to announce the release of GitLab 14.1 with the ability to build, publish, and share Helm charts, create escalation policies to page responders, connect GitLab Runners to your Kubernetes clusters, enforce code coverage decisions, and much more!
These are just a few highlights from the 50+ improvements in this release. Read on to check out all of the great updates below.
To preview what's coming in next month’s release, check out our Upcoming Releases page, which includes our 14.2 release kickoff video.
Join us for GitLab Commit Virtual to learn how DevOps teams increase collaboration.









This month's Most Valuable Person (MVP) is
Andrew Smith

Andrew actively contributed numerous merge requests in the GitLab 14.1 release to help improve GitLab’s planning capabil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimize DevOps with enhanced visibility tools in GitLab 14]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/21/optimizing-devops-visibility-in-gitlab-14/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/21/optimizing-devops-visibility-in-gitlab-14/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps makes teams and work more efficient, more consistent, and more productive – but how much more?
On its surface, the answer is simple. We need to measure workflow from idea to delivery, identify and remove blockers, and benchmark improvements in a manner that is consistent and replicable. The challenge is the way we've typically built the systems that hold the data we're trying to understand.
Enhanced visibility tools are essential to measuring and optimizing modern DevOps processes, and mapping the work output to ensure the business outcomes that matter are achieved.
The failure of DIY DevOps
Most businesses operate and maintain a multi-product "DIY DevOps" toolchain, but stitched-together applications with bespoke integrations don't lend themselves to visibility. Each component in t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are you ready for the newest era of DevSecOps?]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/are-you-ready-for-the-newest-era-of-devsecops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/are-you-ready-for-the-newest-era-of-devsecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Security is on everyone's radar, from board members to inquisitive grandparents. Everyone wants to know what software development teams are doing to protect their applications from attacks like that of Colonial Pipeline, Solarwinds, and others. With the launch of GitLab 14, we accelerated modern DevOps by bringing velocity with confidence, built-in security, and visibility, into DevOps success.
The modern DevOps solution is platform-driven, has a unified data store, and has security embedded throughout the software development lifecycle (SDLC). We find that it is these three attributes that drive demand for a modern DevOps solution among many different types of businesses.
Security in the modern DevOps solution goes beyond just shifting security features left to empower the developers to f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab introduces updates to paid tiers for improved billing and subscription management]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/improved-billing-and-subscription-management/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/improved-billing-and-subscription-management/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What you need to know
GitLab moves from annual true-ups to quarterly subscription reconciliation
Introduces cloud licensing and auto-renewals for improved license management
Requires collection of operational data for customer success services
Applicable to new customers from August 1, 2021 and existing customers at their next renewal
Today, we are announcing changes to improve the billing and subscription management experience for customers. While quarterly subscription reconciliation benefits both our SaaS and self-managed customers, the three other improvements, including the collection of operational data for customer success services, auto-renewals, and cloud licensing, will enhance the product and service experience for self-managed customers.
While other vendors are shifting to only…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.6]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/20/gitlab-14-0-6-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/20/gitlab-14-0-6-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.6 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Replace Excon with Faraday for requesting object storage
Fix LFS objects not downloading with Bitbucket
Resolve "Terraform module usage instructions are incorrect"
Geo: Fix snippet verification by replicating the HEAD ref
Fix validation method regarding MIME type keys
coordinator: Fix repo creation/removal race for up-to-date secondaries for 14-0-stable
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How teams can use the Gitpod integration in GitLab to speed up their development process]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/19/teams-gitpod-integration-gitlab-speed-up-development/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/19/teams-gitpod-integration-gitlab-speed-up-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Turn back time a bit and try to remember the first project you started or joined, and the onboarding experience. How long did it take to install the development environment on your local machine?
We talked about our own onboarding experiences into software development, and thought about sharing our favorite tips with GitLab users.
A developer's tale
Everyone starts fresh, and often best practices are just "learning by doing," requiring documentation in the same moment. Programming languages and application architectures are also different - a C++ backend environment has different requirements than a Ruby on Rails web application.
Start with defining the requirements and stages. Oftentimes they are equivalent to CI/CD pipeline stages but executed in your own environment.
Compile/build the a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>