<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-08-06T00:21:15.920Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-08-06T00:21:15.920Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FUTEX2 Patches Sent Out In Simpler Form For Helping Windows Games On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FUTEX2-Simpler-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FUTEX2-Simpler-Patches"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T19:20:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ongoing FUTEX2 work for making the futex handling more like Windows to in turn help Windows games on Linux via Wine (with a focus on Steam Play's Proton) has taken a new turn...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tyan Transport CX GC68B8036-LE AMD EPYC 7003 1U Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30422</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30422"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T13:06:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This summer we have been testing the Tyan Transport CX GC68B8036-LE as one of the company's newest options for those in the market for an AMD EPYC 7003 "Milan" 1U 1P barebones server. Across our wide range of Linux and BSD benchmarking this Tyan Transport CX GC68B8036-LE with Tyan S8036GM2NE motherboard has been holding up well and meeting our requirements and proven reliability in having tested Tyan products now at Phoronix for over the past 16 years.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung Revs Its In-Kernel SMB3 Server Focused On Fast Performance, New Features]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Samsung-KSMBD-v7</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Samsung-KSMBD-v7"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T10:23:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Samba is well known for SMB/CIFS server support on Linux and other platforms for supporting Microsoft's SMB networking protocol for file and print services, Samba is implemented in user-space while Samsung has been pursuing an SMB server implemented in kernel-space for better performance and wiring up new features that can be more easily accomplished within the kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 12's Static Analyzer Gaining Initial Assembly Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12-Analyzer-ASM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12-Analyzer-ASM"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T08:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Merged into the GNU Compiler Collection development code on Wednesday was an initial implementation of Assembly support for its analyzer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[23% Cost savings and 36% performance gain by deploying GitLab on Arm-based AWS Graviton2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/05/achieving-23-cost-savings-and-36-performance-gain-using-gitlab-and-gitlab-runner-on-arm-neoverse-based-aws-graviton2-processor/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/05/achieving-23-cost-savings-and-36-performance-gain-using-gitlab-and-gitlab-runner-on-arm-neoverse-based-aws-graviton2-processor/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Companies in all industries and sectors have significantly invested in digital transformation and increased their software development capabilities. GitLab delivers modern DevOps with a complete DevOps platform. However, some organizations require self-managed GitLab and GitLab Runners, which creates added costs for hosting and running GitLab infrastructure. Our latest cost analysis and performance benchmarks show that customers can realize cost savings of up to 23% and performance gains of up to 36% by deploying the GitLab application and GitLab Runner on the Arm-based Graviton2 when compared to the x86 based M5/C5 EC2 instances.
Arm is a leading provider of silicon intellectual property (IP) for intelligent systems-on-chip (SoC) that power billions of devices. GitLab and Arm have collabo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.2 Released With New Intel Crocus Driver, PanVK, Early M1 Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T19:30:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.2 is out as the latest quarterly update to this open-source Linux graphics driver stack for user-space, most notably providing the Intel and Radeon OpenGL/Vulkan drivers among others...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle Working On BPF CO-RE Support For GCC To Easily Run BPF Programs On Any Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BPF-CO-RE-For-GCC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BPF-CO-RE-For-GCC"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T19:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Running eBPF kernel programs continues to be increasing popular and used for a variety of use-cases in production environments but one of the challenges is around needing to compile the (e)BPF programs for a given kernel while BPF CO-RE has been working to change that. The LLVM Clang compiler already supports the ability for BPF "Compile Once, Run Everywhere" while now Oracle engineers are working to bring the same level of support to GCC...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Proposes Linux Kernel Driver Allow/Deny Filtering]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Driver-Filtering-Option</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Driver-Filtering-Option"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T18:13:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of their work around Trust Domain Extensions (TDX) support for Linux, Intel engineers are proposing a driver filter option for Linux to be able to set allow or deny lists of driver(s) that can or cannot be loaded by the booted kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arch Linux, Clear Linux, Fedora Compete On The ASUS ROG Strix G15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30414</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30414"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T12:45:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following last month's look at the ASUS ROG Strix G15 AMD Advantage laptop with Ryzen 9 5900HX processor and some of the initial hurdles seen on Ubuntu, readers were curious about how well other Linux distributions fared compatibility wise or if offering better performance elsewhere. Here are some tests across Arch Linux, Clear Linux, Fedora Workstation, and Ubuntu 21.04 for reference.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server Adds "Fake Screen FPS" Option]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-fakescreenfps</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-fakescreenfps"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T10:06:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The X.Org Server has picked up a new "-fakescreenfps" option to help with VNC and other remote  display scenarios...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many Interesting Talks On Deck For The X.Org Developers Conference 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XDC-2021-Scheduler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XDC-2021-Scheduler"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T09:45:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The program/schedule for this year's XDC21 X.Org Developers' Conference was posted this week ahead of the event occurring in mid-September. There are many interesting talks about X.Org and beyond, which in recent years largely revolve around Mesa and Wayland...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD PTDMA Driver Revised Ahead Of Its Possible Inclusion For Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PTDMA-Linux-v11</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PTDMA-Linux-v11"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the AMD patch series that has been in the works for more than one year is the PTDMA driver providing pass-through DMA engine support on Linux. The driver is now up to its eleventh revision but the mainlining might happen soon...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How UBS created their own open DevOps Platform using GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/04/ubs-gitlab-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/04/ubs-gitlab-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UBS, the largest truly global wealth manager, uses GitLab to power DevCloud, a single DevOps Platform that allows for a cloud-based, service-oriented, software development lifecycle.
"GitLab is a fundamental part of DevCloud," said Rick Carey, Group Chief Technology Officer at UBS. "We wouldn't be able to have that seamless experience without GitLab. It allowed us to pull ahead of many of our competitors, and break down the barriers between coding, testing, and deployment."
During GitLab Virtual Commit 2021, Rick and Eric Johnson, Chief Technology Officer at GitLab, talked about how building DevCloud on GitLab's DevOps Platform allowed UBS to increase their development velocity, lower their infrastructure costs, and increase collaboration between engineers and non-engineering teams worldwi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Hiring For Open-Source GPU Driver Work With Mentions Of Tesla Model S, Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Linux-Job-Tesla-Steam-Deck</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Linux-Job-Tesla-Steam-Deck"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With AMD's increasing marketshare on the CPU and GPU front, scoring more data center wins, and also scoring custom design wins for Linux-based environments such as with the Tesla Model S and most recently with the Steam Deck, AMD continues hiring more Linux engineers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon ROCm 4.3 Released With HMM Allocations, Many Other Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Radeon-ROCm-4.3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Radeon-ROCm-4.3"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T17:09:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD has released ROCm 4.3 as the newest version of their Radeon Open eCosystem stack for providing open-source GPU compute and CUDA portability for their supported graphics processors under Linux. ROCm 4.3 is the biggest update we've seen for this important enterprise piece to their enterprise GPU compute stack in a while...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Calls On Companies To Devote More Engineers To Upstream Linux, Toolchains]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-Security-More-Engineers</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-Security-More-Engineers"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Longtime kernel developer Kees Cook of the Google Security Team published a post on Google's Security Blog today effectively calling for more organizations to devote a greater number of engineers to the upstream Linux kernel in order to improve open-source security...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeWeavers Releases CrossOver 21 - Rebased On Wine 6.0]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CrossOver-21.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=CrossOver-21.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T15:54:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CodeWeavers has announced the release of CrossOver 21.0 as the latest major update to their commercial software powered by Wine for running Windows games and applications on Linux and macOS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sabrent Rocket 4 Plus 1TB NVMe PCIe 4.0 SSD On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30409</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30409"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T12:05:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year Sabrent launched the Rocket 4 Plus PCIe 4.0 NVMe solid-state drive and left me puzzled for months finding that the Linux performance was coming in short of expectations under Linux. However, Sabrent recently released a firmware update (v1.2) for the Rocket 4 Plus and now the drive seems to be much better positioned under Linux.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Pinot Makes It To The Organization's Top Shelf For Real-Time Big Data Analytics]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apache-Pinot-TLP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apache-Pinot-TLP"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T10:04:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After being started by LinkedIn and open-source now for more than a half-decade while incubating at the Apache Software Foundation the past three years, Apache Pinot is the latest project graduating to become a top-level Apache project...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM 13 Feature Development Is Over, LLVM 14 Enters Development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LLVM-13.0-Features-Over</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LLVM-13.0-Features-Over"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T09:51:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM 13.0 feature development has ended with the code now branched and the first release candidate tagged...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X-Plane Flight Simulator Continues Advancing Its Renderer With Vulkan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X-Plane-More-Vulkan-Future</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X-Plane-More-Vulkan-Future"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T08:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[X-Plane is not only the most realistic flight simulator that has long offered native Linux support but it's the only instance of a Vulkan-powered flight simulator I am aware of. While long tied to OpenGL, the company behind X-Plane is making it clear that the graphics rendering future is with Vulkan (and Metal when talking about Apple platforms)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git 2.33 Is On The Way With An Assortment Of Fixes, Updated Documentation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Git-2.33-rc0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Git-2.33-rc0"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Monday marked the release of Git 2.33-rc0 as the first test release of the next version of this distributed revision control system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the DevOps Platform era]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/03/welcome-to-the-devops-platform-era/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/03/welcome-to-the-devops-platform-era/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps has evolved since its infancy, over a decade ago. Swiss developmental psychologist Jean Piaget believed human cognitive development has four stages (sensorimotor, preoperational, concrete operational, and formal operational). Through each of these stages, the human mind obtains new knowledge while building and modifying memories to inform one's understanding of the world around them.
In the same way that people go through stages as they grow, markets and industries also go through stages of development. Over the years, DevOps has grown into a mature, business-critical practice.
As the DevOps industry expanded, so did the number and complexity of tool-project integrations within an organization. This was the result of three developments in DevOps:
Companies moved from monolithic arch…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Security Release: 14.1.2, 14.0.7, and 13.12.9]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/03/security-release-gitlab-14-1-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/03/security-release-gitlab-14-1-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.1.2, 14.0.7, and 13.12.9 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD SB-RMI Driver Coming For Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-SB-RMI-Linux-Sensor</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-SB-RMI-Linux-Sensor"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T20:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD continues pushing new code out for Linux in better exposing their platform's capabilities in the open-source world. The latest AMD driver work now queued via "-next" branches for introduction this autumn in Linux 5.15 is SB-RMI sensor support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WireGuard Sees Native, High-Performance Port To The Windows Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=WireGuardNT-Windows-Kernel</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=WireGuardNT-Windows-Kernel"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T18:13:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The excellent WireGuard open-source secure VPN tunnel has been seeing growing adoption on Linux now that it's been in the mainline kernel for a while and also seeing continued progress on the BSDs. While there has been beta WireGuard for Windows in user-space, "WireGuardNT" was announced today as a native high-performance port to the Windows kernel...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FWUPD 1.6.2 Released With Exciting Improvements For Hardware Firmware Updates On Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FWUPD-1.6.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FWUPD-1.6.2"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T17:54:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While FWUPD 1.5.12 released last week with expanded support for Poly web cameras, FWUPD 1.6.2 is out today as the newest feature release in their latest series. FWUPD 1.6.2 brings several significant improvements for advancing open-source firmware update capabilities on Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD + Valve Working On New Linux CPU Performance Scaling Design]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Valve-New-CPU-Freq</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Valve-New-CPU-Freq"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Along with other optimizations to benefit the Steam Deck, AMD and Valve have been jointly working on CPU frequency/power scaling improvements to enhance the Steam Play gaming experience on modern AMD platforms running Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Debian Improves Docs To Inform Users Their Systems Might Not Work Without Non-Free Firmware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Debian-Installer-Bullseye-RC3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Debian-Installer-Bullseye-RC3"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T10:38:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debian 11 "Bullseye" is set to be released mid-August while out this morning is the third release candidate of the Debian Bullseye installer. With this installer update is more documentation for users letting them know the risks of modern graphics cards and the like that are often inoperable unless loading firmware that isn't considered free software...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Work Is Back Underway On A Task Isolation Interface For The Linux Kernel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Task-Isolation-Interface-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Task-Isolation-Interface-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T10:09:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat's Marcelo Tosatti has submitted his latest patches implementing a basic task isolation interface for the Linux kernel that would be particularly useful for real-time workloads and high-bandwidth networking applications making use of user-space drivers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU C Library 2.34 Released With More Functionality Squeezed Into libc]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-C-Library-Glibc-2.34</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-C-Library-Glibc-2.34"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T09:53:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Version 2.34 of the GNU C Library (glibc) is now available with a wide variety of changes that accumulated over the past six months...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org's XEyes 1.2 Released, Other Updated X11 Components Too]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-xeyes-1.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-xeyes-1.2"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T09:29:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Several X.Org/X11 components saw new releases on Sunday for kicking off August, including the xeyes program seeing its first non-point release in eleven years...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[dav1d 0.9.1 Released With More Optimizations - Particularly For Older CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Dav1d-0.9.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Dav1d-0.9.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dav1d 0.9.1 was released on Sunday as the newest feature update to this leading open-source CPU-based AV1 video decoder...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.14-rc4 Released With Change Following Some Broken Android Apps, Other Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-rc4-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-rc4-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T00:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.14-rc4 is available today as a rather smooth update with nothing too worrisome but just a decent amount of fixes and nothing that is causing Linux creator Linus Torvalds to be frustrated...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Survey Shows Linux Marketshare Hitting 1.0%]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Linux-July-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Linux-July-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T00:15:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not only did Valve announce Steam Deck in July but the overall Linux gaming marketshare according to the Steam Survey also hit a multi-year high...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Adding Management Component Transport Protocol (MCTP)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-MCTP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-MCTP"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T18:42:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 is positioned now to see a Management Component Transport Protocol (MCTP) implementation with the code now queued in net-next with this being a protocol for communication between management controllers and managed devices...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GitLab 14 satisfies the need for speed with modern DevOps]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/velocity-with-confidence/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/velocity-with-confidence/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How DevOps and NFS changed the game
What if I told you that one of the best-selling racing video game franchises of all time, the "Need For Speed" (NFS), and DevOps have more in common with each other than you think? Yes, you read that correctly, probably not the NFS (Network File System) you were expecting.
An appetite for change
For context, the NFS series originally set out to redefine a saturated, yet unsophisticated, racing video game market. Motivated by an appetite for change, the NFS user experience reflected the human connection to real cars and how they behaved, which was a big challenge for developers in the 1990s. Nearly 30 years ago, "The Need for Speed" forever changed the landscape of racing games, selling 150 million copies since its debut.

The original Need For Speed vide…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Orange made a first step toward CI/CD standardization with GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/how-orange-uses-gitlab-ci-cd-for-modern-devops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/how-orange-uses-gitlab-ci-cd-for-modern-devops/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CI/CD is a foundational piece to modern software development. It's a major brick in the DevOps "Automation" pillar and every company involved in IT has to implement CI/CD or they're already quite far behind the curve.
But implementing CI/CD can be challenging especially for growing or large companies. Some of those challenges include:
DevOps expertise and technical skills
DevSecOps
Standardization
Three key hurdles that come with implementing CI/CD
This blog post unpackes these challenges and explains how Orange overcame them using GitLab.
DevOps and technical skills
No matter which CI/CD tool you're using, it requires some amount of expertise to implement it right.
DevOps expertise is important because your team needs some experience with Git workflows, deployment, environments, secrets m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your container images with GitLab and Grype]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/28/secure-container-images-with-gitlab-and-grype/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/28/secure-container-images-with-gitlab-and-grype/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The importance of container image security
Thanks to containers, what it means to "ship software" has changed dramatically. Engineering teams have shifted to produce container images and use these container images to deploy their software. Because of this change teams are now shipping significantly more software alongside their app – whether they realize it or not.
Besides packaging an application, container images also include hundreds of binaries and libraries. These binaries and libraries are included in the container image produced by the team because the process of creating a container image requires teams to select a base image. A base image is a preexisting container image on which to "base" their own container image. In doing so, all software contained in the base image is inherite…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.1.1]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/28/gitlab-14-1-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/28/gitlab-14-1-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.1.1 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.1 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Extend RackAttack basic authentication detection for rate limiting
Enable bulk dismissal checkboxes on group vulnerability report"
Fix syntax highlighting inline background on darkmode
Fix: Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Prevent terms from being created if blank
Remove backfill migration for ci_build_trace_sections
Geo: Fix snippet verification by replicating the HEAD ref
Remove securityScansSucceeded from DevOps adoption
Fix markdown in development docs
Fix deployer task
Don't ask users to upgrade to PG 13 yet
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing the GitLab Helm Package Registry]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/26/gitlab-helm-package-registry/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/26/gitlab-helm-package-registry/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud native application architectures use containerization, microservices, and Kubernetes to run reliably at cloud-scale. With a built-in container registry and Kubernetes integration, GitLab is the best way to develop and deploy cloud native applications. GitLab version 14.1 also includes a Helm registry, which allows users to publish, install, and share Helm charts and packages from within our single application for the entire DevOps lifecycle.
What is Helm?
Helm is a package manager for Kubernetes. A Chart is a Helm package that contains the resource definitions required to run an application inside a Kubernetes cluster. Helm allows you to manage complex applications by storing the application definition in a chart that can be versioned, shared, and collaborated on.
The differences bet…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use a push-based approach for GitOps with GitLab scripting and variables]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/how-to-agentless-gitops-vars/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/how-to-agentless-gitops-vars/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In part one of our GitOps series, we described how to use a pull-based (or agent-based) approach. In this second blog post, we'll dig deep into how to use a push-based approach. The agentless approach may be preferable for situations with non-Kubernetes infrastructure components or when you don't want to install, run, and maintain agents in each infrastructure component for GitOps. In this post, we will discuss how the scripting capabilities of GitLab can be used in GitOps workflows, and how to use predefined GitLab variables to shape infrastructure components.
About a push-based or agentless approach
With the agentless approach, infrastructure expressed and managed as code on GitLab, and updates and drift detection are automated and handled by GitLab without having to install any agents o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Package Hunter: A tool for detecting malicious code in your dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/announcing-package-hunter/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/announcing-package-hunter/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern programming ecosystems make code reuse exceptionally easy. No matter the
programming task at hand, chances are there is a package in a public registry
such as rubygems.org or npmjs.com that implements that task.
While the reuse of publicly available packages reduces the time necessary to write an app, this reuse
brings its own set of challenges. Apps quickly depend on hundreds of packages,
and programmers often simply just trust that these packages don't contain malicious code.
In an ideal world, all depended-upon code is thoroughly vetted before being included in a program – however, this is often unfeasible in practice due to the sheer amount of dependency code that needs to be reviewed and the lack of existing tools to help with vetting dependency code.
Malicious code in the wild…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab 14.1 released with Helm Chart Registry and Escalation Policies]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/22/gitlab-14-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/22/gitlab-14-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are excited to announce the release of GitLab 14.1 with the ability to build, publish, and share Helm charts, create escalation policies to page responders, connect GitLab Runners to your Kubernetes clusters, enforce code coverage decisions, and much more!
These are just a few highlights from the 50+ improvements in this release. Read on to check out all of the great updates below.
To preview what's coming in next month’s release, check out our Upcoming Releases page, which includes our 14.2 release kickoff video.
Join us for GitLab Commit Virtual to learn how DevOps teams increase collaboration.









This month's Most Valuable Person (MVP) is
Andrew Smith

Andrew actively contributed numerous merge requests in the GitLab 14.1 release to help improve GitLab’s planning capabil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimize DevOps with enhanced visibility tools in GitLab 14]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/21/optimizing-devops-visibility-in-gitlab-14/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/21/optimizing-devops-visibility-in-gitlab-14/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps makes teams and work more efficient, more consistent, and more productive – but how much more?
On its surface, the answer is simple. We need to measure workflow from idea to delivery, identify and remove blockers, and benchmark improvements in a manner that is consistent and replicable. The challenge is the way we've typically built the systems that hold the data we're trying to understand.
Enhanced visibility tools are essential to measuring and optimizing modern DevOps processes, and mapping the work output to ensure the business outcomes that matter are achieved.
The failure of DIY DevOps
Most businesses operate and maintain a multi-product "DIY DevOps" toolchain, but stitched-together applications with bespoke integrations don't lend themselves to visibility. Each component in t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are you ready for the newest era of DevSecOps?]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/are-you-ready-for-the-newest-era-of-devsecops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/are-you-ready-for-the-newest-era-of-devsecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Security is on everyone's radar, from board members to inquisitive grandparents. Everyone wants to know what software development teams are doing to protect their applications from attacks like that of Colonial Pipeline, Solarwinds, and others. With the launch of GitLab 14, we accelerated modern DevOps by bringing velocity with confidence, built-in security, and visibility, into DevOps success.
The modern DevOps solution is platform-driven, has a unified data store, and has security embedded throughout the software development lifecycle (SDLC). We find that it is these three attributes that drive demand for a modern DevOps solution among many different types of businesses.
Security in the modern DevOps solution goes beyond just shifting security features left to empower the developers to f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab introduces updates to paid tiers for improved billing and subscription management]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/improved-billing-and-subscription-management/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/improved-billing-and-subscription-management/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What you need to know
GitLab moves from annual true-ups to quarterly subscription reconciliation
Introduces cloud licensing and auto-renewals for improved license management
Requires collection of operational data for customer success services
Applicable to new customers from August 1, 2021 and existing customers at their next renewal
Today, we are announcing changes to improve the billing and subscription management experience for customers. While quarterly subscription reconciliation benefits both our SaaS and self-managed customers, the three other improvements, including the collection of operational data for customer success services, auto-renewals, and cloud licensing, will enhance the product and service experience for self-managed customers.
While other vendors are shifting to only…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.6]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/20/gitlab-14-0-6-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/20/gitlab-14-0-6-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.6 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Replace Excon with Faraday for requesting object storage
Fix LFS objects not downloading with Bitbucket
Resolve "Terraform module usage instructions are incorrect"
Geo: Fix snippet verification by replicating the HEAD ref
Fix validation method regarding MIME type keys
coordinator: Fix repo creation/removal race for up-to-date secondaries for 14-0-stable
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How teams can use the Gitpod integration in GitLab to speed up their development process]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/19/teams-gitpod-integration-gitlab-speed-up-development/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/19/teams-gitpod-integration-gitlab-speed-up-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Turn back time a bit and try to remember the first project you started or joined, and the onboarding experience. How long did it take to install the development environment on your local machine?
We talked about our own onboarding experiences into software development, and thought about sharing our favorite tips with GitLab users.
A developer's tale
Everyone starts fresh, and often best practices are just "learning by doing," requiring documentation in the same moment. Programming languages and application architectures are also different - a C++ backend environment has different requirements than a Ruby on Rails web application.
Start with defining the requirements and stages. Oftentimes they are equivalent to CI/CD pipeline stages but executed in your own environment.
Compile/build the a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitOps viewed as part of the Ops evolution]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/12/gitops-as-the-evolution-of-operations/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/12/gitops-as-the-evolution-of-operations/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitOps is a hot topic in the world of operations, but what does it provide to workflows that we didn’t have already? Looking at the evolution of the operations space, there have been many big changes in the past 20 years, and I argue that GitOps is not a change, rather a summary of best practices. So, how do we describe the major phenomenon in Ops over the past 20 years?
Before 2000, the primary approach to operations was to hire a System Administrator or empower Lead Developers to do Ops work. System Administrators knew a lot about networking and server optimisations, and a good sysadmin can do most of their work through code, using Bash, Perl or Python scripts. While every software engineer likely knows at least the basics of shell scripting, even many backend engineers would not be comf…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we’re creating a threat model framework that works for GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/09/creating-a-threat-model-that-works-for-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/09/creating-a-threat-model-that-works-for-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the first in a series of three blog posts where we discuss threat modeling and how we’re using it at GitLab to help secure our product, our company, and most importantly our customer’s data. As usual, we’re doing things a bit differently, but when you hear why it will make a lot of sense.
Threat modeling
Let’s start with the basics, what is threat modeling?
Threat modeling is the process of risk assessment for a particular project, asset, procedure, or product. While it can apply to nearly any established or new procedure, it seems to most often get applied to software. For GitLab, this would mainly apply to our source code.
As assessing risk has historically been the domain of the security department of most organizations, the threat modeling process has been nearly exclusively ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A brief look at Gitpod, two bugs, and a quick fix]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/08/two-bugs-and-a-quick-fix-in-gitpod/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/08/two-bugs-and-a-quick-fix-in-gitpod/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While looking at GitLab's Gitpod integration, I came across two rather critical flaws in Gitpod itself. In this post, I'll cover the process of identifying the vulnerabilities and some background on Gitpod. The more critical issue was fixed and the fix was pushed to production by the Gitpod team in less than five hours from my initial report. Huge kudos to the Gitpod team for that quick turnaround.
What is Gitpod?
First, let's see what Gitpod actually is – taken straight from gitpod.io:
Spin up fresh, automated dev environments for each task, in the cloud, in seconds.
That quote sums it up really well. You can login to Gitpod with your GitLab, GitHub, or Bitbucket account and then use a pretty full-blown, web-based development environment to work on your code, run tests, or even spin up se…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.5]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/08/gitlab-14-0-5-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/08/gitlab-14-0-5-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.5 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Resolve "404 for package details link under Infrastructure Registry for projects nested under 2 group levels"
Resolve "Terraform module usage instructions are incorrect"
Add documentation for boards epic create
Initialize conversion of ci_builds_metadata.id for bigint migration
Fix git clone for projects with a trailing dot over HTTP
Do not create audit event for failed logins on read-only DB
Add prefix to autocomplete path
Return empty strings for Jira links when URL is not set
Fix libmagic not being able to find magic files
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>