<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-10-19T00:38:06.179Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-19T00:38:06.179Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.04 LTS "Jammy Jellyfish" Begins Development]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-22.04-LTS-Development</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-22.04-LTS-Development"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T20:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical today formally opened the "Jammy" archive for development for what will be the next version of Ubuntu, 22.04 LTS "Jammy Jellyfish"...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Announces The M1 Pro / M1 Max, Asahi Linux Starts Eyeing Their Bring-Up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M1-Pro-M1-Max</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apple-M1-Pro-M1-Max"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T18:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple today announced the M1 Pro and M1 Max as their most powerful SoCs ever built by the company. The new chips feature up to a 10-core processor, 32-core GPU, and up to 64GB of unified memory...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valve Launches "Steam Deck Verified" Program For Games That Run Well On The Steam Deck]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Deck-Verified</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Deck-Verified"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T18:15:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve is introducing a Steam Deck Verified system for helping gamers find out what games have been verified to work well on their forthcoming AMD+Linux-powered handheld game console...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D-Proton 2.5 Released With Experimental DXR 1.1, More Games Working]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=VKD3D-Proton-2.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=VKD3D-Proton-2.5"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T16:04:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VKD3D-Proton as Valve's Direct3D 12 over Vulkan implementation for Steam Play's Proton is out with a big feature update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Radeon Gaming With KDE Plasma vs. GNOME Shell + Wayland vs. X.Org]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30617</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30617"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T12:14:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With last week's release of Ubuntu 21.10, here are some fresh benchmarks looking at the Linux gaming performance on this new release while testing both the GNOME Shell 40 default desktop to that of its KDE Plasma 5.22 based option. Both the X.Org and Wayland sessions for KDE and GNOME were benchmarked for seeing how the Linux gaming performance compares with the Radeon open-source GPU driver stack.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Habana Labs For Linux 5.16 To Bring Peer-To-Peer Support With DMA-BUF]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Habana-Labs-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Habana-Labs-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T10:38:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The drama around DMA-BUF code for the Habana Labs AI driver appears to be wrapping up with the Linux 5.16 cycle that is coming up...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 22.0 Lands Some Patches Toward OpenCL Image Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-22.0-OpenCL-Image-Prep</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-22.0-OpenCL-Image-Prep"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T09:29:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 22.0-devel is one step closer to having OpenCL image support that is sought after by many individuals for allowing more OpenCL-enabled desktop software to work nicely with this open-source OpenCL component in Mesa...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15-rc6 Ticks Up In Size, Stops Using AMD SME By Default]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc6-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-rc6-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T08:33:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linus Torvalds is out with Linux 5.15-rc6 and its increase in size has him slightly worried...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get started with GitLab's Helm Package Registry]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/18/improve-cd-workflows-helm-chart-registry/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/18/improve-cd-workflows-helm-chart-registry/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In our 14.1 release, we offered the ability to add Helm charts to the GitLab Package Registry. Here's everything you need to know to leverage application deployment with these new features.
The role of container images
The de-facto standard is to package applications into OCI Images which are often just referred to as container images and more often as Docker containers. The Open Container Initiative was launched in 2015 by Docker and other companies to define industry standards around container image formats and runtimes. GitLab introduced an OCI conform Container Registry with the release of GitLab 8.8 in May 2016.
Today, a common and widely adopted approach is to deploy applications with Helm charts to Kubernetes. This will be covered in this blog together with the feature release in Gi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux To No Longer Enable AMD SME Usage By Default Due To Problems With Some Hardware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-SME-No-Default-Use</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-SME-No-Default-Use"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Being sent in as a fix for the Linux 5.15 kernel this morning and to be back-ported to existing stable series is a behavior change that the Linux kernel will no longer use AMD Secure Memory Encryption (SME) by default on supported hardware but rather making it now opt-in due to shortcomings of some platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vortex86 Processors Finally Seeing Work In 2021 For Proper Handling Under Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Linux-Detection</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Linux-Detection"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T10:13:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Vortex86 32-bit SoCs have worked under Linux for those distributions still maintaining 32-bit x86 support and where not hitting corner-cases of some i686 level features not being supported by some Vortex86 cores, but there is finally a pending kernel patch to provide proper CPU detection for Vortex86 hardware...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Axboe Achieves 8M IOPS Per-Core With Newest Linux Optimization Patches]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=8M-IOPS-Per-Core-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=8M-IOPS-Per-Core-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-10-17T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was just last week that Linux optimizations were leading to possible 6M IOPS per core and then at the start of this week new patches pushed Linux past 7M IOPS per-core with an ideal hardware configuration as well. In ending out the week, 8M IOPS has been reached!..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rust-Based Cloud-Hypervisor 19.0 Released With Improved Live Migration, Faster Boot Time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Cloud-Hypervisor-19.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Cloud-Hypervisor-19.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T17:33:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud-Hypervisor 19.0 debuted this week as the Intel-led open-source VMM focused on supporting modern cloud workloads and written in the Rust programming language while leveraging the Linux's KVM virtualization code or the Microsoft MSHV hypervisor on Windows...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Realtek 802.11ax WiFi Driver "rtw89" Queued Ahead Of Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Realtek-802.11ax-rtw89</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Realtek-802.11ax-rtw89"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T09:40:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arriving in the wireless-drivers-next branch this week is the "rtw89" driver as a Realtek-contributed open-source 802.11ax WiFi driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE's Plasma Wayland Session Continues Seeing More Crash Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-More-Crash-Fixes-Coming</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-More-Crash-Fixes-Coming"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T09:27:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week marked the release of Plasma 5.23 in celebrating 25 years of the KDE desktop project while celebrations didn't last long with developers already hard at work on the Plasma 5.23.1 point release, feature work for Plasma 5.24, and also improvements to the KDE Applications and KDE Frameworks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bareflank Hypervisor 3.0 Pre-Release Debuts With Many Changes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bareflank-3.0-Pre-Release</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bareflank-3.0-Pre-Release"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T08:46:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-source Bareflank Hypervisor project designed to prototype new hypervisors across Intel, AMD, and AArch64 platforms issued their long-awaited 3.0 pre-release on Friday...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Genode-Based Sculpt OS 21.10 Adds Intel GPU Acceleration, USB Web Camera Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Sculpt-OS-21.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Sculpt-OS-21.10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T07:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Thursday in addition to the releases of Ubuntu 21.10 (plus its derivatives) and OpenBSD 7.0, the Genode OS Framework based Sculpt OS saw its 21.10 release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.3]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: broken links in documentation
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @hirdot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenCL 3.0.9 Specification Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenCL-3.0.9</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenCL-3.0.9"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T23:32:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Khronos Group's OpenCL working group did a quiet Friday evening tagging of OpenCL 3.0.9...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PinePhone Pro Announced As New Linux Smartphone]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PinePhone-Pro</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PinePhone-Pro"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The PinePhone Pro is being announced this morning as the organization's new smartphone building upon the successes and experience of the original PinePhone Linux smartphone...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Compute-Runtime 21.41.21220 Ships Updated DG1 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Compute-21.41.21220</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Compute-21.41.21220"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T13:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's open-source engineers have shipped Compute-Runtime 21.41.21220 as the newest version of this Linux compute stack enabling OpenCL and Level Zero support with their graphics processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AV1 Codec Library libaom v3.2 Brings More Performance Optimizations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AV1-libaom-3.2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AV1-libaom-3.2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T12:31:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Libaom 3.2 is now available as the latest version of the official AOMedia/Google-developed AV1 Codec Library. With libaom 3.2 comes compression efficiency improvements, perceptual quality improvements, and a variety of speed-ups and memory optimizations...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cluster Scheduler Support Queued Ahead Of Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Cluster-Scheduler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.16-Cluster-Scheduler"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T10:37:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cluster scheduler support has been queued up for landing in the Linux 5.16 kernel for AArch64 and x86_64 systems for improving the CPU scheduler behavior for systems that have clusters of CPU cores...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SALSA Back In Development As A Small ALSA Library For Linux Systems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SALSA-Linux-Audio-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SALSA-Linux-Audio-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T10:03:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux sound subsystem maintainer Takashi Iwai of SUSE is back to hacking on SALSA, the "small ALSA" library that he started a decade ago but hadn't seen a new release in six years or any code activity for the past four years... until this week...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Finally Enabling PSR By Default For Newer Hardware With Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Linux-5.16-PSR</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-Linux-5.16-PSR"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T09:33:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With it getting late into the Linux 5.15 kernel cycle, the focus is shifting by the Direct Rendering Driver maintainers from new feature work targeting the next cycle (5.16) to instead on bug fixes. AMD sent out a pull request of new AMDGPU Linux 5.16 material this week that is primarily delivering bug fixes but one notable addition is finally enabling PSR by default for newer GPUs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The "What If" Performance Cost To Kernel Page Table Isolation On AMD CPUs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30613</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30613"/>
        <updated>2021-10-15T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Made public this week by CPU security researchers at Graz University of Technology and CISPA Helmholtz Center for Information Security was the research paper published "AMD Prefetch Attacks through Power and Time". The paper points to AMD CPUs suffering from a side-channel leakage vulnerability through timing and power variations of the PREFETCH instruction. The paper argues that AMD CPUs should activate stronger page table isolation by default. AMD has now published their security response where they are not recommending any mitigation changes at this time. But what if Kernel Page Table Isolation (KPTI/PTI) proves necessary for AMD CPUs? Here are some initial benchmarks showing what that performance impact could look like.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1 RC2 Brings Fix For Mixed VRR/Non-VRR Multi-Monitor Setups]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1-RC2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=X.Org-Server-21.1-RC2"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T19:36:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[X.Org Server 21.1 continues running slightly behind schedule but out today is a second release candidate of that upcoming xorg-server version -- the first in more than three years...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Devuan 4.0 Released As Debian 11 Without Systemd]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Devuan-4.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Devuan-4.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T17:46:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Devuan 4.0 "Chimaera" is officially out today as the latest stable release of this Linux distribution known for being a close rebuild of Debian but without a dependence on systemd...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 Released With GNOME 40 Desktop, Many Underlying Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T14:53:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.10 "Impish Indri" is now officially available as the latest six-month update to Ubuntu Linux and also serving as the last release prior to the next long-term support cycle, Ubuntu 22.04 LTS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 495 Linux Beta Driver Released With GBM Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-495.29.05-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-495.29.05-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T13:36:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA 495.29.05 is out today as the first public Linux driver in the 495 series...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenBSD 7.0 Released With RISC-V 64-bit Port, Better Apple Silicon Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenBSD-7.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenBSD-7.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T13:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not only is Ubuntu 21.10 releasing today but over on the BSD side of the table is the debut this morning of OpenBSD 7.0...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[9-Way H2'2021 Linux OS Performance Comparison On Intel Xeon Scalable Ice Lake]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30607</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30607"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While we recently looked at autumn 2021 Linux distributions on Intel Tiger Lake for seeing how these various latest distributions are competing on client platforms, in today's article is a look at how well the latest Linux distributions perform when using the latest-generation Intel Xeon Scalable 3rd Gen "Ice Lake" server hardware with two Xeon Platinum 8380 processors. AlmaLinux, Arch Linux, CentOS Stream, Clear Linux, Debian, Fedora, openSUSE, and Ubuntu were battling it out on this Intel reference server.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 5.23 Released In Marking 25 Years Of KDE]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-5.23-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-5.23-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T10:22:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 5.23 is officially out this morning as the newest major open-source desktop release and is known now as the KDE 25th Anniversary Edition...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qt Creator 6 Beta Released With Updated C++ Code Model, Binaries Built Against Qt 6.2]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Qt-Creator-6-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Qt-Creator-6-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T10:15:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Qt 6.2 LTS having shipped at the end of September, The Qt Company is now turning their attention to Qt Creator 6 as the next version of their Qt/C++ focused integrated development environment...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Inc. takes The DevOps Platform public]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/14/gitlab-inc-takes-the-devops-platform-public/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/14/gitlab-inc-takes-the-devops-platform-public/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, GitLab Inc. announced the next milestone in our journey as we become a publicly traded company on the Nasdaq Global Market (NASDAQ: GTLB). GitLab was the first company to publicly live stream the entire end-to-end listing day at Nasdaq.
In a world where software defines the speed of innovation, every company must become a software company or they’ll be disrupted by a software company. We believe that GitLab, the DevOps Platform, helps companies to deliver software faster and more efficiently, while strengthening security and compliance. And it all happens inside our single platform where engineering, security, and operations teams can collaborate together.
In my Founder’s Letter, which you can read below, I told GitLab’s origin story. GitLab did not start in a tech incubator, garage…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab’s Kubernetes Operator with support for Red Hat OpenShift is now generally available]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/12/open-shift-ga/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/12/open-shift-ga/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, GitLab is pleased to announce the general availability (GA) of the GitLab-supported GitLab Operator, with the ability to run production instances of GitLab on Kubernetes platforms, including Red Hat OpenShift.
IT organizations that rely on Red Hat OpenShift can now deploy and run GitLab on the same infrastructure they trust for their other shared services. For many organizations in the public sector and regulated industries that only use Red Hat OpenShift, the Operator unlocks the ability to use GitLab, the DevOps Platform, allowing them to move out of the DIY DevOps stage and embrace modern DevOps practices with greater speed, efficiency, and improved security.
 



Why did we build the GitLab Operator?
We believe user expectations are at an all-time high. They expect always-on app…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab updates its cookie management tool]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/12/gitlab-updates-its-cookie-management-tool/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/12/gitlab-updates-its-cookie-management-tool/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We recently completed a review of our cookie management tool and have decided to take this opportunity to improve the overall experience for our users by unifying our cookie management tool across all GitLab Inc. domains.
GitLab committed to not sending  service usage data from our products (GitLab SaaS and self-managed) to a third-party product analytics service and we keep that commitment with this update.
What is changing?
We’re unifying our cookie management tool across all GitLab Inc. domains to improve the user experience. Starting on 2021-10-12 we will deploy the OneTrust Cookie Management Tool to manage cookies across all gitlab.com sites. This change will provide users with a central location to opt in or out of cookies that are not strictly necessary for our site and its subdomains, including docs.gitlab.com, about.gitlab.com and customers.gitlab.com.
We also plan to add  a cookie to our trial signup flow and to our commerce flows located inside the gitlab.com application to enable us to understand how visitors are engaging with these pages and to help analyze and and improve these flows and resolve any technical issues.  This cookie will not be used for any tracking of how you use the functionality of our SaaS or self-managed products, and users can opt in or out of this cookie through our cookie management tool.
What won’t change
We will not be adding additional metrics or mechanisms to collect analytics data from our core product (including all GitLab features and categories). We will continue to honor the Do Not Track (DNT) mechanism in web browsers for both GitLab.com and GitLab Self-Managed users.
Timeline and implementation
We plan to roll  out the new cookie management tool on 2021-10-12. This will replace our current cookie tool and will require users to review a new cookie notice and manage the settings of cookies on their next visit. Those settings will be retained per-device and per browser and can be modified after the original selection.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.3.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/12/gitlab-14-3-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/12/gitlab-14-3-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.3.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.3 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Fix dependency proxy image prefix
Drop taggings index if exists during migration
Fix 2FA setup for users with no password
Disable caching of MergeToRefService call in mergeability check
Delay praefect database_*_no_proxy removals
Update cacerts to 2021-09-30
Symlink OpenSSL default cert file to Debian cert path
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Threat modeling the Kubernetes Agent: from MVC to continuous improvement]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/threat-modeling-kubernetes-agent/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/threat-modeling-kubernetes-agent/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Threat modeling is more common in people’s everyday lives than they might think.  Each of us performs some level of threat modeling every time we’re in a situation where we’re evaluating threats. An everyday example I really like: crossing the street. Before we cross the street we look both ways, we evaluate the speed of each oncoming vehicle and verify the driver has seen us. Finally, if the lights are green, we cross the street. This is threat modeling!
If you’re interested in learning more about what threat modeling is and how we’re developing our threat model here at GitLab, you can read about “How we’re creating a threat model framework that works for GitLab“ by my teammate Mark Loveless.
Threat modeling IRL
In this blog post I’ll talk about how we put our threat modeling process into…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notice for GitKraken users with GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/notice-for-gitkraken-users-with-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/notice-for-gitkraken-users-with-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing details on a vulnerability found with the Axosoft GitKraken software. Axosoft found a defect in the key gen package used by GitKraken versions 7.6.0 to 8.0.0 that could generate weak or duplicate SSH keys. This could enable an attacker to gain unauthorized access to an account or repositories on GitLab.com or a self-managed instance.
Based on our investigations to date, there is no indication that GitLab.com or any projects on GitLab.com that use the GitKraken tool have been impacted by this vulnerability.
Who is affected?
This vulnerability affects GitKraken users who created SSH keys using GitKraken releases from May 12, 2021 (7.6.0) to the week of September 27, 2021 (8.0.0).
GitKraken 8.0.1, released on September 28, 2021, fixes the bug.
Action we have taken
We have emailed users with affected keys earlier today, October 11, 2021.
For GitLab.com customers, we have already blocked known weak keys.
If affected, action you need to take
If you used a version of GitKraken prior to 8.0.1 to generate SSH keys, we highly recommend that you take the following actions:
Self-managed customers:
Revoke the SSH keys immediately. For additional instructions, see: https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/admin_area/credentials_inventory.html#delete-a-users-ssh-key
Update GitKraken to the latest version: https://support.gitkraken.com/release-notes/current/
Generate new SSH keys: https://support.gitkraken.com/integrations/gitlab/#generating-an-ssh-key-for-gitlab
GitLab.com customers:
Update GitKraken to the latest version: https://support.gitkraken.com/release-notes/current/
Generate new SSH keys: https://support.gitkraken.com/integrations/gitlab/#generating-an-ssh-key-for-gitlab
More information can be found in Axosoft’s disclosure: https://www.gitkraken.com/blog/weak-ssh-key-fix 
and in CVE-2021-41117.
For questions or concerns regarding GitKraken or its use with GitLab, please contact Axosoft (support@gitkraken.com). For questions concerning your GitLab account, please contact our Support department.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How ten steps over ten years led to the DevOps Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/how-ten-steps-over-ten-years-led-to-the-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/how-ten-steps-over-ten-years-led-to-the-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first commit to GitLab (!!) was 10 years ago. Today, it’s an entirely different world: DevOps is increasingly mainstream and there's a DevOps platform revolution.
We didn’t have a crystal ball back then, but we did try to create a product, a culture and a company that reflected what we thought mattered most. Here’s a look back at 10 key decisions we made that still have impact:
Work in parallel: When we started, it was clear the waterfall method of software development - where one stage waited on another stage and nothing happened independently - slowed everything. We decided right from the beginning that a “work in parallel” philosophy would be fundamental to our culture and our behaviors. Also, such a philosophy naturally supported everything else we did, including bringing CI and CD…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updates to de-identifying Service Usage Data]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/08/updates-to-de-identifying-service-usage-data/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/08/updates-to-de-identifying-service-usage-data/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab has been working on a process to intentionally limit our own ability to identify individual users from Service Usage Data in order to protect user privacy even better. Earlier this year, we solicited input on plans to de-identify GitLab’s Service Usage Data. We are now ready to move forward with a new system to de-identify SaaS usage data before it enters GitLab’s internal analytics environment.
What isn’t changing?
The service usage data policy for SaaS and Self-Managed remains unchanged.
What is changing?
With user privacy in mind, we are building a pseudonymization process to run against our SaaS service usage data.
We have determined that we do not need fully identifiable information anymore for our analytics environment, and as such we are pursuing this approach that will result in better privacy for GitLab users.
We’ll create a one-way hash or transform directly identifiable data. This means that the data will be hashed at the collection layer before it is sent to our analytics environment.
You can read more details about our pseudonymization solution here. Once our pseudonymization solution is in place, we will update data we collect to ensure it follows the  solution. You can read more about what data we collect and its de-identification state here.
Timeline and implementation
We’re planning to roll out these changes in October 2021. Keep an eye on our Product Intelligence roadmap to monitor our progress. Once complete, we’ll update this blog post with the final status.
More information
Please find more information about our privacy policy. Further details on how service usage data is used for product improvement can be found on our Product Direction page. Also see  GitLab’s analytics environment and SaaS Data Collection Catalog.
Please share your questions on the community forum.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps salaries in 2021: where do you rank?]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/07/a-look-at-devops-salaries/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/07/a-look-at-devops-salaries/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the first in an occasional series of blog posts looking at DevOps salaries and careers.
Despite the COVID-19 pandemic and the subsequent economic crisis that has disrupted lives and business across industries and around the world, demand for DevOps professionals remains strong and salaries continue to increase.
The IT industry, in general, fared better than many during the economic uncertainty of 2020 and 2021. With a strong IT infrastructure already in place and IT professionals accustomed to working remotely, increased demand and short supply for IT workers meant IT salaries held steady or rose in turbulent times, reported Randstad, a multinational human resources consulting firm. 
And DevOps professionals did even better than most in IT.
DevOps salaries are on the rise
DevOps, s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to provision Ready-To-Run GitLab for 50,000 users with the AWS Quick Start]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/06/gitlab-cnh-for-50k-users/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/06/gitlab-cnh-for-50k-users/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you have spent time reviewing GitLab Reference Architectures, you may have noticed the flexibility of the GitLab codebase; it's possible to support a broad range of implementations from a single box for under one hundred users to horizontal hyper-scaled setups for 50,000 or more.
Scaling to massive sizes requires the services within GitLab to be broken out into dedicated compute and storage layers so they can each expand cost effectively based on high loading and an organization's specific usage patterns.
Those who provision large scale systems on the cloud generally turn to Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to ensure consistency and to allow easy setup of pre-production environments for the target system. Until recently, GitLab implementers have had to craft this code from scratch.
Now, tha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why we built GitDock, our desktop app to navigate your GitLab activities]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/05/gitpod-desktop-app-personal-activities/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/05/gitpod-desktop-app-personal-activities/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping track of everything that is happening in your GitLab projects and groups can be quite overwhelming. Often times you care about not only one project, but multiple ones. Even worse, these projects might even belong to different groups, making everything more complex.
As an example, product designers at GitLab might work on all of these different projects over the course of just one week:
gitlab-org/gitlab (our product)
gitlab-com/www-gitlab-com (our handbook)
gitlab-org/gitlab-design (space for discussions)
gitlab-org/gitlab-services/design.gitlab.com (our design system)
gitlab-org/ux-research (research studies)
User-centric vs. project-centric navigation
One of our product design managers (@jackib) created a visualization that shows the current project-centric navigation model that …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use external status checks for merge requests]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/04/how-to-status-checks/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/04/how-to-status-checks/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The external status checks for merge requests capability was recently introduced in GitLab and it allows the integration of third-party systems and applications with GitLab merge requests.
What are "external status checks for merge requests"?
External status checks are API calls to systems or applications that sit outside GitLab. These API calls are invoked during merge requests, which display a widget with the status of each external check. With external status checks, you can integrate GitLab with third-party systems, e.g. Salesforce, PeopleSoft, Microsoft Dynamics, etc., that require manual approval for merge requests. This makes it easy to see that merge requests have met external requirements before being merged, adding an extra method to ensure compliance and audit requirements are m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Join us for Hacktoberfest 2021!]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/01/join-us-for-hacktoberfest-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/01/join-us-for-hacktoberfest-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s October 2021, and we have quite a few treats in store. In addition to celebrating the 10th anniversary of the GitLab open source project, GitLab Inc. will be participating in Hacktoberfest, an event dedicated to increasing contributions to open source projects that's now in its eighth year. This has been widely requested by the open source community for years, so we’re thrilled to see GitLab support rolled out!
Thanks to DigitalOcean, the organization behind Hacktoberfest, people can now contribute to open source projects that are hosted on GitLab.com.
It’s easy, sign up on the Hacktoberfest website using your GitLab account and explore the available projects to contribute.
Project maintainers who want their projects to participate in Hacktoberfest should follow the steps described on…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.3.2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/01/gitlab-14-3-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/01/gitlab-14-3-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.3.2 GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
the 14.3 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Add OR REPLACE when creating function
Top 7 Highlight items for 14.3
Update GitLab Shell to v13.21.1
Remove feature flag check for candece finder
Remove unexpected FK prior to swapping columns
Allow ee images to be skipped on CE pipelines
Bump kas to v14.3.3
Important notes on upgrading
These versions do not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab user profiles have just become more personal]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/30/personal-profile/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/30/personal-profile/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GitLab user profile contains information about you and your GitLab activity. You can select what information to display.
We recently added a few new settings to make you user profile more personal:
User pronouns
User pronunciation guides
User local times
User pronouns
You can now set pronouns to your GitLab user profile. The pronoun appears:
Next to your user name in your public profile.
On the snapshot view of your user profile when someone hovers over your name on an issue or
merge request.
Besides being more inclusive, GitLab wants to help you use the correct pronouns when replying
to comments to respect people's identity. You can:
Decide whether or not to add pronouns to your profile.
Self-identify and enter whatever pronouns you want, without having to select from a pre-defined list.
Read more about adding
pronouns to your profile.
User pronunciation
You can now add a pronunciation guide to your user profile. In distributed teams where team
members are from different countries, it can be difficult to determine how to say someone's
name correctly. You can now help people know how to pronounce your name.
Read more about adding a
pronunciation guide to your profile.
User local time
Your local time is now displayed on your profile. Previously, you could set your time
zone but your local time was not visible throughout GitLab. This improvement helps
others know when you are likely to be available.
Read more about adding a
local time zone to your profile.
Additional settings for user profiles
In the upcoming milestone, we are planning to add your timezone to the snapshot view of the GitLab user profile.
In GitLab, everyone can contribute. If you would like to see even
more additions to user profiles, you can:
Open an issue with your request.
Upvote an existing issue. Read more in our Users direction page.
Even code it yourself!
Cover image by Ben Sweet on Unsplash]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Want faster releases? Your answer lies in automated software testing]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/30/want-faster-releases-your-answer-lies-in-automated-software-testing/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/30/want-faster-releases-your-answer-lies-in-automated-software-testing/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For three years in a row, our Global DevSecOps Survey found testing was the number one reason (by large margins) for release delays. A lack of automated software testing, combined with too many manual tests conducted too late in the process, was a story told time after time, and it certainly was one without any kind of happy ending.
Despite the undeniable progress DevOps has brought to software development, integrating automated software testing into the lifecycle has remained an elusive goal for many teams. Here’s a look at why testing is such a difficult step to get right, and how an integrated DevOps Platform can bring much-needed structure to the process.
The state of automated software testing
According to our 2021 Survey, it’s safe to say respondents are frustrated with software test…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Security Release: 14.3.1, 14.2.5, and 14.1.7]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/30/security-release-gitlab-14-3-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/09/30/security-release-gitlab-14-3-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.3.1, 14.2.5, and 14.1.7 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why we spent the last month eliminating PostgreSQL subtransactions]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/29/why-we-spent-the-last-month-eliminating-postgresql-subtransactions/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/29/why-we-spent-the-last-month-eliminating-postgresql-subtransactions/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since last June, we noticed the database on GitLab.com would
mysteriously stall for minutes, which would lead to users seeing 500
errors during this time. Through a painstaking investigation over
several weeks, we finally uncovered the cause of this: initiating a
subtransaction via the SAVEPOINT SQL query while
a long transaction is in progress can wreak havoc on database
replicas. Thus launched a race, which we recently completed, to
eliminate all SAVEPOINT queries from our code. Here's what happened,
how we discovered the problem, and what we did to fix it.
The symptoms begin
On June 24th, we noticed that our CI/CD runners service reported a high
error rate:

A quick investigation revealed that database queries used to retrieve
CI/CD builds data were timing out and that the unprocessed b…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SemVer versioning: how we handled it with linear interval arithmetic]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/28/generic-semantic-version-processing/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/28/generic-semantic-version-processing/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The semantic versioning (SemVer) specification can be
considered the de-facto standard for tracking software states during its
evolution. Unfortunately, in reality many languages/ecosystems practice "SemVer versioning" and have not adopted
the standard as-is; instead we can find many different semantic versioning
flavors that are not necessarily compatible with the original SemVer spec. SemVer Versioning has
led to the creation of a variety of different semantic versioning schemes.
GitLab provides a Dependency Scanning (DS)
feature that automatically detects vulnerabilities in the dependencies of a
software project for a variety of different languages. DS relies on the
GitLab security advisory database
that is updated on a daily basis providing information about
vulnerable packages that is…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to configure Sidekiq for specialized or large-scale GitLab instances]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/27/how-to-configure-sidekiq-for-gitlab-at-scale/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/27/how-to-configure-sidekiq-for-gitlab-at-scale/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-27T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Configuring Sidekiq in your own deployment of GitLab is a little complicated, but entirely possible. In this blog post, we share how to set up Sidekiq for GitLab in special cases and at a large scale by sharing some exmaples that may be useful to you.
Why consider special configuration?
While Sidekiq (both in general, and in a GitLab deployment) will usually just work most of the time, there can be some sharp edges and limits. Raw scale is a clear and obvious driver for needing to take action, and although it may be fine to simply scale out multiple Sidekiq nodes each listening to all the queues, at some point:
The uniqueness of workload distribution and job characteristics may require dedicated workers, either sharded on job attributes (as for GitLab.com), or specific workers (based on yo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>