<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-08-30T00:34:23.723Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-08-30T00:34:23.723Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.14 Released With New Hardware Support, Core Scheduling, MEMFD_SECRET]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-29T22:30:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As expected Linus Torvalds promoted Linux 5.14 to stable in providing the latest features, hardware support, and other improvements ahead of the autumn 2021 Linux distribution releases...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Yellow Carp + Another Water Cooling Pump Head To Linux's Hardware Monitoring Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-HWMON-AMD-YC-WC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-HWMON-AMD-YC-WC"/>
        <updated>2021-08-29T21:45:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux hardware monitoring "HWMON" subsystem for the 5.15 cycle is already seeing the AMD SB-RMI driver and AMD Cezanne Zen 3 APU temperature monitoring while there was also some last-minute additions around AMD next-gen "Yellow Carp" temperature reporting and separately support for another water cooling pump...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yet-To-Be-Released Intel "Bz" WiFi Chipset To Be Supported By Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Bz-WiFi-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Bz-WiFi-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-08-29T19:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the Linux 5.15 merge window opening is imminent, merged today to net-next were the latest batch of wireless driver updates for this next kernel version. Notable to this batch of WiFi driver updates was the new Intel material...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 To Fix Regression In Its Floppy Disk Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Floppy-Disk-Linux-5.15-Fix</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Floppy-Disk-Linux-5.15-Fix"/>
        <updated>2021-08-29T17:48:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Near the beginning of the year was some rare work on Linux's floppy disk driver and -- a half-year later -- it was found out that not only do people with systems using floppy disks still move to newer kernels, but that work earlier in the year had regressed the Linux kernel's floppy disk handling. Now coming for Linux 5.15 is a fix...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Of The Features Expected For Linux 5.15: DG2/Alchemist, BPF Timers, DAMON + More]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Features-Expected</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Features-Expected"/>
        <updated>2021-08-29T10:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If all goes according to plan the Linux 5.14 kernel will be released as stable today. Linux 5.14 has many new features but there is also a lot of work slated for the next cycle, Linux 5.15. Here's a look...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome/Chromium's Ozone X11 Code Now Fully Enabled, Old Legacy X11 Code To Be Removed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-Ozone-X11-Future</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-Ozone-X11-Future"/>
        <updated>2021-08-29T07:15:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Chrome/Chromium web browser now has fully-enabled the Ozone/X11 platform support across both beta and stable channels...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Prominent, Longtime Dell Linux Engineer Recently Joined AMD's Linux Team]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Dell-Mario-On-AMD-Linux-Team</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Dell-Mario-On-AMD-Linux-Team"/>
        <updated>2021-08-28T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here should hopefully be a great indication about AMD's Linux efforts moving forward with one of their recent and exciting hires at the company...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Lands Initial Code For Mesh Shaders Within Mesa]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesh-Shaders-Mesa-Merged</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesh-Shaders-Mesa-Merged"/>
        <updated>2021-08-28T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In preparation for the support within their Vulkan driver, the Intel-led effort for preparing mesh shader support within Mesa's NIR and SPIR-V code has now been merged...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine-Staging 6.16 Implements Two More D3DX Functions To Help Some Windows Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-Staging-6.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-Staging-6.16"/>
        <updated>2021-08-28T09:44:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a relatively quiet summer in the Wine-Staging world with not many new patches surfacing for testing/experimental purposes for this more bleeding edge version of Wine. However, with Wine-Staging 6.16 there are at least some new patches now to talk about...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma 5.23 Will Be Another Exciting Release With Many Improvements Abound]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-5.23-Looking-Good</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-5.23-Looking-Good"/>
        <updated>2021-08-28T09:32:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Plasma 5.23 desktop release is looking like it will be quite an eventful milestone while KDE developers are finishing August strong with many improvements and fixes across their desktop stack...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD ROCm 4.3.1 Released With RHEL 8.4 + SLES 15 SP3 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-ROCm-4.3.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-ROCm-4.3.1"/>
        <updated>2021-08-28T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ROCm 4.3 released at the start of August with support for HMM memory allocations, support for indirect function calls and C++ virtual functions with the ROCm compiler, improved data center tool integration, better rocBLAS performance, and a range of other improvements. In approaching the end of August, ROCm 4.3.1 is now available...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.16 Released With Better HiDPI Theming, Initial HID-Based Joystick Backend]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.16-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.16-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T20:14:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.16 is out as the newest bi-weekly development release of this widely-used software for running Windows games and applications on Linux and other systems...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Could Use A New Maintainer For Its CD-ROM Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-New-CD-ROM-Maintainer</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-New-CD-ROM-Maintainer"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T17:53:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Current Linux block subsystem maintainer Jens Axboe started out in the late 90's taking over maintainership of the Linux kernel's CD-ROM driver code. However, as he's busy these days with IO_uring and other prominent I/O activities for Linux, he's hoping someone interested and capable would want to take over the Linux kernel's CD-ROM code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.14 SSD Benchmarks With Btrfs vs. EXT4 vs. F2FS vs. XFS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-File-Systems</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-File-Systems"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T13:15:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A number of Phoronix readers have been asking about some fresh file-system comparisons on recent kernels. With not having the time to conduct the usual kernel version vs. file-system comparison, here are some fresh benchmarks looking at the Btrfs, EXT4, F2FS, and XFS file-system benchmarks on a speedy WD_BLACK SN850 NVMe solid-state drive...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AVX2-Optimized SM4 Cipher Implementation Queued Ahead Of Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AES-NI-AVX2-SM4-Crypto-Optimize</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AES-NI-AVX2-SM4-Crypto-Optimize"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T13:10:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux kernel has already sported SM4 cipher algorithm implementation optimized for AES-NI and AVX while now an Alibaba engineer has contributed an AVX2 optimized variant for even greater performance...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Red Hat Patch Proposal To Split FBDEV Core Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Red-Hat-Split-FBDEV-Core-FB</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Red-Hat-Split-FBDEV-Core-FB"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T10:34:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For nearly the past decade there has been calls for deprecating the Liux kernel's frame-buffer "FBDEV" device code though the code remains within the kernel. While these days most display drivers are DRM-based even in the embedded world, a lot of FBDEV code still ends up in kernel builds even when just wanting to use DRM's FBDEV emulation layer. But a patch proposal out of Red Hat would further split-up the FBDEV core support to allow less of it to be built...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Adds 17 More PCI IDs For RDNA2 GPUs To Their Linux Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-17-More-RDNA2-GPU-IDs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-17-More-RDNA2-GPU-IDs"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T09:37:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On top of all the PCI IDs in place already for the AMDGPU Linux kernel graphics driver, another 17 PCI IDs were added in a new patch for this open-source Radeon graphics driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 22.04 LTS Release Schedule Published]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-22.04-Release-Schedule</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-22.04-Release-Schedule"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Ubuntu 21.10 isn't being released for another two months, the release schedule for Ubuntu 22.04 has been published that is rather notable in being the next bi-annual long-term support (LTS) release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PipeWire 0.3.34 Released With Yet More Improvements, Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PipeWire-0.3.34-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PipeWire-0.3.34-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-27T00:06:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PipeWire, for managing audio/video streams on Linux and proving itself to be a viable replacement to PulseAudio and JACK, is out with a new update...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 94 Beta Released With WebCodecs API Promoted, WebGPU Origin Trial]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-94-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-94-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T19:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google promoted Chrome 94 to beta status today with some exciting changes...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NetBSD Continues Long Overdue Push To Modernize Their WiFi Drivers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NetBSD-WiFi-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NetBSD-WiFi-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T18:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Started back in 2018 was an effort by the NetBSD project to update their operating system WiFi drivers by re-syncing more code from FreeBSD and making various improvements. Three years later the work has yet to be merged but after stalling for some time is back to being worked on by interested developers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM Clang 13 Performance Is In Great Shape For Intel Xeon "Ice Lake"]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30491</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30491"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T13:20:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month was a look at the LLVM Clang 13 performance on EPYC 7003 showing this forthcoming compiler update to be in good shape for AMD Zen 3, but how is the performance looking on the Intel side? This round of benchmarking is looking at the LLVM Clang 11 / 12 / 13 compiler performance on Intel's flagship Xeon Platinum 8380 "Ice Lake" 2P server configuration.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS Released With Fixes, Newer Hardware Enablement Stack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-20.04.3-LTS</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-20.04.3-LTS"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T13:16:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a slight delay, Ubuntu 20.04.3 LTS is available today as the newest point release for the current Ubuntu Linux long-term support release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Apps For GNOME" Launches To Highlight GNOME Apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apps-For-GNOME</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apps-For-GNOME"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T10:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GNOME project has launched "Apps For GNOME" at apps.gnome.org for highlighting the ecosystem of available GNOME applications...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qt Creator 5.0 Released With Experimental Clangd Backend, Experimental Docker Builds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Qt-Creator-5.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Qt-Creator-5.0"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T10:11:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Qt Company has formally released Qt Creator 5.0 today as their latest version of this Qt/C++ minded integrated development environment...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Working On Making VirtIO-GPU More Extensible]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=VirtIO-Context-Type</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=VirtIO-Context-Type"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T09:47:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google Chrome OS engineers are working on making Linux's VirtIO-GPU driver more extensible. The VirtIO-GPU driver has been modeled around the Virgl protocol for handling 3D within guest virtual machines but with a new context type addition they aim to support additional protocols...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel AMX Patches For The Kernel Posted A 10th Time, But To Miss Out On Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-v10</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-v10"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going back to June of last year there has been work on Intel bringing up Advanced Matrix Extension (AMX) that will debut with next-gen Xeon "Sapphire Rapids" processors as a new programming paradigm. Over the past year they have published patches for the Linux kernel and open-source toolchains with GCC and LLVM Clang. One year later, the AMX kernel patches are up to their tenth revision but will miss out on the imminent Linux 5.15 merge window...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's time to update Docker Engine]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/26/its-time-to-upgrade-docker-engine/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/26/its-time-to-upgrade-docker-engine/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alpine Linux distribution is the base OS used by many Linux container images. It provides a handy packaging mechanism, new versions of software, and a quick and predictable release cycle – all while being distributed using a minimal image size. It's used by many very popular container images, for example docker:dind,
widely used in GitLab CI/CD workloads handling container
images building and management in the jobs.
On June 15, 2021, Alpine Linux released version 3.14. As documented in the release notes, changes in the musl library require
an updated version of runc or updated version of
Docker for the Alpine 3.14-based images to work properly.
Software products across the computer industry have started migrating their Alpine Linux-based container images to 3.14 since it includes significa…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.8]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/26/gitlab-14-0-8-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/26/gitlab-14-0-8-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.8 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
the 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Revert backfill on ci_build_trace_sections
Resolve "operator does not exist: integer[] || bigint in app/models/namespace/traversal_hierarchy.rb"
Fix Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Geo 2.0 Regression - Add ability to remove primary
Backport fix for flaky spec to 14.0
Important notes on upgrading
This version includes a post deploy migration. For multi-node deployments, it should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Pipe Code Again Sees Patch To Restore Buggy/Improper User-Space Behavior]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Pipe-Broken-User-Again</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Pipe-Broken-User-Again"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T23:38:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was just last month that the Linux kernel saw a pipe code change to address a user-space regression due to the kernel's policy about not breaking the user-space even if that non-kernel code is in the wrong. A similar kernel regression fix was merged today...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimized C3 Entry Handling For AMD CPUs Queued For Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-C3-Optimize-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-C3-Optimize-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T19:15:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The work I initially wrote about last week for AMD optimizing their C3 entry handling to avoid an unnecessary cache flush will now be picked up for the upcoming Linux 5.15 kernel cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShot 2.6 Video Editor Released With Computer Vision + AI Effects]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenShot-2.6-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenShot-2.6-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T17:05:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenShot 2.6 has been released as the newest version of this non-linear open-source video editing system for Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Ryzen 7 5700G Linux Performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30483</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30483"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month the AMD Ryzen 5 5600G and Ryzen 7 5700G desktop APUs officially launched for retail availability. Unfortunately we were not seeded with any review sample for being able to conduct Linux testing on these Zen 3 APUs with Vega graphics, but ended up purchasing one afterwards due to the number of readers inquiring about the Linux support. Here are some preliminary benchmarks of the AMD Ryzen 7 5700G.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.14 Features Aplenty With New AMD GPUs, SmartShift, More Alder Lake, Core Scheduling]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-Features</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-Features"/>
        <updated>2021-08-25T13:18:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the 30th birthday of Linux since it was announced by Linus Torvalds. Meanwhile in just a few days the Linux 5.14 kernel is expected to be released as stable. Here is a look back at the most prominent features coming for this kernel release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Write a stageless CI/CD pipeline using GitLab 14.2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/24/stageless-pipelines/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/24/stageless-pipelines/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab CI/CD technology has historically divided a pipeline into stages based on the typical development workflow. Now that GitLab 14.2 has launched, users can speed up cycle times by using the needs command to write a complete CI/CD pipeline with every job in the single stage. In fact, you can omit stages completely and have a "stageless" pipeline that executes entirely based on the needs dependencies.
Understanding stages
In GitLab CI/CD, you use stages to group jobs based on the development workflow and control the order of execution for CI/CD jobs.
Pipelines execute each stage in order, where all jobs in a single stage run in parallel. After a stage completes, the pipeline moves on to execute the next stage and runs those jobs, and the process continues like this until the pipeline com…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/23/build-cloud-for-macos-beta/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/23/build-cloud-for-macos-beta/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[World-class CI/CD comes as a part of the GitLab DevOps Platform to help streamline how development teams build, test, and deploy their apps. GitLab Runner is the execution engine that "does the work," enabling you, as a developer, to run fast, scalable CI/CD pipelines on your on-premises infrastructure or the cloud. Historically, Apple developers on GitLab SaaS had to set up runners on their own macOS systems to execute CI/CD workflows, introducing additional cost and operational overhead. As organizations and teams develop more apps for the Apple ecosystem, the need to create and deploy quickly becomes more important.
Introducing GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta
Today, you can say goodbye to that Mac mini under your desk! We are pleased to announce the GitLab Build Cloud for macOS Beta, …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.2.1]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/23/gitlab-14-2-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/23/gitlab-14-2-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.2.1 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.2 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Adding upgrade messaging for PK migrations
Don't override vulnerability feedback UUID anymore
Reorder vulnerability check criteria
Fix "getAction is undefined" bug
Drop un-used db/ci_migrate symlink
Fix migration NameError in rails env helper
Bump Container Registry to v3.9.0-gitlab
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab 14.2 released with the Build Cloud for macOS beta and Markdown preview]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/22/gitlab-14-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/22/gitlab-14-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are excited to announce the release of GitLab 14.2 with  introduction of the Build Cloud for macOS beta, Markdown preview, expanded Gitpod integration, new DevOps adoption metrics, and much more!
These are just a few highlights of the 50+ improvements in this release. Read on to check out all of the great updates below.
To preview what's coming in next month’s release, check out our Upcoming Releases page, which includes our 14.3 release kickoff video.
Join us for an upcoming event









This month's Most Valuable Person (MVP) is
Cornelius Ludmann

Cornelius added support
for opening code changes directly in Gitpod when viewing a merge request. In fact, this
release blog post was created and edited with Gitpod! Cornelius initially helped add an
option to open a project in Gitp…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a new integration helps GitLab customers secure their code]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/20/how-grammatech-and-gitlab-enables-better-devsecops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/20/how-grammatech-and-gitlab-enables-better-devsecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software development teams that embrace agile and DevSecOps are able to code with a security-first mindset, which is essential for industries that build particularly complicated products where security is paramount, like: Aerospace and defense, automotive, industrial controls, medical devices, and more.
Static application security testing (SAST) solutions, like CodeSonar® from GrammaTech, integrate directly into CI/CD pipelines to bake security into every step of the software development life cycle (SDLC) – protecting your products every step of the way. Security solutions like GrammaTech pair well with an all-in-one DevOps Platform like GitLab, and allow development teams to follow best practices and industry standards to develop code that is better quality and more secure.
The GrammaTech…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Spamcheck: A data-driven, anti-abuse engine]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/19/introducing-spamcheck-data-driven-anti-abuse/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/19/introducing-spamcheck-data-driven-anti-abuse/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spam and abuse are a very real concern for us at GitLab – and likely every company providing services at scale. That's why our Trust and Safety team works hard every day to detect, mitigate, and lessen the effects of spam. Back in October 2020, the GitLab Security team detailed some of the ways they combat spam and abuse and referenced new approaches we were developing and testing to help us better detect and prevent spam.
We're excited to introduce Spamcheck, our new anti-spam engine. Spamcheck has been enabled for all projects on GitLab.com, which runs 14.1, and will be included in the 14.2 release for GitLab self-managed coming on August 22.
This tool was designed, tested and integrated by our GitLab Security Automation team (with amazing partnership from our Trust and Safety team and o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How DevSecOps can protect businesses from future supply chain attacks]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/18/what-the-solarwinds-attack-can-teach-us-about-devsecops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/18/what-the-solarwinds-attack-can-teach-us-about-devsecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of the cybersecurity keywords for 2021 will undoubtedly be "software supply chain attacks". For decades, we've seen a global move toward connected systems and highly complex supply chains. Today these supply chains are under attack, with malicious actors jeopardizing the sensitive data of millions of users through attacks on the public and private sectors.
After public and federal entities were targeted in some high-profile supply chain attacks, the United States government released an executive order with plans to improve the security posture of the nation when it comes to software supply chains. The UK issued a similar call for views on cybersecurity in supply chains around the same time.
Supply chain security became a global priority after the SolarWinds attack, reminding businesses…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to provision 100 AWS Graviton GitLab Spot Runners in 10 Minutes for $2/hour]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/17/100-runners-in-less-than-10mins-and-less-than-10-clicks/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/17/100-runners-in-less-than-10mins-and-less-than-10-clicks/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Managing elastically scaled or highly available compute infrastructures is one of the key challenges the cloud was built for. Application scaling concerns can be handled by cloud services that are purpose designed, rigorously tested, and continually improved. This article dives into some specific enablement automation that brings the benefits of AWS Autoscaling Groups (ASG) to runner management. There are benefits to both the largest fleets and single instance runners.
Embedded in this article is a YouTube video that demonstrates the deployment of 100 GitLab runners on Amazon EC2 Spot compute in less than 10 minutes using less than 10 clicks. The video also shows updating this entire fleet in under 10 minutes to emphasize the time savings of built-in maintenace.
The information and automat…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.1.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/17/gitlab-14-1-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/17/gitlab-14-1-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.1.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
last month's 14.1 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
AS Fix SAML SSO login redirects not working
Bump kas to v14.1.1
Resolve operator does not exist: integer[] || bigint in app/models/namespace/traversal_hierarchy.rb
Geo 2.0 Regression - Add ability to remove primary
Add AES256-GCM-SHA384 to allowed list of Nginx SSL ciphers
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I use analogy to design for highly technical spaces]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/13/understand-highly-technical-spaces/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/13/understand-highly-technical-spaces/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a designer, you're lucky when you get to design an application you're familiar with, such as a supermarket app or a travel website – something we might have already used or even use every day. Most of the time, we are tasked with designing an application or technology that's unfamiliar or highly technical. Sometimes, we may not know what the application we're designing is used for, like creating an interface for an MRI machine controlled by a doctor, or a dashboard used by a professional musician – knowing what all the buttons do is already an achievement.
One of the trickiest questions for designers is understanding exactly how much you need to know how to use an application to design the best system for the user. This conundrum is typical for designers that work in a highly technical,…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Great Phabricator features that inspired GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/13/five-great-phabricator-features-inspired-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/13/five-great-phabricator-features-inspired-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Innovation often happens because competition sparks new ideas. We unpack how Phabricator inspired GitLab to add new features.
Turning back time a bit, what exactly is Phabricator? Built on the concept of web-based applications, Phabricator enables developers to collaborate with code reviews, repository browser, change monitoring, bug tracking and wiki. On May 29, 2021, Phacility, the maintainer and sponsor of Phabricator announced end-of-life and stopped maintaining Phabricator.
GitLab co-founder and CEO, Sid Sijbrandij gives credit to Phabricator on HackerNews:
Phabricator was an inspiration to me when starting GitLab. It is shutting down now. Many of its features were years ahead of its time and there was a lot of humor in the product. As a tribute to it shall we add Clowcoptarize as a w…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use a push-based approach for GitOps with Terraform and AWS ECS and EC2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/10/how-to-agentless-gitops-aws/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/10/how-to-agentless-gitops-aws/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In part two of our GitOps series, we described how to use a push-based (or agentless) approach for GitOps by using GitLab scripting capabilities as well as integrating infrastructure-as-code tools into GitOps pipelines. In this third blog post, we’ll also dig deep into how to use a push-based approach, but this time our focus will be on the integrations of Terraform, AWS ECS, and AWS EC2 in GitOps flows. This approach may be preferable when using infrastructure components that aren't Kubernetes, such as VMs, physical devices, and cloud-provider services.
Similar to Ansible – an agentless IT automation solution – Terraform can be leveraged by the scripting capabilities of GitLab to shape your infrastructure. GitLab also provides out-of-the-box integrations with Terraform, such as GitLab-man…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 13.12.10]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/10/gitlab-13-12-10-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/10/gitlab-13-12-10-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 13.12.10 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
May's 13.12 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Fix: Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Do not create audit event for failed logins on read-only DB
Fix validation method regarding MIME type keys
Resolve "operator does not exist" in app/models/namespace/traversal_hierarchy.rb
gitlab-rails: checks/postgresql detect silent NoDatabaseError
Adding -ubi8 to version to find UBI images
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Ways to scale remote work on your team]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/09/five-ways-to-scale-remote-work/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/09/five-ways-to-scale-remote-work/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At GitLab, we believe that remote work at scale will define not only the future of work, but the future of living. We created REMOTE by GitLab to bring together the remote work community and answer the questions many companies are asking: "How do we do this, and what's next?"
We heard from some of the top leaders in remote work, from large companies that made the decision to leave the office behind, to teams of experts who have been studying the organizational design for years.
We share five lessons from the REMOTE by GitLab event that your team can apply to uplevel your remote practices and culture.
Set guiding principles for your remote transition (and stick to them)
As you navigate the changes that come with implementing remote-first practices, it's important to have a set of values and…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[23% Cost savings and 36% performance gain by deploying GitLab on Arm-based AWS Graviton2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/05/achieving-23-cost-savings-and-36-performance-gain-using-gitlab-and-gitlab-runner-on-arm-neoverse-based-aws-graviton2-processor/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/05/achieving-23-cost-savings-and-36-performance-gain-using-gitlab-and-gitlab-runner-on-arm-neoverse-based-aws-graviton2-processor/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Companies in all industries and sectors have significantly invested in digital transformation and increased their software development capabilities. GitLab delivers modern DevOps with a complete DevOps platform. However, some organizations require self-managed GitLab and GitLab Runners, which creates added costs for hosting and running GitLab infrastructure. Our latest cost analysis and performance benchmarks show that customers can realize cost savings of up to 23% and performance gains of up to 36% by deploying the GitLab application and GitLab Runner on the Arm-based Graviton2 when compared to the x86 based M5/C5 EC2 instances.
Arm is a leading provider of silicon intellectual property (IP) for intelligent systems-on-chip (SoC) that power billions of devices. GitLab and Arm have collabo…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How UBS created their own open DevOps Platform using GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/04/ubs-gitlab-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/04/ubs-gitlab-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UBS, the largest truly global wealth manager, uses GitLab to power DevCloud, a single DevOps Platform that allows for a cloud-based, service-oriented, software development lifecycle.
"GitLab is a fundamental part of DevCloud," said Rick Carey, Group Chief Technology Officer at UBS. "We wouldn't be able to have that seamless experience without GitLab. It allowed us to pull ahead of many of our competitors, and break down the barriers between coding, testing, and deployment."
During GitLab Virtual Commit 2021, Rick and Eric Johnson, Chief Technology Officer at GitLab, talked about how building DevCloud on GitLab's DevOps Platform allowed UBS to increase their development velocity, lower their infrastructure costs, and increase collaboration between engineers and non-engineering teams worldwi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the DevOps Platform era]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/03/welcome-to-the-devops-platform-era/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/08/03/welcome-to-the-devops-platform-era/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps has evolved since its infancy, over a decade ago. Swiss developmental psychologist Jean Piaget believed human cognitive development has four stages (sensorimotor, preoperational, concrete operational, and formal operational). Through each of these stages, the human mind obtains new knowledge while building and modifying memories to inform one's understanding of the world around them.
In the same way that people go through stages as they grow, markets and industries also go through stages of development. Over the years, DevOps has grown into a mature, business-critical practice.
As the DevOps industry expanded, so did the number and complexity of tool-project integrations within an organization. This was the result of three developments in DevOps:
Companies moved from monolithic arch…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Security Release: 14.1.2, 14.0.7, and 13.12.9]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/03/security-release-gitlab-14-1-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/08/03/security-release-gitlab-14-1-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.1.2, 14.0.7, and 13.12.9 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>