<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-08-02T00:21:06.778Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-08-02T00:21:06.778Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 Adding Management Component Transport Protocol (MCTP)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-MCTP</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-MCTP"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T18:42:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.15 is positioned now to see a Management Component Transport Protocol (MCTP) implementation with the code now queued in net-next with this being a protocol for communication between management controllers and managed devices...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ReactOS "Open-Source Windows" Making Progress On x86_64, Multi-Monitor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ReactOS-AMD64-Multi-Monitor</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=ReactOS-AMD64-Multi-Monitor"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T11:21:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ReactOS as the long-running open-source project striving for Windows ABI compatibility has been making some significant progress this summer on various endeavors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 7.2 RC2 Up For Testing With Its Initial GTK4 Work, Command Pop-Up / HUD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LibreOffice-7.2-RC2</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=LibreOffice-7.2-RC2"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T11:13:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LibreOffice 7.2 is preparing to ship this month while out today is LibreOffice 7.2 RC2 for facilitating last minute testing of this leading open-source office suite...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LE9, Canonical's Profits, Steam Deck, & Loongson 3A5000 Made For An Exciting July]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=July-2021-Highlights</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=July-2021-Highlights"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T10:36:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[July was a pretty damn exciting summer month amid the pandemic thanks to many interesting Linux software and hardware announcements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SDL 2.0.16 Is On The Way With Better Wayland Support, Improved PipeWire Integration]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL-2.0.16-Coming</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL-2.0.16-Coming"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T10:12:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SDL 2.0.16 is being prepared for release as the successor to SDL 2.0.14. Particularly for Linux users this SDL 2.0.16 update is significant with some key enhancements for this library that is common to multi-platform games and part of the Steam runtime...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lutris 0.5.9 Beta Released With Epic Games Store Support, DXVK-NVAPI/DLSS, Gamescope]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lutris-0.5.9-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lutris-0.5.9-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T09:35:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lutris 0.5.9-beta1 is out this Sunday as a rather significant update to this open-source Linux game manager. With this new version there are many new features for this centralized game launcher...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Changes Pipe Behavior After Breaking Problematic Android Apps On Recent Kernels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Broke-Android-Apps-Pipe</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Broke-Android-Apps-Pipe"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T16:10:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the end of 2019 a rework to the Linux kernel's pipe code saw some of its logic reworked to only wake up readers if needed and avoid a possible thundering herd problem. But it turns out some Android libraries abused the functionality and this has led to broken Android applications when moving to recent kernels. While the user-space software is in the wrong, the kernel is sticking to its policy of not breaking user-space and as such Linus Torvalds has changed the code's behavior for Linux 5.14 and to be back-ported to prior stable kernels...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New NTFS Driver Looks Like It Will Finally Be Ready With Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=New-NTFS-Likely-For-Linux-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=New-NTFS-Likely-For-Linux-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T13:37:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's looking like the new NTFS file-system kernel driver developed by Paragon Software and over the past year revised more than two dozen times could be ready for mainlining in the kernel in about one month's time when the Linux 5.15 merge window opens. Everything is finally aligning and looking like the code is in good enough shape for its initial merging though not necessarily replacing the existing NTFS driver at this point...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.14 Drops Old DEC Alpha-Specific Binary Loader Used For x86 Binary Emulation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Alpha-Specific-x86-Loader-Drop</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Alpha-Specific-x86-Loader-Drop"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T13:21:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a weekend blast from the past, the Linux 5.14 kernel saw some Alpha CPU architecture updates -- including various fixes and the removal of an Alpha-specific binary loader for running a decades dated x86 software emulator...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux's FWUPD Expands Poly High-End Web Camera Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-FWUPD-1.5.12</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-FWUPD-1.5.12"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T10:42:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those looking to purchase a high-end Linux-friendly web camera for your home office or other environment, there are a few more options now compatible with Linux's fwupd if interested in having the capability of updating the camera firmware under Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[More RT Code Out For Review, RT Patches Updated Against Linux 5.14]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-RT-Updates</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-RT-Updates"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T10:06:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The real-time (RT) patches for the Linux kernel still appear a ways off from mainline but at least there is movement on this important patch series for embedded and other use-cases needing real-time support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE's HiDPI Scaling Support For X11 Is Getting Into Better Shape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-X11-Better-HiDPI-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-X11-Better-HiDPI-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T09:39:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While KDE on Wayland has generally enjoyed good HiDPI support, it's now taken until 2021 for KDE's X11 HiDPI support to be in a position of greater usability after evolving over the years...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linspire-Based Freespire Announces "Entirely New Direction" With Cloud Apps...]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Freespire-7.7-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Freespire-7.7-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T00:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What started off as Lindows twenty years ago as an easy-to-use Linux-based operating system with great Wine integration and easy application support but then changed to Linspire following a Microsoft lawsuit has had quite a journey. PC/OpenSystems LLC revived Linspire after a multi-year gap following the closure of Xandros and since then it's been a rather peculiar platform. Today they are now shifting focus once again...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.14 Implements More 32-bit To 64-bit Thunks, Updated Mono]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.14</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.14"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine developers have popped open a new bi-weekly development snapshot of this software that allows Windows games/applications to run on Linux and macOS along with being what powers Valve's Steam Play (Proton) and CodeWeavers' CrossOver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Compute-Runtime 21.30.20482 Brings Initial WSL2 Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Compute-21.30.20482</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Compute-21.30.20482"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Compute-Runtime stack for providing open-source OpenCL and Level Zero compute for their graphics hardware under Linux is out with a new release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[xf86-video-amdgpu 21.0.0 Released For Radeon Linux Users Still On X.Org]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=xf86-video-amdgpu-21.0.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=xf86-video-amdgpu-21.0.0"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T17:45:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those making use of Radeon graphics on Linux with an X.Org-based environment and not using the generic xf86-video-modesetting DDX but rather than the xf86-video-amdgpu driver, AMD today put out a rare update to that diminishing driver component...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon "Cyan Skillfish" Navi 1x APU Submitted For Linux 5.15 Plus Many Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Cyan-Skillfish-Linux-AMDGPU-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Cyan-Skillfish-Linux-AMDGPU-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T13:30:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD driver engineers have submitted their latest batch of AMDGPU feature updates to DRM-Next for queuing ahead of the Linux 5.15 merge window opening up in about one month's time. With this latest pull request the big addition is the new "Cyan Skillfish" GPU support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[VMware Hits A Nasty Performance Regression With Linux 5.13]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=VMware-ESXi-Nasty-Linux-5.13</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=VMware-ESXi-Nasty-Linux-5.13"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[VMware has found the Linux 5.13 kernel that was released as stable one month ago has led to a serious performance regression for their ESXi enterprise hypervisor...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenGL Drivers In 2021 Still Sadly Benefit From Faking Their Driver Name / GPU]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenGL-Drivers-2021-Faking-It</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OpenGL-Drivers-2021-Faking-It"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Years ago particularly when the open-source Linux GPU drivers were in their infancy it was known in some cases having to fake/spoof the GPU driver name or model in order to workaround artificial bugs / problematic code paths targeted to a particular OpenGL driver or even to achieve greater performance. With a new Mesa merge request called "Unleash the dragon!", this is still very much a problem in 2021 even now in the Android space...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xubuntu 21.10 To Ship Some More GNOME Apps, Drops Pidgin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Xubuntu-21.10-Apps</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Xubuntu-21.10-Apps"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T10:38:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those wondering what has been going on in the Xubuntu camp for this Xfce desktop spin of Ubuntu, a Xubuntu 21.10 development update was shared concerning package changes and other happenings...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 93 Beta Brings Multi-Screen Window Placement API, CSD-Like Overlay Option]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-93-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-93-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T10:06:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following last week's release of Chrome 92, Google has now made available the Chrome 93 beta as the next iteration of their cross-platform web browser...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Releases AOMP 13.0-5 Radeon OpenMP Compiler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AOMP-13.0-5-Compiler</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AOMP-13.0-5-Compiler"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T09:49:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to the AOCC compiler for Zen CPUs, another LLVM/Clang downstream maintained by AMD is the AOMP compiler as where they host their various patches not yet merged around Radeon OpenMP offloading support. This week marked the release of AOMP 13.0-5 as their latest work on that front for the newest OpenMP GPU offloading capabilities...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Radeon RX 6600 XT Launching For 1080p RDNA2 Gaming At ~$379 USD]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30401</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30401"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD just lifted the embargo on the Radeon RX 6600 XT, its newest entry in their RDNA2 line-up and optimized for delivering a superior 1080p gaming performance against the NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3060 series. The RX 6600 XT isn't hitting retail availability until August and that is when we'll be able to publish benchmarks, but for now here is an overview of this new graphics card launching at the $379 price point.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Beta Brings New Downloads Page, Linux Container Updates]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Beta-29-July-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Beta-29-July-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T22:39:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve just pushed out a rather significant Steam beta update for gamers across Windows, macOS, and Linux...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lavapipe Keeps Tacking On Features, LLVMpipe Lands New Rasterizer With 2~3x Faster 2D]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lavapipe-LLVMpipe-July</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Lavapipe-LLVMpipe-July"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve contractor Mike Blumenkrantz is known for his work on the Zink OpenGL-on-Vulkan implementation but recently has also been engaged in some of the Lavapipe software Vulkan driver work and related to that is the venerable LLVMpipe OpenGL Gallium3D driver. Needless to say, there's some interesting work happening...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paragon's NTFS Driver For The Linux Kernel Spun Up A 27th Time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NTFS3-For-Linux-v27</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NTFS3-For-Linux-v27"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T17:30:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Those having to deal with data stored on NTFS partitions from Linux have been eagerly awaiting the "NTFS3" kernel driver that Paragon Software has been working now for a year to upstream into the Linux kernel. No pull request has been sent in yet but the twenty-seventh spin of this driver was published today...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AOCC 3.1 Compiler Performance Against Clang 12, GCC 11 On AMD EPYC]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30395</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30395"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T12:50:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the recent benchmarks seeing how AMD's new AOCC 3.1 compiler has brought some performance improvements over the prior AOCC 3.0 release that introduced initial Zen 3 optimizations, here are some benchmarks looking at how that latest AMD Optimizing C/C++ Compiler performance compares to the upstream LLVM Clang 12 compiler for which it is based as well as against GCC 11 as the latest GNU compiler release that remains common to Linux systems.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manjaro 21.1 Bringing Enhanced Support For Btrfs, Automatic Backups]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Manjaro-21.1-Better-Btrfs</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Manjaro-21.1-Better-Btrfs"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T10:53:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Manjaro 21.1 is on the way as the newest release of this Arch Linux based operating system that is popular for its desktop ease of use...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD PMC Updates, Intel Alder Lake HID, Gigabyte-WMI Patches Land In Linux 5.14]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PMC-Intel-HID-5.14</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-PMC-Intel-HID-5.14"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T09:46:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While solidly into the "fixes" stage of Linux 5.14 kernel development, the x86 platform driver pull request this week -- which has already been merged to mainline -- does have some new additions worth mentioning...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RenderDoc 1.15 Released For Cross-Platform/API Graphics Debugging]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RenderDoc-1.15-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RenderDoc-1.15-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T09:30:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[RenderDoc continues maturing gracefully as the leading frame-capture based graphics debugging system for OpenGL / Direct3D / Vulkan across all major operating systems as well as some consoles...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Systemd/Microsoft Effort For A Global Counter On Block/Disk Changes Coming To Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Disk-Seq-No</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.15-Disk-Seq-No"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last month I wrote about a possible global counter for block/disk changes on Linux being discussed by Microsoft and systemd developers to better track changes via a system-wide monotonically increasing number as an alternative to the existing per-disk tracking. That functionality is now queued up as part of the block subsystem changes ahead of the Linux 5.15 merge window in a few weeks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.2-rc3 Offered For Testing, Mesa 21.1.6 Reaches Stable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.2-rc3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.2-rc3-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T00:17:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Mesa release train continues at full speed ahead for these open-source Linux graphics driver components...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How GitLab 14 satisfies the need for speed with modern DevOps]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/velocity-with-confidence/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/velocity-with-confidence/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How DevOps and NFS changed the game
What if I told you that one of the best-selling racing video game franchises of all time, the "Need For Speed" (NFS), and DevOps have more in common with each other than you think? Yes, you read that correctly, probably not the NFS (Network File System) you were expecting.
An appetite for change
For context, the NFS series originally set out to redefine a saturated, yet unsophisticated, racing video game market. Motivated by an appetite for change, the NFS user experience reflected the human connection to real cars and how they behaved, which was a big challenge for developers in the 1990s. Nearly 30 years ago, "The Need for Speed" forever changed the landscape of racing games, selling 150 million copies since its debut.

The original Need For Speed vide…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Orange made a first step toward CI/CD standardization with GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/how-orange-uses-gitlab-ci-cd-for-modern-devops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/29/how-orange-uses-gitlab-ci-cd-for-modern-devops/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CI/CD is a foundational piece to modern software development. It's a major brick in the DevOps "Automation" pillar and every company involved in IT has to implement CI/CD or they're already quite far behind the curve.
But implementing CI/CD can be challenging especially for growing or large companies. Some of those challenges include:
DevOps expertise and technical skills
DevSecOps
Standardization
Three key hurdles that come with implementing CI/CD
This blog post unpackes these challenges and explains how Orange overcame them using GitLab.
DevOps and technical skills
No matter which CI/CD tool you're using, it requires some amount of expertise to implement it right.
DevOps expertise is important because your team needs some experience with Git workflows, deployment, environments, secrets m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your container images with GitLab and Grype]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/28/secure-container-images-with-gitlab-and-grype/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/28/secure-container-images-with-gitlab-and-grype/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The importance of container image security
Thanks to containers, what it means to "ship software" has changed dramatically. Engineering teams have shifted to produce container images and use these container images to deploy their software. Because of this change teams are now shipping significantly more software alongside their app – whether they realize it or not.
Besides packaging an application, container images also include hundreds of binaries and libraries. These binaries and libraries are included in the container image produced by the team because the process of creating a container image requires teams to select a base image. A base image is a preexisting container image on which to "base" their own container image. In doing so, all software contained in the base image is inherite…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.1.1]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/28/gitlab-14-1-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/28/gitlab-14-1-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.1.1 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.1 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Extend RackAttack basic authentication detection for rate limiting
Enable bulk dismissal checkboxes on group vulnerability report"
Fix syntax highlighting inline background on darkmode
Fix: Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Prevent terms from being created if blank
Remove backfill migration for ci_build_trace_sections
Geo: Fix snippet verification by replicating the HEAD ref
Remove securityScansSucceeded from DevOps adoption
Fix markdown in development docs
Fix deployer task
Don't ask users to upgrade to PG 13 yet
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing the GitLab Helm Package Registry]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/26/gitlab-helm-package-registry/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/26/gitlab-helm-package-registry/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud native application architectures use containerization, microservices, and Kubernetes to run reliably at cloud-scale. With a built-in container registry and Kubernetes integration, GitLab is the best way to develop and deploy cloud native applications. GitLab version 14.1 also includes a Helm registry, which allows users to publish, install, and share Helm charts and packages from within our single application for the entire DevOps lifecycle.
What is Helm?
Helm is a package manager for Kubernetes. A Chart is a Helm package that contains the resource definitions required to run an application inside a Kubernetes cluster. Helm allows you to manage complex applications by storing the application definition in a chart that can be versioned, shared, and collaborated on.
The differences bet…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use a push-based approach for GitOps with GitLab scripting and variables]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/how-to-agentless-gitops-vars/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/how-to-agentless-gitops-vars/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In part one of our GitOps series, we described how to use a pull-based (or agent-based) approach. In this second blog post, we'll dig deep into how to use a push-based approach. The agentless approach may be preferable for situations with non-Kubernetes infrastructure components or when you don't want to install, run, and maintain agents in each infrastructure component for GitOps. In this post, we will discuss how the scripting capabilities of GitLab can be used in GitOps workflows, and how to use predefined GitLab variables to shape infrastructure components.
About a push-based or agentless approach
With the agentless approach, infrastructure expressed and managed as code on GitLab, and updates and drift detection are automated and handled by GitLab without having to install any agents o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Package Hunter: A tool for detecting malicious code in your dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/announcing-package-hunter/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/announcing-package-hunter/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern programming ecosystems make code reuse exceptionally easy. No matter the
programming task at hand, chances are there is a package in a public registry
such as rubygems.org or npmjs.com that implements that task.
While the reuse of publicly available packages reduces the time necessary to write an app, this reuse
brings its own set of challenges. Apps quickly depend on hundreds of packages,
and programmers often simply just trust that these packages don't contain malicious code.
In an ideal world, all depended-upon code is thoroughly vetted before being included in a program – however, this is often unfeasible in practice due to the sheer amount of dependency code that needs to be reviewed and the lack of existing tools to help with vetting dependency code.
Malicious code in the wild…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab 14.1 released with Helm Chart Registry and Escalation Policies]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/22/gitlab-14-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/22/gitlab-14-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are excited to announce the release of GitLab 14.1 with the ability to build, publish, and share Helm charts, create escalation policies to page responders, connect GitLab Runners to your Kubernetes clusters, enforce code coverage decisions, and much more!
These are just a few highlights from the 50+ improvements in this release. Read on to check out all of the great updates below.
To preview what's coming in next month’s release, check out our Upcoming Releases page, which includes our 14.2 release kickoff video.
Join us for GitLab Commit Virtual to learn how DevOps teams increase collaboration.









This month's Most Valuable Person (MVP) is
Andrew Smith

Andrew actively contributed numerous merge requests in the GitLab 14.1 release to help improve GitLab’s planning capabil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimize DevOps with enhanced visibility tools in GitLab 14]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/21/optimizing-devops-visibility-in-gitlab-14/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/21/optimizing-devops-visibility-in-gitlab-14/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps makes teams and work more efficient, more consistent, and more productive – but how much more?
On its surface, the answer is simple. We need to measure workflow from idea to delivery, identify and remove blockers, and benchmark improvements in a manner that is consistent and replicable. The challenge is the way we've typically built the systems that hold the data we're trying to understand.
Enhanced visibility tools are essential to measuring and optimizing modern DevOps processes, and mapping the work output to ensure the business outcomes that matter are achieved.
The failure of DIY DevOps
Most businesses operate and maintain a multi-product "DIY DevOps" toolchain, but stitched-together applications with bespoke integrations don't lend themselves to visibility. Each component in t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are you ready for the newest era of DevSecOps?]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/are-you-ready-for-the-newest-era-of-devsecops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/are-you-ready-for-the-newest-era-of-devsecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Security is on everyone's radar, from board members to inquisitive grandparents. Everyone wants to know what software development teams are doing to protect their applications from attacks like that of Colonial Pipeline, Solarwinds, and others. With the launch of GitLab 14, we accelerated modern DevOps by bringing velocity with confidence, built-in security, and visibility, into DevOps success.
The modern DevOps solution is platform-driven, has a unified data store, and has security embedded throughout the software development lifecycle (SDLC). We find that it is these three attributes that drive demand for a modern DevOps solution among many different types of businesses.
Security in the modern DevOps solution goes beyond just shifting security features left to empower the developers to f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab introduces updates to paid tiers for improved billing and subscription management]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/improved-billing-and-subscription-management/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/improved-billing-and-subscription-management/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What you need to know
GitLab moves from annual true-ups to quarterly subscription reconciliation
Introduces cloud licensing and auto-renewals for improved license management
Requires collection of operational data for customer success services
Applicable to new customers from August 1, 2021 and existing customers at their next renewal
Today, we are announcing changes to improve the billing and subscription management experience for customers. While quarterly subscription reconciliation benefits both our SaaS and self-managed customers, the three other improvements, including the collection of operational data for customer success services, auto-renewals, and cloud licensing, will enhance the product and service experience for self-managed customers.
While other vendors are shifting to only…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.6]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/20/gitlab-14-0-6-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/20/gitlab-14-0-6-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.6 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Replace Excon with Faraday for requesting object storage
Fix LFS objects not downloading with Bitbucket
Resolve "Terraform module usage instructions are incorrect"
Geo: Fix snippet verification by replicating the HEAD ref
Fix validation method regarding MIME type keys
coordinator: Fix repo creation/removal race for up-to-date secondaries for 14-0-stable
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How teams can use the Gitpod integration in GitLab to speed up their development process]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/19/teams-gitpod-integration-gitlab-speed-up-development/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/19/teams-gitpod-integration-gitlab-speed-up-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Turn back time a bit and try to remember the first project you started or joined, and the onboarding experience. How long did it take to install the development environment on your local machine?
We talked about our own onboarding experiences into software development, and thought about sharing our favorite tips with GitLab users.
A developer's tale
Everyone starts fresh, and often best practices are just "learning by doing," requiring documentation in the same moment. Programming languages and application architectures are also different - a C++ backend environment has different requirements than a Ruby on Rails web application.
Start with defining the requirements and stages. Oftentimes they are equivalent to CI/CD pipeline stages but executed in your own environment.
Compile/build the a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitOps viewed as part of the Ops evolution]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/12/gitops-as-the-evolution-of-operations/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/12/gitops-as-the-evolution-of-operations/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitOps is a hot topic in the world of operations, but what does it provide to workflows that we didn’t have already? Looking at the evolution of the operations space, there have been many big changes in the past 20 years, and I argue that GitOps is not a change, rather a summary of best practices. So, how do we describe the major phenomenon in Ops over the past 20 years?
Before 2000, the primary approach to operations was to hire a System Administrator or empower Lead Developers to do Ops work. System Administrators knew a lot about networking and server optimisations, and a good sysadmin can do most of their work through code, using Bash, Perl or Python scripts. While every software engineer likely knows at least the basics of shell scripting, even many backend engineers would not be comf…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we’re creating a threat model framework that works for GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/09/creating-a-threat-model-that-works-for-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/09/creating-a-threat-model-that-works-for-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the first in a series of three blog posts where we discuss threat modeling and how we’re using it at GitLab to help secure our product, our company, and most importantly our customer’s data. As usual, we’re doing things a bit differently, but when you hear why it will make a lot of sense.
Threat modeling
Let’s start with the basics, what is threat modeling?
Threat modeling is the process of risk assessment for a particular project, asset, procedure, or product. While it can apply to nearly any established or new procedure, it seems to most often get applied to software. For GitLab, this would mainly apply to our source code.
As assessing risk has historically been the domain of the security department of most organizations, the threat modeling process has been nearly exclusively ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A brief look at Gitpod, two bugs, and a quick fix]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/08/two-bugs-and-a-quick-fix-in-gitpod/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/08/two-bugs-and-a-quick-fix-in-gitpod/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While looking at GitLab's Gitpod integration, I came across two rather critical flaws in Gitpod itself. In this post, I'll cover the process of identifying the vulnerabilities and some background on Gitpod. The more critical issue was fixed and the fix was pushed to production by the Gitpod team in less than five hours from my initial report. Huge kudos to the Gitpod team for that quick turnaround.
What is Gitpod?
First, let's see what Gitpod actually is – taken straight from gitpod.io:
Spin up fresh, automated dev environments for each task, in the cloud, in seconds.
That quote sums it up really well. You can login to Gitpod with your GitLab, GitHub, or Bitbucket account and then use a pretty full-blown, web-based development environment to work on your code, run tests, or even spin up se…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.5]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/08/gitlab-14-0-5-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/08/gitlab-14-0-5-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.5 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Resolve "404 for package details link under Infrastructure Registry for projects nested under 2 group levels"
Resolve "Terraform module usage instructions are incorrect"
Add documentation for boards epic create
Initialize conversion of ci_builds_metadata.id for bigint migration
Fix git clone for projects with a trailing dot over HTTP
Do not create audit event for failed logins on read-only DB
Add prefix to autocomplete path
Return empty strings for Jira links when URL is not set
Fix libmagic not being able to find magic files
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Critical Security Release: 14.0.4, 13.12.8, and 13.11.7]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/07/critical-security-release-gitlab-14-0-4-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/07/critical-security-release-gitlab-14-0-4-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.0.4, 13.12.8, and 13.11.7 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/06/gitlab-14-0-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/06/gitlab-14-0-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Reintroduce recursive_approach_for_all_projects default-enabled
Fix pages deployment storage migration
Fix frequent items timestamps not updated
Fix bug where Milestone page led to console error
Fix broken Time Tracking Reports on Issuable sidebar
Geo - Fix state value in the lfs_object_registry table
Revert a 14.0 change in the deployments API
DevOps Adoption - ensure displayNamespaceId is included
Geo - Move migration to a pre-deployment migration
Run batched migrations on self-managed instances
Fix deploy keys not working with LFS auth check
Repository: Fix repo replication with transactions
Repository: Fix excessive voting in CreateRepositoryFromBundle
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 13.12.7]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/05/gitlab-13-12-7-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/05/gitlab-13-12-7-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 13.12.7 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 13.12 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Fix pages deployment storage migration
Reintroduce recursive_approach_for_all_projects default-enabled
Exempt unicorn['svlogd_prefix'] from deprecation check
Gitaly: fixes to issues with strong consistency/transactional voting
Geo - Fix state value in the lfs_object_registry table
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>