<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-07-29T00:19:45.757Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-07-29T00:19:45.757Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa 21.2-rc3 Offered For Testing, Mesa 21.1.6 Reaches Stable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.2-rc3-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mesa-21.2-rc3-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-07-29T00:17:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Mesa release train continues at full speed ahead for these open-source Linux graphics driver components...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's Iris Gallium3D OpenGL Driver Now Supports Threaded Shader Compilation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Iris-Threaded-Shader-Comp</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Iris-Threaded-Shader-Comp"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's open-source "Iris" Gallium3D driver for providing modern OpenGL driver support on their graphics hardware from Broadwell through all current Gen12 / Xe Graphics era hardware has been in great shape for some time and works wonderfully. But Intel's not done furthering this Linux OpenGL driver and today they now have threaded shader compilation merged...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OPNsense 21.7 Released With New Installer Offering Better ZFS Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OPNsense-21.7</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=OPNsense-21.7"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T17:47:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OPNsense as the FreeBSD/HardenedBSD-based firewall and routing platform long ago forked from pfSense is out with its newest major release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[O3DE Game Engine Quickly Settling Its Linux Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=O3DE-Linux-Goes</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=O3DE-Linux-Goes"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T17:11:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Less than one month since Open 3D Engine was announced based on Amazon's Lumberyard engine, the Linux support is nearly in a pleasant state...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA["Beyond Stupid" Paranoid L1d Cache Flushing Looks Like It Will Try Again For Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Paranoid-L1d-Flush-x86-CPU-5.15</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Paranoid-L1d-Flush-x86-CPU-5.15"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The work going on for over a year to optionally flush the L1 data cache on context switching is going to try again for the next kernel cycle as an opt-in feature for select tasks. This was the feature rejected last year by Linus Torvalds that went on to "beyond stupid" and other concerns about it when it was trying to be mainlined originally...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu 21.04 vs. Windows 10 Trade Blows On The AMD Ryzen 9 5900HX / ASUS ROG Strix G15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30386</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30386"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the AMD Ryzen 9 5900HX performance is great on Linux once overcoming any laptop support quirks like with the ASUS ROG Strix G15 "AMD Advantage" laptop running into keyboard and WiFi issues on Linux depending upon the kernel version, how does the performance compare to Microsoft Windows 10? Here are some benchmarks of that ROG Strix G15 AMD laptop under Windows 10 as shipped by ASUS against Ubuntu 21.04 when upgraded to the Linux 5.13 stable kernel.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeRDP 2.4 Released With Support For Multi-Threaded Decoding]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FreeRDP-2.4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FreeRDP-2.4"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T10:16:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FreeRDP as a leading open-source implementation of the Remote Desktop Protocol is up to version 2.4 and exciting about this release is multi-threaded decoding support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Btrfs Picking Up FS-VERITY Support, Other Improvements With Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Btrfs-Linux-5.15-FS-VERITY</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Btrfs-Linux-5.15-FS-VERITY"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T09:49:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of new code landed yesterday in the Btrfs file-system's "for-next" Git branch ahead of the Linux 5.15 merge window opening up in about one month's time...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PulseAudio 15 Released With Bluetooth Improvements, Better Hardware Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PulseAudio-15.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PulseAudio-15.0"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T09:28:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While PipeWire continues on a nice upward trajectory for fulfilling the roles of PulseAudio and JACK along with other audio/video stream management needs, PulseAudio isn't letting up yet and on Tuesday saw its big version 15.0 release...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 11.2 Compiler Released With 95+ Bug Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-11.2-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-11.2-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T09:02:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 11.2 is now available as the latest stable version of the GNU Compiler Collection...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to secure your container images with GitLab and Grype]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/28/secure-container-images-with-gitlab-and-grype/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/28/secure-container-images-with-gitlab-and-grype/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The importance of container image security
Thanks to containers, what it means to "ship software" has changed dramatically. Engineering teams have shifted to produce container images and use these container images to deploy their software. Because of this change teams are now shipping significantly more software alongside their app – whether they realize it or not.
Besides packaging an application, container images also include hundreds of binaries and libraries. These binaries and libraries are included in the container image produced by the team because the process of creating a container image requires teams to select a base image. A base image is a preexisting container image on which to "base" their own container image. In doing so, all software contained in the base image is inherite…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.1.1]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/28/gitlab-14-1-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/28/gitlab-14-1-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.1.1 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.1 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Extend RackAttack basic authentication detection for rate limiting
Enable bulk dismissal checkboxes on group vulnerability report"
Fix syntax highlighting inline background on darkmode
Fix: Sidekiq workers delete each other's metrics
Prevent terms from being created if blank
Remove backfill migration for ci_build_trace_sections
Geo: Fix snippet verification by replicating the HEAD ref
Remove securityScansSucceeded from DevOps adoption
Fix markdown in development docs
Fix deployer task
Don't ask users to upgrade to PG 13 yet
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RADV Ray-Tracing Now Rendering Quake II RTX Correctly But Very Slowly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-RT-Quake-II-RTX-Correct</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=RADV-RT-Quake-II-RTX-Correct"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T22:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-source Mesa RADV driver for independent Radeon Vulkan driver support on Linux has been working towards supporting ray-tracing for months. Progress is being made with the latest being more test cases passes and even the Quake II RTX game rendering correctly, but the performance is far short of being satisfactory yet...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Linux Foundation's Latest Effort is Around Firefighter Safety]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Foundation-Firefighters</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Foundation-Firefighters"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T18:22:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the formation of the Open 3D Foundation and their open-source IBM-led work around watering farms from the cloud, the Linux Foundation's newest effort is around trying to enhance firefighter safety with open-source...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Cassandra 4.0 Big Data Database Management System Released]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apache-Cassandra-4.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Apache-Cassandra-4.0"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T18:08:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apache Cassandra 4.0 is finally available as the latest major feature release to this widely-used NoSQL database management system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Micron Working On NVMe SSD Abrupt Shutdown Support For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVMe-Abrupt-Shutdown-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVMe-Abrupt-Shutdown-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T12:58:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NVMe specification provides for an abrupt shutdown mode over the normal/safe shutdown command if needing to quickly get the NVMe solid-state storage ready for powering off as quickly as possible. Currently the Linux kernel isn't making use of the NVMe abrupt shutdown command but a proposal by Micron is looking to begin its usage...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD AOCC 3.1 Compiler Performance On EPYC 7003 / Zen 3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30380</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30380"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T11:17:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week AMD released their AOCC 3.1 compiler that is their downstream of LLVM Clang/Flang and carrying various yet-to-be-upstreamed patches for benefiting their latest processors. While just a point release, curiosity got the best of me for firing up benchmarks of this latest AMD Optimizing C/C++ Compiler release.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DMA-Fence Deadline Awareness Proposed To Help Ensure GPU Drivers Render On-Time]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DMA-Fence-Deadline-Awareness</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DMA-Fence-Deadline-Awareness"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T09:52:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is the phenomenon on Linux where when double-buffered rendering and missing vblanks can lead to the GPU running at a lower frequency when instead the opposite should happen so it will try to not miss vblanks in the first place. In the past there's been talks of "boost" support in the GPU drivers or also workarounds from user-space like dynamic triple buffering, but sent out this week is a new proposal around DMA-Fence deadline awareness as another means of addressing this problem...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RISC-V Developers Continue Working On KVM Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KVM-RISC-V-Virtualization-v19</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KVM-RISC-V-Virtualization-v19"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T09:30:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Going on for more than one year now is the effort for supporting KVM virtualization with the RISC-V architecture, which is very much important for RISC-V processors to be able to eventually take lift in the server space. The KVM RISC-V enablement work is now up to its nineteenth revision but not yet clear if it's ready for mainlining...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Continues Working On Suspend-Only Swap Spaces For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Suspend-Only-Swap-Spaces</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Suspend-Only-Swap-Spaces"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T00:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Google engineers and other parties are interested in being able to create swap spaces on Linux systems that would be reserved just for system suspend/hibernation purposes and not for generic swapping to disk...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[H.264 SVC / Temporal Encoding Wired Up For AMD's Linux Graphics Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=H264-SVC-Mesa-AMD-VCN</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=H264-SVC-Mesa-AMD-VCN"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T22:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those making use of Radeon GPUs for H.264 encoding on Linux, the open-source Mesa driver stack for VCN hardware has just merged support for handling H.264 Scalable Video Coding (SVC) / temporal encoding...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Accelerated: New Node Naming & Ambitious Roadmap]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Accelerated-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Accelerated-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel CEO Pat Gelsinger is back with another webcast following his update in March that focused on the new Intel Foundry Services, new US fabs, and more. Today's event is "Intel Accelerated" and offering an update on the company's IDM 2.0 process and packaging...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Regressed Its Floppy Disk Driver - Someone Actually Noticed Just A Few Months Later]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Floppy-2021-Regression</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Floppy-2021-Regression"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T18:05:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It turns out there is actually people running modern versions of the Linux kernel in 2021 that also are using floppy disks...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse OpenJ9 0.27 Released For OpenJDK 8/11/16 Alternative]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Eclipse-OpenJ9-0.27</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Eclipse-OpenJ9-0.27"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T17:44:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Eclipse Foundation has released OpenJ9 as the latest version of their high performance virtual machine that continues advancing four years after IBM donated the original J9 code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DXVK 1.9.1 Released With Several Game Fixes]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-1.9.1-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-1.9.1-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T14:17:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DXVK 1.9.1 is out as the newest version of this key component to Steam Play / Proton for running Windows games on Linux with DXVK being responsible for translating Direct3D 9/10/11 calls to Vulkan...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XanMod, Liquorix Kernels Offer Some Advantages On AMD Ryzen 5 Notebook]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30374</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30374"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T12:32:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Motivated in part by the recent le9 kernel patches that are already carried by XanMod and not having benchmarked the XanMod or Liquorix Linux kernel downstreams in a while, here are some fresh benchmarks of Liquorix and XanMod against the recent upstream Linux kernel releases.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Haiku R1 Beta 3 Released As Spiritual Successor To BeOS]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Haiku-R1-Beta-3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Haiku-R1-Beta-3"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T09:50:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One year after Haiku R1 Beta 2, the third beta of this inaugural release of the open-source Haiku operating system is now available for testing. Haiku remains the open-source OS project going on two decades for advancing as the spiritual successor to BeOS...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SDL2 Lands Support For Client-Side Decorations On Wayland]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL2-Wayland-CSD</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SDL2-Wayland-CSD"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T09:35:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The SDL2 library that is commonly used by many cross-platform games landed several patches this weekend to improve its Wayland support...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing the GitLab Helm Package Registry]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/26/gitlab-helm-package-registry/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/26/gitlab-helm-package-registry/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud native application architectures use containerization, microservices, and Kubernetes to run reliably at cloud-scale. With a built-in container registry and Kubernetes integration, GitLab is the best way to develop and deploy cloud native applications. GitLab version 14.1 also includes a Helm registry, which allows users to publish, install, and share Helm charts and packages from within our single application for the entire DevOps lifecycle.
What is Helm?
Helm is a package manager for Kubernetes. A Chart is a Helm package that contains the resource definitions required to run an application inside a Kubernetes cluster. Helm allows you to manage complex applications by storing the application definition in a chart that can be versioned, shared, and collaborated on.
The differences bet…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux 5.14-rc3 Released - It's In Good Shape]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-rc3</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-5.14-rc3"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following last week's big kernel in the form of Linux 5.14-rc2, rc3 is now available and it's much saner this week with fewer changes and those scattered changes being on the smaller side...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[BLAKE3 v1.0 Released - Faster & More Secure Than SHA-1, Etc]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BLAKE3-1.0-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=BLAKE3-1.0-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T17:46:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The BLAKE3 cryotpgraphic hash function that was announced last year and based on its predecessor BLAKE2 has now reached version 1.0 for its official/reference software implementation. BLAKE3 continues to be much faster than BLAKE2 while also being much faster than the likes of SHA-1/SHA--2/SHA-3 and even MD5 while being more secure...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed Reflink Support Would Provide Big Space Savings For Wine]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Reflink-For-Wine-Patches</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Reflink-For-Wine-Patches"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T16:30:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When sticking to Wine recommendations of maintaining separate prefixes per-application, a lot of system files get duplicated for each game/application and in turn leading to significant bloat. With the current state of Wine it can mean hundreds of megabytes per prefix in duplicated files. But proposed reflink patches for Wine are aiming to cut down on this severe bloat...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu vs. Arch Linux On The ASUS ROG Strix G15 / Ryzen 9 5900HX]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30367</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30367"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T11:07:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This past week were the initial Linux benchmarks of the Ryzen 9 5900HX with the ASUS ROG Strix G15 laptop. Ubuntu was used as the default test platform as usual given its popularity and arguably the most relevant Linux distribution to use given that it's the most common Linux distribution at the moment for preloads on laptops by multiple vendors. In any case, as usual many users were quick to say "but Arch Linux!" as if it was going to make a dramatic difference in my findings. Well, here are some Ubuntu 21.04 versus Arch Linux benchmarks on that AMD Advantage laptop.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's IMA-Based Measurements For Device Mapper Slated For Linux 5.15]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=IMA-Target-Measurements-DM</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=IMA-Target-Measurements-DM"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Linux kernel feature proposed by Microsoft that is now working its way to the mainline kernel is IMA-based target measurements for the Device Mapper (DM) subsystem for enhanced security...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loongson 3A5000 Benchmarks For These New Chinese CPUs Built On The LoongArch ISA]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Loongson-3A5000-Benchmark</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Loongson-3A5000-Benchmark"/>
        <updated>2021-07-24T17:55:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While Loongson has been known for their MIPS-based Loongson chips that are open-source friendly and have long been based on MIPS, with MIPS now being a dead-end, the Chinese company has begun producing chips using its own "LoongArch" ISA. The first Loongson 3A5000 series hardware was just announced and thanks to the company apparently using the Phoronix Test Suite and OpenBenchmarking.org we have some initial numbers...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use a push-based approach for GitOps with GitLab scripting and variables]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/how-to-agentless-gitops-vars/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/how-to-agentless-gitops-vars/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In part one of our GitOps series, we described how to use a pull-based (or agent-based) approach. In this second blog post, we'll dig deep into how to use a push-based approach. The agentless approach may be preferable for situations with non-Kubernetes infrastructure components or when you don't want to install, run, and maintain agents in each infrastructure component for GitOps. In this post, we will discuss how the scripting capabilities of GitLab can be used in GitOps workflows, and how to use predefined GitLab variables to shape infrastructure components.
About a push-based or agentless approach
With the agentless approach, infrastructure expressed and managed as code on GitLab, and updates and drift detection are automated and handled by GitLab without having to install any agents o…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Package Hunter: A tool for detecting malicious code in your dependencies]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/announcing-package-hunter/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/23/announcing-package-hunter/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Modern programming ecosystems make code reuse exceptionally easy. No matter the
programming task at hand, chances are there is a package in a public registry
such as rubygems.org or npmjs.com that implements that task.
While the reuse of publicly available packages reduces the time necessary to write an app, this reuse
brings its own set of challenges. Apps quickly depend on hundreds of packages,
and programmers often simply just trust that these packages don't contain malicious code.
In an ideal world, all depended-upon code is thoroughly vetted before being included in a program – however, this is often unfeasible in practice due to the sheer amount of dependency code that needs to be reviewed and the lack of existing tools to help with vetting dependency code.
Malicious code in the wild…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab 14.1 released with Helm Chart Registry and Escalation Policies]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/22/gitlab-14-1-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/22/gitlab-14-1-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are excited to announce the release of GitLab 14.1 with the ability to build, publish, and share Helm charts, create escalation policies to page responders, connect GitLab Runners to your Kubernetes clusters, enforce code coverage decisions, and much more!
These are just a few highlights from the 50+ improvements in this release. Read on to check out all of the great updates below.
To preview what's coming in next month’s release, check out our Upcoming Releases page, which includes our 14.2 release kickoff video.
Join us for GitLab Commit Virtual to learn how DevOps teams increase collaboration.









This month's Most Valuable Person (MVP) is
Andrew Smith

Andrew actively contributed numerous merge requests in the GitLab 14.1 release to help improve GitLab’s planning capabil…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimize DevOps with enhanced visibility tools in GitLab 14]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/21/optimizing-devops-visibility-in-gitlab-14/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/21/optimizing-devops-visibility-in-gitlab-14/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps makes teams and work more efficient, more consistent, and more productive – but how much more?
On its surface, the answer is simple. We need to measure workflow from idea to delivery, identify and remove blockers, and benchmark improvements in a manner that is consistent and replicable. The challenge is the way we've typically built the systems that hold the data we're trying to understand.
Enhanced visibility tools are essential to measuring and optimizing modern DevOps processes, and mapping the work output to ensure the business outcomes that matter are achieved.
The failure of DIY DevOps
Most businesses operate and maintain a multi-product "DIY DevOps" toolchain, but stitched-together applications with bespoke integrations don't lend themselves to visibility. Each component in t…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are you ready for the newest era of DevSecOps?]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/are-you-ready-for-the-newest-era-of-devsecops/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/are-you-ready-for-the-newest-era-of-devsecops/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Security is on everyone's radar, from board members to inquisitive grandparents. Everyone wants to know what software development teams are doing to protect their applications from attacks like that of Colonial Pipeline, Solarwinds, and others. With the launch of GitLab 14, we accelerated modern DevOps by bringing velocity with confidence, built-in security, and visibility, into DevOps success.
The modern DevOps solution is platform-driven, has a unified data store, and has security embedded throughout the software development lifecycle (SDLC). We find that it is these three attributes that drive demand for a modern DevOps solution among many different types of businesses.
Security in the modern DevOps solution goes beyond just shifting security features left to empower the developers to f…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab introduces updates to paid tiers for improved billing and subscription management]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/improved-billing-and-subscription-management/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/20/improved-billing-and-subscription-management/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What you need to know
GitLab moves from annual true-ups to quarterly subscription reconciliation
Introduces cloud licensing and auto-renewals for improved license management
Requires collection of operational data for customer success services
Applicable to new customers from August 1, 2021 and existing customers at their next renewal
Today, we are announcing changes to improve the billing and subscription management experience for customers. While quarterly subscription reconciliation benefits both our SaaS and self-managed customers, the three other improvements, including the collection of operational data for customer success services, auto-renewals, and cloud licensing, will enhance the product and service experience for self-managed customers.
While other vendors are shifting to only…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.6]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/20/gitlab-14-0-6-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/20/gitlab-14-0-6-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.6 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Replace Excon with Faraday for requesting object storage
Fix LFS objects not downloading with Bitbucket
Resolve "Terraform module usage instructions are incorrect"
Geo: Fix snippet verification by replicating the HEAD ref
Fix validation method regarding MIME type keys
coordinator: Fix repo creation/removal race for up-to-date secondaries for 14-0-stable
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How teams can use the Gitpod integration in GitLab to speed up their development process]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/19/teams-gitpod-integration-gitlab-speed-up-development/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/19/teams-gitpod-integration-gitlab-speed-up-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Turn back time a bit and try to remember the first project you started or joined, and the onboarding experience. How long did it take to install the development environment on your local machine?
We talked about our own onboarding experiences into software development, and thought about sharing our favorite tips with GitLab users.
A developer's tale
Everyone starts fresh, and often best practices are just "learning by doing," requiring documentation in the same moment. Programming languages and application architectures are also different - a C++ backend environment has different requirements than a Ruby on Rails web application.
Start with defining the requirements and stages. Oftentimes they are equivalent to CI/CD pipeline stages but executed in your own environment.
Compile/build the a…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitOps viewed as part of the Ops evolution]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/12/gitops-as-the-evolution-of-operations/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/12/gitops-as-the-evolution-of-operations/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitOps is a hot topic in the world of operations, but what does it provide to workflows that we didn’t have already? Looking at the evolution of the operations space, there have been many big changes in the past 20 years, and I argue that GitOps is not a change, rather a summary of best practices. So, how do we describe the major phenomenon in Ops over the past 20 years?
Before 2000, the primary approach to operations was to hire a System Administrator or empower Lead Developers to do Ops work. System Administrators knew a lot about networking and server optimisations, and a good sysadmin can do most of their work through code, using Bash, Perl or Python scripts. While every software engineer likely knows at least the basics of shell scripting, even many backend engineers would not be comf…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we’re creating a threat model framework that works for GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/09/creating-a-threat-model-that-works-for-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/09/creating-a-threat-model-that-works-for-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the first in a series of three blog posts where we discuss threat modeling and how we’re using it at GitLab to help secure our product, our company, and most importantly our customer’s data. As usual, we’re doing things a bit differently, but when you hear why it will make a lot of sense.
Threat modeling
Let’s start with the basics, what is threat modeling?
Threat modeling is the process of risk assessment for a particular project, asset, procedure, or product. While it can apply to nearly any established or new procedure, it seems to most often get applied to software. For GitLab, this would mainly apply to our source code.
As assessing risk has historically been the domain of the security department of most organizations, the threat modeling process has been nearly exclusively ha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A brief look at Gitpod, two bugs, and a quick fix]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/08/two-bugs-and-a-quick-fix-in-gitpod/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/07/08/two-bugs-and-a-quick-fix-in-gitpod/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While looking at GitLab's Gitpod integration, I came across two rather critical flaws in Gitpod itself. In this post, I'll cover the process of identifying the vulnerabilities and some background on Gitpod. The more critical issue was fixed and the fix was pushed to production by the Gitpod team in less than five hours from my initial report. Huge kudos to the Gitpod team for that quick turnaround.
What is Gitpod?
First, let's see what Gitpod actually is – taken straight from gitpod.io:
Spin up fresh, automated dev environments for each task, in the cloud, in seconds.
That quote sums it up really well. You can login to Gitpod with your GitLab, GitHub, or Bitbucket account and then use a pretty full-blown, web-based development environment to work on your code, run tests, or even spin up se…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.5]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/08/gitlab-14-0-5-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/08/gitlab-14-0-5-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.5 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Resolve "404 for package details link under Infrastructure Registry for projects nested under 2 group levels"
Resolve "Terraform module usage instructions are incorrect"
Add documentation for boards epic create
Initialize conversion of ci_builds_metadata.id for bigint migration
Fix git clone for projects with a trailing dot over HTTP
Do not create audit event for failed logins on read-only DB
Add prefix to autocomplete path
Return empty strings for Jira links when URL is not set
Fix libmagic not being able to find magic files
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Critical Security Release: 14.0.4, 13.12.8, and 13.11.7]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/07/critical-security-release-gitlab-14-0-4-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/07/critical-security-release-gitlab-14-0-4-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.0.4, 13.12.8, and 13.11.7 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.0.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/06/gitlab-14-0-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/06/gitlab-14-0-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.0.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.0 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Reintroduce recursive_approach_for_all_projects default-enabled
Fix pages deployment storage migration
Fix frequent items timestamps not updated
Fix bug where Milestone page led to console error
Fix broken Time Tracking Reports on Issuable sidebar
Geo - Fix state value in the lfs_object_registry table
Revert a 14.0 change in the deployments API
DevOps Adoption - ensure displayNamespaceId is included
Geo - Move migration to a pre-deployment migration
Run batched migrations on self-managed instances
Fix deploy keys not working with LFS auth check
Repository: Fix repo replication with transactions
Repository: Fix excessive voting in CreateRepositoryFromBundle
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 13.12.7]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/05/gitlab-13-12-7-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/05/gitlab-13-12-7-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 13.12.7 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 13.12 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Available in GitLab Free, Premium, and Ultimate:
Fix pages deployment storage migration
Reintroduce recursive_approach_for_all_projects default-enabled
Exempt unicorn['svlogd_prefix'] from deprecation check
Gitaly: fixes to issues with strong consistency/transactional voting
Geo - Fix state value in the lfs_object_registry table
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Security Release: 14.0.2, 13.12.6, and 13.11.6]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/01/security-release-gitlab-14-0-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/07/01/security-release-gitlab-14-0-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing versions 14.0.2, 13.12.6, and 13.11.6 for GitLab Community Edition (CE) and Enterprise Edition (EE).
These versions contain important security fixes, and we strongly recommend that all GitLab installations be upgraded to one of these versions immediately.
GitLab releases patches for vulnerabilities in dedicated security releases. There are two types of security releases: a monthly, scheduled security release, released a week after the feature release (which deploys on the 22nd of each month), and ad-hoc security releases for critical vulnerabilities. For more information, you can visit our security FAQ. You can see all of our regular and security release blog posts here. In addition, the issues detailing each vulnerability are made public on our issue tracker 30 days…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to stand-up a GitLab instance in AWS Marketplace]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/06/30/how-to-stand-up-gitlab-in-awsmp/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/06/30/how-to-stand-up-gitlab-in-awsmp/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this guide we will learn how to spin up GitLab in the AWS Marketplace:
Pre requisites for this lab are having an account in AWS and an accessible and working VPC.
We will learn the following steps:
Stand up a self-managed instance of GitLab.
Install Runner and Docker Engine.
Step-by-step Instructions
Step 1 - Stand up GitLab instance in AWS
Open GitLab Ultimate in AWS Marketplace.
Click on Continue to Subscribe

Sign in with your IAM user.

Click on Continue to Configuration.

Leave the default value for Delivery Method, select the latest version in Software Version, select your Region, click Continue to Launch.

In Launch this software page, scroll down.

Under Security Group Settings click Create New Based On Seller Settings .

Name your security group, add a description, and save it.…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>