<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-10-25T00:39:24.733Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-10-25T00:39:24.733Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.3</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meson v0.60 Build System Brings Numerous Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Meson-0.60-Build-System</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Meson-0.60-Build-System"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T17:54:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meson 0.60 was released on Sunday as the newest version of this increasingly popular and widely-used cross-platform build system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD Continues Work On USB4 Support In Their Linux Graphics Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-More-USB4-DC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMDGPU-More-USB4-DC"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T15:08:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this month AMD's open-source driver engineers began posting patches for the AMDGPU kernel driver to handle USB4 DP tunneling. That tunneling for DisplayPort with USB4 is for upcoming Yellow Carp / Rembrandt APUs. The USB4 driver bring-up  within AMDGPU continues...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GNU Toolchain Begins Landing LoongArch Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Binutils-LoongArch</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GNU-Binutils-LoongArch"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T14:53:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In addition to Loongson working on Linux kernel support for their MIPS-derived LoongArch CPU architecture, the first bits of the GNU toolchain support for this Chinese CPU architecture have been merged...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Continues Work On User-Managed Concurrency Groups For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-UMCG-Linux-v0.7</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Google-UMCG-Linux-v0.7"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T10:21:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this year was news that Google is finally working to open-source their Fibers user-space scheduling framework. For the better part of the past decade they have been developing this user-space scheduling framework and finally now are working on offering public, open-source code intended for upstream around their work...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bareflank 3.0 Hypervisor Released With Microkernel Design, AMD Virtualization Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bareflank-3.0</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Bareflank-3.0"/>
        <updated>2021-10-24T09:37:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bareflank, as what started a few years ago as a Linux hypervisor written in modern C++ and focused on security and other new features as a "hypervisor SDK" of sorts, is now up to version 3.0...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mediatek Posts 8k Lines Of New Linux Kernel Driver Code For AI Processing Unit Support]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mediatek-MT8192-APU-Driver</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Mediatek-MT8192-APU-Driver"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T21:24:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a number of months Mediatek engineers have been posting some Linux kernel driver code for bringing up the AI Processing Unit (APU) within the MT8192 SoC while out this weekend is the complete patch series at more than eight thousand lines of code...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vortex86 Processor Detection Landing For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Detection-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vortex86-Detection-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T16:47:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recently I wrote about Vortex86 processors seeing detection work under Linux for improving the state of these aging x86 32-bit SoCs. That work is now slated to be introduced in the upcoming Linux 5.16 cycle for those running these aging SoCs/processors...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KDE Plasma Readies Its NVIDIA GBM Support, Fingerprint Authentication Added]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-GBM-NVIDIA-Ready</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=KDE-Plasma-GBM-NVIDIA-Ready"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T09:36:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been an exciting week for KDE developers with preparing their formal support for handling NVIDIA's driver with GBM support as well as getting fingerprint authentication finally in place, among other improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FreeBSD 12.3 Prepares For New Release Ahead Of Christmas, Beta Starts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FreeBSD-12.3-BETA1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=FreeBSD-12.3-BETA1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T08:52:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The FreeBSD team has begun preparations for their next release process with an aim to ship FreeBSD 12.3 in early December...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vulkanised Fall 2021 Material Available - Autodesk Has Begun Using MoltenVK]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkanised-Fall-2021-Materials</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Vulkanised-Fall-2021-Materials"/>
        <updated>2021-10-23T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week was the virtual Vulkanised Fall 2021 event hosted by The Khronos Group. The two-day event was focused on all things Vulkan and for those that missed it all of the slide decks and other material are now available...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.20 Released With More Modules Switching To The PE Format]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.20-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Wine-6.20-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T19:57:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wine 6.20 was released today as the latest bi-weekly development release of this open-source software for enjoying Windows games and applications on Linux and other platforms...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[System76 Laptops To See Some Useful Improvements With Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=System76-ACPI-Linux-5.16</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=System76-ACPI-Linux-5.16"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T19:14:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Patches queued this week into the platform-drivers-x86 "for-next" branch ahead of the Linux 5.16 merge window will provide some useful improvements to System76 laptop owners...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PipeWire 0.3.39 Brings Libcamera Plugin Improvements, Better Compatibility For JACK Apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PipeWire-0.3.39-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=PipeWire-0.3.39-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T17:43:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PipeWire 0.3.39 was released on Thursday as the newest update to this audio/video stream solution for Linux systems that continues proving itself capable of replacing the roles of JACK and PulseAudio, among other use-cases...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Posts The "Last Part" To Their AMX Bring-Up For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-Linux-Part-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-AMX-Linux-Part-4"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T13:07:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While for many years we have been accustomed to seeing Intel land their new hardware feature enablement work in the Linux kernel and related components well ahead of products shipping, occasionally there are lapses due to various internal and external timings. The launch of Sapphire Rapids is quickly approaching and one of the major additions is Advanced Matrix Extensions with its Linux support still being in the works...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Early Look At The GCC 12 Compiler Performance On AMD Zen 3]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12.0-October-Zen-3-Perf</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GCC-12.0-October-Zen-3-Perf"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T10:07:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GCC 12 isn't seeing its stable release until around March~April as usual, but with feature development slowly wrapping up as approaching the next stage of development next month to focus on fixes, recently I wrapped up some preliminary benchmarks for how GCC 12.0 is currently performing against GCC 11.2 on an AMD Ryzen 9 5950X (Zen 3) system...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DXVK-Native 1.9.2a Released For Direct3D-Over-Vulkan With Native Games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-Native-1.9.2a</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=DXVK-Native-1.9.2a"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T09:16:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Valve continues embracing DXVK-Native for allowing more of their older games to target Vulkan by using this Direct3D-to-Vulkan translation layer for native games. DXVK-Native 1.9.2a is out with the latest fixes and improvements...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Graphics Driver's New Parallel Submission uAPI Landing For Linux 5.16]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Linux-5.16-Multi-LRC-Exec</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-Linux-5.16-Multi-LRC-Exec"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T06:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel's "parallel submission" user-space API for their i915 kernel graphics driver has been queued into DRM-Next today ahead of the Linux 5.16 kernel cycle...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steam Continues Improving Its Shader Pre-Caching Support, Other Beta Improvements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Continues-Mesa-Cache</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Steam-Continues-Mesa-Cache"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new Steam client beta is out with a few Linux enhancements worth noting...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab 14.4 released with Scheduled DAST scans and Integrated error tracking]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/22/gitlab-14-4-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/22/gitlab-14-4-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, we are excited to announce the release of GitLab 14.4 with Scheduled DAST scans, Integrated error tracking inside GitLab without a Sentry instance, Remote Repositories for GitLab in Visual Studio Code, DevOps Adoption trend graph, GA for GitLab Operator and much more!
These are just a few highlights from the 30+ improvements in this release. Read on to check out all of the great updates below.
To preview what's coming in next month’s release, check out our Upcoming Releases page, which includes our 14.5 release kickoff video.
Join us for an upcoming event









This month's Most Valuable Person (MVP) is
Ethan Reesor

Ehtan leapt in and offered to contribute remote repository support in VS Code for GitLab hosted projects. This effort was no small feat and consisted of not one, not…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SiFive Has A New RISC-V Core To Improve Performance By 50%, Outperform Cortex-A78]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SiFive-P550-Successor</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=SiFive-P550-Successor"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T22:42:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SiFive just shared word that at today's Linley Conference they teased their Performance P550 successor that will "set a new standard for the highest efficiency RISC-V processor available."..]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying Out Ubuntu's New Flutter+Curtin-Powered Desktop Installer Was Disappointing]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10-New-Install-Try</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ubuntu-21.10-New-Install-Try"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T19:15:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An effort going on for a while at Canonical has been to develop a new desktop installer for Ubuntu. With the recent Ubuntu 21.10 release they are still using their classic Ubiquity installer by default but have published a new preview build of Ubuntu 21.10 with their new desktop installer option. Here is a look at Ubuntu's forthcoming new installer...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome 96 Beta Begins Preparing For Chrome 100, Adds Priority Hints Feature]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-96-Beta</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Chrome-96-Beta"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T18:37:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following this week's release of Chrome 95, Google has now promoted Chrome 96 to beta status...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[XWayland 21.1.3 Nears With Support For NVIDIA 495 Driver's GBM]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-21.1.3-RC</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=XWayland-21.1.3-RC"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T17:57:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The release candidate to XWayland 21.1.3 is out today with just a few changes but made significant by support for the NVIDIA 495 series driver GBM code path...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD EPYC 7003 "Milan" Performance On Ubuntu Linux Six Months After Launch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30634</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30634"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been a half-year already since AMD introduced the EPYC 7003 "Milan" processors that continue performing well and gaining marketshare. While the recently released Ubuntu 21.10 is not a long-term support (LTS) release, for those wondering what this latest Linux distribution means for EPYC 7003 series performance, here is a look at its performance across many benchmarks against that of Ubuntu 21.04 that was released right after the Milan launch and then Ubuntu 20.04 as the current LTS stable series.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AMD "Smart Trace Buffer" Feature Being Wired Up For Linux]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Smart-Trace-Buffer-Linux</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=AMD-Smart-Trace-Buffer-Linux"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T10:15:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AMD patches this month have begun preparing support for a new CPU feature called Smart Trace Buffer (STB)...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[V3DV Raspberry Pi Driver Now Exposes Vulkan 1.1]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-Vulkan-1.1</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=V3DV-Vulkan-1.1"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T09:19:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mesa's V3DV driver for supporting newer Broadcom VideoCore graphics hardware with Vulkan now is advertising v1.1 support. This Vulkan 1.1 support in V3DV is notable as the Raspberry Pi 4 and newer are the most notable beneficiaries of this driver...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Sees Their First Price Increase Due To Supply Chain issues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Raspberry-Pi-Supply-Chain</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Raspberry-Pi-Supply-Chain"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ongoing supply chain issues across the semiconductor industry (and more broadly) are now impacting the Raspberry Pi operations for end-users/customers when it comes to pricing...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby Lands "YJIT" As A Speedy, In-Process JIT Compiler]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ruby-YJIT</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Ruby-YJIT"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Ruby programming language implementation has merged YJIT, its new just-in-time (JIT) compiler...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get started with Python programming]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/21/beginner-guide-python-programming/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/21/beginner-guide-python-programming/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are you a programming enthusiast who wants to learn Python? Are you new to coding? Do you need help deciding where to begin with Python? If you are looking for answers to these questions, then you are in the right place.
Python is an easy-to-learn, easy-to-use and easy-to-deploy programming language, with rampant usage in building web and desktop applications, analyzing data and performing DevOps tasks. It is a free, open-source, object-oriented coding language used to write simple scripts and complex programs. Of the almost 700 programming languages, Python is considered one of the best to learn first.
Installing Python
Before discussing the basics of Python, it is essential to download and install Python on your desktop/laptop. Python works on multiple platforms, including Linux, Windows…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Here's how to do GitOps with GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/21/gitops-with-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/21/gitops-with-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is possible to use GitLab as a best-in-class GitOps tool, and this blog post series is going to show you how. This is the first post in a series of easy-to-follow tutorials; posts will focus on different user problems including provisioning, managing a base infrastructure, and deploying various 3rd party or custom applications on top of them.
This post provides an overview of the entire series, and will provide a bit of context around GitOps, Infrastructure as Code and related notions.
Start with the buzzwords
The DevOps industry is changing at a very fast pace, and there are plenty of new ideas popping up around this transformation. What are these? Let’s look into the following concepts and why they matter: DevOps, site reliability engineers (SRE), GitOps, Infrastructure as Code, and c…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CUDA-Python Reaches "GA" With NVIDIA CUDA 11.5 Release, __int128 Preview]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-CUDA-11.5</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=NVIDIA-CUDA-11.5"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T23:00:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[NVIDIA has made available CUDA 11.5 today as the latest version of their popular but proprietary compute stack/platform. Notable with CUDA 11.5 is that CUDA-Python has reached general availability status...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GIMP 2.99.8 Released As Another Step Toward The Long Overdue GIMP 3.0]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GIMP-2.99.8-Released</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=GIMP-2.99.8-Released"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T19:06:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GIMP 3.0 as the GTK3 port of this open-source Adobe Photoshop alternative has been talked about for nearly a decade now and the work remains ongoing. However, out today is GIMP 2.99.8 as the newest development snapshot...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel Makes ControlFlag Open-Source For Helping To Detect Bugs In Code]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-ControlFlag-Open-Source</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-ControlFlag-Open-Source"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T18:29:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year Intel announced ControlFlag as a machine learning tool for helping to uncover bugs within code. ControlFlag promised impressive results after being trained on more than one billion lines of code and at the end of 2020 was already being used internally on Intel's code-bases from firmware to software applications. We hadn't heard anything more about ControlFlag this year... Until today. Intel has now made ControlFlag open-source for helping to autonomously detect more programming bugs...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclipse OpenJ9 0.29 Released With Full AArch64 Linux Support, More Mature JITServer Tech]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Eclipse-OpenJ9-v0.29</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Eclipse-OpenJ9-v0.29"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T18:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The newest feature release to Eclipse OpenJ9 is now available, the high performance Java Virtual Machine originating from IBM J9...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radeon RX 6600 Linux Performance Rising Even Higher With Newest Open-Source Driver]]></title>
        <id>https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30628</id>
        <link href="https://www.phoronix.com/vr.php?view=30628"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T13:09:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just one week ago was the public launch of the Radeon RX 6600 as the newest offering in the RDNA2 GPU line-up. While in our Radeon RX 6600 Linux review the performance was good on AMD's well regarded open-source driver stack and standing ground against the likes of the GeForce RTX 3060 with NVIDIA's proprietary Linux driver, it turns out the RX 6600 Linux performance can be even better already. Here are benchmarks of the Radeon RX 6600 on Linux across six different driver configurations.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoronix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four tips to increase your DevOps salary]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/20/four-tips-to-increase-your-devops-salary/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/20/four-tips-to-increase-your-devops-salary/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the second in an occasional series looking at DevOps salaries and careers. Find out how your DevOps salary stacks up.
Salaries for DevOps professionals are strong, despite a pandemic and a global economic crisis. However, you can still command an even higher salary with four straightforward strategies.
Various surveys have shown the IT industry is thriving right now and DevOps professionals, in particular, are increasing in demand and value. DevOps repeatedly ranks well on some reputable lists such as Robert Half’s 15 highest paying IT jobs and Glassdoor’s 2021 list of Best Jobs in America.
In an August jobs report, Dice CEO Art Zeile called this “one of the hottest tech job markets since the dot-com era,” and pointed to the upward trend in tech job postings since November 2020.
Ho…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Top ten GitLab hacks for all stages of the DevOps Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/19/top-10-gitlab-hacks/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/19/top-10-gitlab-hacks/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's been ten years since the first commit to GitLab, so we are sharing our ten favorite GitLab hacks to help you get the most out of our DevOps Platform. These are tips for all stages of the development lifecycle, so roll up your sleeves and let's get started.
Manage faster with quick actions
You might have adopted keyboard shortcuts for faster navigation and workflows already - if not, check out the GitLab documentation for platform specific shortcuts. The knowledge of pressing r to land in the reply to comment in text form can be combined with other quick actions, including:
/assign_reviewer @ <search username>

/label ~ <search label>
/label ~enhancement ~workflow::indev

/due Oct 8

/rebase

/approve

/merge 


Quick actions are also helpful if you have to manage many issues, merge re…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get started with GitLab's Helm Package Registry]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/18/improve-cd-workflows-helm-chart-registry/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/18/improve-cd-workflows-helm-chart-registry/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In our 14.1 release, we offered the ability to add Helm charts to the GitLab Package Registry. Here's everything you need to know to leverage application deployment with these new features.
The role of container images
The de-facto standard is to package applications into OCI Images which are often just referred to as container images and more often as Docker containers. The Open Container Initiative was launched in 2015 by Docker and other companies to define industry standards around container image formats and runtimes. GitLab introduced an OCI conform Container Registry with the release of GitLab 8.8 in May 2016.
Today, a common and widely adopted approach is to deploy applications with Helm charts to Kubernetes. This will be covered in this blog together with the feature release in Gi…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.3]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.3"/>
        <updated>2021-10-16T00:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: broken links in documentation
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @hirdot]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Inc. takes The DevOps Platform public]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/14/gitlab-inc-takes-the-devops-platform-public/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/14/gitlab-inc-takes-the-devops-platform-public/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, GitLab Inc. announced the next milestone in our journey as we become a publicly traded company on the Nasdaq Global Market (NASDAQ: GTLB). GitLab was the first company to publicly live stream the entire end-to-end listing day at Nasdaq.
In a world where software defines the speed of innovation, every company must become a software company or they’ll be disrupted by a software company. We believe that GitLab, the DevOps Platform, helps companies to deliver software faster and more efficiently, while strengthening security and compliance. And it all happens inside our single platform where engineering, security, and operations teams can collaborate together.
In my Founder’s Letter, which you can read below, I told GitLab’s origin story. GitLab did not start in a tech incubator, garage…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab’s Kubernetes Operator with support for Red Hat OpenShift is now generally available]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/12/open-shift-ga/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/12/open-shift-ga/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today, GitLab is pleased to announce the general availability (GA) of the GitLab-supported GitLab Operator, with the ability to run production instances of GitLab on Kubernetes platforms, including Red Hat OpenShift.
IT organizations that rely on Red Hat OpenShift can now deploy and run GitLab on the same infrastructure they trust for their other shared services. For many organizations in the public sector and regulated industries that only use Red Hat OpenShift, the Operator unlocks the ability to use GitLab, the DevOps Platform, allowing them to move out of the DIY DevOps stage and embrace modern DevOps practices with greater speed, efficiency, and improved security.
 



Why did we build the GitLab Operator?
We believe user expectations are at an all-time high. They expect always-on app…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab updates its cookie management tool]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/12/gitlab-updates-its-cookie-management-tool/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/12/gitlab-updates-its-cookie-management-tool/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We recently completed a review of our cookie management tool and have decided to take this opportunity to improve the overall experience for our users by unifying our cookie management tool across all GitLab Inc. domains.
GitLab committed to not sending  service usage data from our products (GitLab SaaS and self-managed) to a third-party product analytics service, and we keep that commitment with this update.
What is changing?
We’re unifying our cookie management tool across all GitLab Inc. domains to improve the user experience. Starting on 2021-10-12 we will deploy the OneTrust Cookie Management Tool to manage cookies across all gitlab.com sites. This change will provide users with a central location to opt in or out of cookies that are not strictly necessary for our site and its subdomains, including docs.gitlab.com, about.gitlab.com and customers.gitlab.com.
We also plan to add  a cookie to our trial signup flow and to our commerce flows located inside the gitlab.com application to enable us to understand how visitors are engaging with these pages and to help analyze and improve these flows and resolve any technical issues.  This cookie will not be used for any tracking of how you use the functionality of our SaaS or self-managed products, and users can opt in or out of this cookie through our cookie management tool.
What won’t change
We will not be adding additional metrics or mechanisms to collect analytics data from our core product (including all GitLab features and categories). We will continue to honor the Do Not Track (DNT) mechanism in web browsers for both GitLab.com and GitLab Self-Managed users.
Timeline and implementation
We plan to roll  out the new cookie management tool on 2021-10-12. This will replace our current cookie tool and will require users to review a new cookie notice and manage the settings of cookies on their next visit. Those settings will be retained per-device and per browser and can be modified after the original selection.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.3.3]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/12/gitlab-14-3-3-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/12/gitlab-14-3-3-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.3.3 for GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
this month's 14.3 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Fix dependency proxy image prefix
Drop taggings index if exists during migration
Fix 2FA setup for users with no password
Disable caching of MergeToRefService call in mergeability check
Delay praefect database_*_no_proxy removals
Update cacerts to 2021-09-30
Symlink OpenSSL default cert file to Debian cert path
Important notes on upgrading
This version does not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Threat modeling the Kubernetes Agent: from MVC to continuous improvement]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/threat-modeling-kubernetes-agent/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/threat-modeling-kubernetes-agent/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Threat modeling is more common in people’s everyday lives than they might think.  Each of us performs some level of threat modeling every time we’re in a situation where we’re evaluating threats. An everyday example I really like: crossing the street. Before we cross the street we look both ways, we evaluate the speed of each oncoming vehicle and verify the driver has seen us. Finally, if the lights are green, we cross the street. This is threat modeling!
If you’re interested in learning more about what threat modeling is and how we’re developing our threat model here at GitLab, you can read about “How we’re creating a threat model framework that works for GitLab“ by my teammate Mark Loveless.
Threat modeling IRL
In this blog post I’ll talk about how we put our threat modeling process into…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notice for GitKraken users with GitLab]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/notice-for-gitkraken-users-with-gitlab/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/notice-for-gitkraken-users-with-gitlab/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing details on a vulnerability found with the Axosoft GitKraken software. Axosoft found a defect in the key gen package used by GitKraken versions 7.6.0 to 8.0.0 that could generate weak or duplicate SSH keys. This could enable an attacker to gain unauthorized access to an account or repositories on GitLab.com or a self-managed instance.
Based on our investigations to date, there is no indication that GitLab.com or any projects on GitLab.com that use the GitKraken tool have been impacted by this vulnerability.
Who is affected?
This vulnerability affects GitKraken users who created SSH keys using GitKraken releases from May 12, 2021 (7.6.0) to the week of September 27, 2021 (8.0.0).
GitKraken 8.0.1, released on September 28, 2021, fixes the bug.
Action we have taken
We have emailed users with affected keys earlier today, October 11, 2021.
For GitLab.com customers, we have already blocked known weak keys.
If affected, action you need to take
If you used a version of GitKraken prior to 8.0.1 to generate SSH keys, we highly recommend that you take the following actions:
Self-managed customers:
Revoke the SSH keys immediately. For additional instructions, see: https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/user/admin_area/credentials_inventory.html#delete-a-users-ssh-key
Update GitKraken to the latest version: https://support.gitkraken.com/release-notes/current/
Generate new SSH keys: https://support.gitkraken.com/integrations/gitlab/#generating-an-ssh-key-for-gitlab
GitLab.com customers:
Update GitKraken to the latest version: https://support.gitkraken.com/release-notes/current/
Generate new SSH keys: https://support.gitkraken.com/integrations/gitlab/#generating-an-ssh-key-for-gitlab
More information can be found in Axosoft’s disclosure: https://www.gitkraken.com/blog/weak-ssh-key-fix 
and in CVE-2021-41117.
For questions or concerns regarding GitKraken or its use with GitLab, please contact Axosoft (support@gitkraken.com). For questions concerning your GitLab account, please contact our Support department.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How ten steps over ten years led to the DevOps Platform]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/how-ten-steps-over-ten-years-led-to-the-devops-platform/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/11/how-ten-steps-over-ten-years-led-to-the-devops-platform/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first commit to GitLab (!!) was 10 years ago. Today, it’s an entirely different world: DevOps is increasingly mainstream and there's a DevOps platform revolution.
We didn’t have a crystal ball back then, but we did try to create a product, a culture and a company that reflected what we thought mattered most. Here’s a look back at 10 key decisions we made that still have impact:
Work in parallel: When we started, it was clear the waterfall method of software development - where one stage waited on another stage and nothing happened independently - slowed everything. We decided right from the beginning that a “work in parallel” philosophy would be fundamental to our culture and our behaviors. Also, such a philosophy naturally supported everything else we did, including bringing CI and CD…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updates to de-identifying Service Usage Data]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/08/updates-to-de-identifying-service-usage-data/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/08/updates-to-de-identifying-service-usage-data/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab has been working on a process to intentionally limit our own ability to identify individual users from Service Usage Data in order to protect user privacy even better. Earlier this year, we solicited input on plans to de-identify GitLab’s Service Usage Data. We are now ready to move forward with a new system to de-identify SaaS usage data before it enters GitLab’s internal analytics environment.
What isn’t changing?
The service usage data policy for SaaS and Self-Managed remains unchanged.
What is changing?
With user privacy in mind, we are building a pseudonymization process to run against our SaaS service usage data.
We have determined that we do not need fully identifiable information anymore for our analytics environment, and as such we are pursuing this approach that will result in better privacy for GitLab users.
We’ll create a one-way hash or transform directly identifiable data. This means that the data will be hashed at the collection layer before it is sent to our analytics environment.
You can read more details about our pseudonymization solution here. Once our pseudonymization solution is in place, we will update data we collect to ensure it follows the  solution. You can read more about what data we collect and its de-identification state here.
Timeline and implementation
We’re planning to roll out these changes in October 2021. Keep an eye on our Product Intelligence roadmap to monitor our progress. Once complete, we’ll update this blog post with the final status.
More information
Please find more information about our privacy policy. Further details on how service usage data is used for product improvement can be found on our Product Direction page. Also see  GitLab’s analytics environment and SaaS Data Collection Catalog.
Please share your questions on the community forum.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevOps salaries in 2021: where do you rank?]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/07/a-look-at-devops-salaries/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/07/a-look-at-devops-salaries/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the first in an occasional series of blog posts looking at DevOps salaries and careers.
Despite the COVID-19 pandemic and the subsequent economic crisis that has disrupted lives and business across industries and around the world, demand for DevOps professionals remains strong and salaries continue to increase.
The IT industry, in general, fared better than many during the economic uncertainty of 2020 and 2021. With a strong IT infrastructure already in place and IT professionals accustomed to working remotely, increased demand and short supply for IT workers meant IT salaries held steady or rose in turbulent times, reported Randstad, a multinational human resources consulting firm. 
And DevOps professionals did even better than most in IT.
DevOps salaries are on the rise
DevOps, s…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to provision Ready-To-Run GitLab for 50,000 users with the AWS Quick Start]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/06/gitlab-cnh-for-50k-users/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/06/gitlab-cnh-for-50k-users/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you have spent time reviewing GitLab Reference Architectures, you may have noticed the flexibility of the GitLab codebase; it's possible to support a broad range of implementations from a single box for under one hundred users to horizontal hyper-scaled setups for 50,000 or more.
Scaling to massive sizes requires the services within GitLab to be broken out into dedicated compute and storage layers so they can each expand cost effectively based on high loading and an organization's specific usage patterns.
Those who provision large scale systems on the cloud generally turn to Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to ensure consistency and to allow easy setup of pre-production environments for the target system. Until recently, GitLab implementers have had to craft this code from scratch.
Now, tha…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why we built GitDock, our desktop app to navigate your GitLab activities]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/05/gitpod-desktop-app-personal-activities/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/05/gitpod-desktop-app-personal-activities/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping track of everything that is happening in your GitLab projects and groups can be quite overwhelming. Often times you care about not only one project, but multiple ones. Even worse, these projects might even belong to different groups, making everything more complex.
As an example, product designers at GitLab might work on all of these different projects over the course of just one week:
gitlab-org/gitlab (our product)
gitlab-com/www-gitlab-com (our handbook)
gitlab-org/gitlab-design (space for discussions)
gitlab-org/gitlab-services/design.gitlab.com (our design system)
gitlab-org/ux-research (research studies)
User-centric vs. project-centric navigation
One of our product design managers (@jackib) created a visualization that shows the current project-centric navigation model that …]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use external status checks for merge requests]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/04/how-to-status-checks/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/04/how-to-status-checks/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The external status checks for merge requests capability was recently introduced in GitLab and it allows the integration of third-party systems and applications with GitLab merge requests.
What are "external status checks for merge requests"?
External status checks are API calls to systems or applications that sit outside GitLab. These API calls are invoked during merge requests, which display a widget with the status of each external check. With external status checks, you can integrate GitLab with third-party systems, e.g. Salesforce, PeopleSoft, Microsoft Dynamics, etc., that require manual approval for merge requests. This makes it easy to see that merge requests have met external requirements before being merged, adding an extra method to ensure compliance and audit requirements are m…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Join us for Hacktoberfest 2021!]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/01/join-us-for-hacktoberfest-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/10/01/join-us-for-hacktoberfest-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s October 2021, and we have quite a few treats in store. In addition to celebrating the 10th anniversary of the GitLab open source project, GitLab Inc. will be participating in Hacktoberfest, an event dedicated to increasing contributions to open source projects that's now in its eighth year. This has been widely requested by the open source community for years, so we’re thrilled to see GitLab support rolled out!
Thanks to DigitalOcean, the organization behind Hacktoberfest, people can now contribute to open source projects that are hosted on GitLab.com.
It’s easy, sign up on the Hacktoberfest website using your GitLab account and explore the available projects to contribute.
Project maintainers who want their projects to participate in Hacktoberfest should follow the steps described on…]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab Patch Release: 14.3.2]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/01/gitlab-14-3-2-released/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/releases/2021/10/01/gitlab-14-3-2-released/"/>
        <updated>2021-10-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we are releasing version 14.3.2 GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition.
This version resolves a number of regressions and bugs in
the 14.3 release and
prior versions.
GitLab Community Edition and Enterprise Edition
Add OR REPLACE when creating function
Top 7 Highlight items for 14.3
Update GitLab Shell to v13.21.1
Remove feature flag check for candece finder
Remove unexpected FK prior to swapping columns
Allow ee images to be skipped on CE pipelines
Bump kas to v14.3.3
Important notes on upgrading
These versions do not include any new migrations, and for multi-node deployments, should not require any downtime.
Please be aware that by default the Omnibus packages will stop, run migrations,
and start again, no matter how “big” or “small” the upgrade is. This behavior
can be changed by adding a /etc/gitlab/skip-auto-reconfigure file,
which is only used for updates.
Updating
To update, check out our update page.
GitLab subscriptions
Access to GitLab Premium and Ultimate features is granted by a paid subscription.
Alternatively, sign up for GitLab.com
to use GitLab's own infrastructure.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitLab user profiles have just become more personal]]></title>
        <id>https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/30/personal-profile/</id>
        <link href="https://about.gitlab.com/blog/2021/09/30/personal-profile/"/>
        <updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The GitLab user profile contains information about you and your GitLab activity. You can select what information to display.
We recently added a few new settings to make you user profile more personal:
User pronouns
User pronunciation guides
User local times
User pronouns
You can now set pronouns to your GitLab user profile. The pronoun appears:
Next to your user name in your public profile.
On the snapshot view of your user profile when someone hovers over your name on an issue or
merge request.
Besides being more inclusive, GitLab wants to help you use the correct pronouns when replying
to comments to respect people's identity. You can:
Decide whether or not to add pronouns to your profile.
Self-identify and enter whatever pronouns you want, without having to select from a pre-defined list.
Read more about adding
pronouns to your profile.
User pronunciation
You can now add a pronunciation guide to your user profile. In distributed teams where team
members are from different countries, it can be difficult to determine how to say someone's
name correctly. You can now help people know how to pronounce your name.
Read more about adding a
pronunciation guide to your profile.
User local time
Your local time is now displayed on your profile. Previously, you could set your time
zone but your local time was not visible throughout GitLab. This improvement helps
others know when you are likely to be available.
Read more about adding a
local time zone to your profile.
Additional settings for user profiles
In the upcoming milestone, we are planning to add your timezone to the snapshot view of the GitLab user profile.
In GitLab, everyone can contribute. If you would like to see even
more additions to user profiles, you can:
Open an issue with your request.
Upvote an existing issue. Read more in our Users direction page.
Even code it yourself!
Cover image by Ben Sweet on Unsplash]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GitLab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[v1.11.2]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/osmoscraft/osmosfeed/releases/tag/v1.11.2"/>
        <updated>2021-09-26T18:45:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fixed: unicode characters in URL caused download error
Fixed: project root npm install error
Added: unit test library
Chore: Dependency updates
Thank you: @CaptNo1]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Release notes from osmosfeed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>